Chapter 371

“Massive milkers?”

Asked Feng Liena as the man was pointing at her. She started looking at her peers that were to the sides. Huo Qiang followed this pointing finger as well and Liena could see his gaze stop at her chest area.

She immediately put her hands to cover up as she realized what the younger man was shouting. Her robe might not have been one of the more revealing ones but her figure was hard to miss.

“What is the meaning of this Soaring Dragon Sect, is this the way you treat other elders?”

While the strongest cultivator by the name of Tong was showing a tired expression. The young man that referred to Zhang Liena’s breasts with milkers started grinning.

“Try as you might, we all know that they are too big to be hidden away!”

“Well, he isn’t wrong…”

“Will you shut up you idiot!”

Huo Qiang shrugged while going back to looking at the enemies that they were standing against. He was a well-trained warrior that was just itching for a fight. Even now he was trying to measure his strength against the other nascent soul cultivators here.

The nascent soul masters that the United Element sect had were slightly different than the ones that came from other factions. For one thing, they were much stronger than their older counterparts.

This was mostly due to how much better their cultivation manuals were which allowed them to jump at least one smaller realm. Then some could further enhance their powers through some skills which could put them at or over the strength of people two small levels above them.

While normally it might have looked bleak from an outsider's perspective. It wasn’t quite as bad, even now defeat wasn’t assured even when they were against a large number of nascent soul elders in the late stage and even one at the great circle level.

“You’ll have to excuse young master Long but if you accept our terms we will quickly leave this place.”

“Old Tong, why are you trying to ruin the fun? It’s not fun if they don’t resist and how many spirit points do you think will be wasted here?”

The elders from the United Element Sect side looked in confusion at the back and forth between the elder and young man. The youngster was a nascent soul cultivator as well but he was not as strong as the old man.

It was clear that the only reason that this man was not acting was that this young man was related to the current patriarch. While the elder wanted to strike the deal it seemed that the man named Long was trying to cut to the chase and just attack them.

Everyone here thought that the young man was quite brazen. They could not get a feeling of his cultivation. Sometimes it was low while other times it raised above what the limit of his abilities seemed. It was clear that he was dangerous and that fighting it out would be the last resort.

“Young master please, I will have to report this to the patriarch if you force us into an unnecessary confrontation with this sect.”

“You’ll tell it to gramps? Fine but make it quick!”

Finally, the elder floated forward while the young man retreated a few meters behind him. Even now he was looking at the sect Matriarch with lustful eyes which gave the mother of two to shudder in disgust.

“I will make it quick, give up that woman there and we will leave. She had been chosen to be the concubine for our young master. This is a great honor, she might even be able to foster the next Patriarch’s son!”

“Have you lost your mind? You wish me to become that bastard’s whore? I already have a husband and children, have you no shame or reason?”

Zhang Liena exploded almost instantly, the elders next to her were taken aback by the revelation. Everyone here had known that the man was here to take away one or more of their women. None of them could have known that this woman would be their matriarch.

This posed a certain problem for the sect. It was fine to give up a disciple that was below the nascent soul level or even an elder but it was different when it came to their backbone.

They would look weak if they just gave her up without getting anything in return. Even then they would be considered a laughing stock by the other sects which might see this as a chance to get something out of it.

“Senior, do you expect us to relinquish our honored matriarch to your sect? Don’t you think that you are being unjust?”

“I am well aware of everything, this does not matter to the Soaring Dragon Sect. The young master desires your matriarch and she will come with us.”

“Hah, you tell them old Tong!”

The old man started changing his tune soon. It was clear that even if this man knew that what he was doing was wrong he could not go against the young master’s wishes. The other elders and the ships started spreading out and even more cultivators appeared as they were clearly ready to act.

“We will of course reimburse you for your loss with high quality spirit stones.”

Elder Tong commented while clearly getting ready for a fight.

“Please give us some time to consider…”

“You have ten minutes and not a second more!”

The young master replied while laughing and then slowly made his way back to the large ship. He was greeted there by a group of scantily clad women, it seemed that even now he was a slave to his lust.

“What do you think of our chances?”

Zhang Liena and the other elders huddled up, their conversations hidden away by the grand formation that was protecting them.

“The barrier should be able to last for a while but without the Patriarch here we can’t activate the grand formation fully… the elders even to this day have not been able to unearth all of the secrets…”

Zhang Dong fashioned this whole sect with the help of his system. It was a fortress that was built to last an extensive attack from all sides but there was a limit. One was the power sources that would be used up and the other were the functions that were locked to his system.

In his absence, his wife had the moderator privileges to the sect grounds, then came his grandfather and disciples. They would be able to activate the basic functions but would not be able to boost them with their lack of cultivation.

Similar to the Thunder tower that belonged to the Thunderball Sect. Only Zhang Dong knew how to fully operate it, without him victory was shaky.

“We stand a fighting chance, the biggest problem is that Tong…”

“Leave him to me!”

Huo Qiang smacked his fists together while getting pumped up. Just like Zhang Dong before him, he also knew a couple of ways to raise his cultivation strength. His cultivation level was the same as the Patriarch so some have hope that he was of similar strength.

“Wait Qiang…”

Feng Liena looked at the red-haired man and then turned around. She looked out into the distance where the city and sect were visible. Her eyes looked up to that large floating castle where she recalled her short blissful life with her husband and family.

She could remember like it was yesterday. His warm touch and the awkward smile that with time turned more genuine. His panicked expression when he realized that the first child was on the way. Then that happiness when her daughter was born and the pampering she received soon after.

She smiled for a moment but then she recalled when the second child was born. The good days were halted and nothing but sadness remained. He was not there anymore to see his son start crawling and utter his first words.

Was he really gone? Would he ever come back? These were the questions that she has been asking herself for a long time. If he was truly dead then it was up to her to pave a path for her children’s survival.

“Liena, what are you planning? You aren’t seriously thinking about giving yourself up to that bastard?”

Huo Qiang’s eyebrows furrowed as he seemed maddened by the fact that Liena was even thinking about taking the Soaring Dragon Sect up on their offer.

“Can you beat him?”

She asked and he quickly replied.

“I can!”

“Then what?”

“Huh?”

“I asked you what will you do, what will we do after we kill them all? Can you say with honesty that we can defend ourselves against the Soaring Dragon Sect? If we manage to push them back they will only return in more numbers and crush everyone till no one is left alive!”

Huo Qiang went silent while the other elders knew the truth to these words. The force that they were against was not that they were afraid of. It was what would come after if they killed them off or managed to somehow outlast their attack.

While all other middle-sized sects would have no way of protecting themselves against something like the Soaring Dragon Sect, this wasn’t the same for them. The whole ground was a massive formation and the buildings were built to last and power it more.

Even without the patriarch the shield that they had here would probably not fall that soon. But it would fall, sooner or later they would run out of options while the other sect could just swarm them with more nascent soul cultivators.

If they wanted the Soaring Dragon Sect could order cultivators from other middle sized sects to aid them. Each of the three large powers had a section of the empire to command and the United Element Sect was under their jurisdiction.

They could do whatever they wished with them and no one would come to their aid. Then if they managed to somehow escape and survive they would not find any shelter. Their faces would be on wanted posters and the only thing they could do is seek shelter in other fringe parts of the empire.

“Even if we win this battle we will still lose the war…”

Zhang Liena commented while turning back to the foe they were facing.

“Damn, if only he was here…”

Huo Qiang shouted out in indignation at the lack of power. He knew that even if he could take care of a couple of the enemies more would just come. He also had a large family and many children. If there was a possibility to just offer up one person to save the rest it was the better option.

“Ten minutes is up, now decide mega milk? I like ya and I want ya, now we can do this the easy way or the hard way, the choice is yours! What will it be?”

The young master shouted out from the large ship that he soon left. The whole sect was already surrounded and it was clear that if she gave the wrong answer all hell would break loose.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 372

“That didn’t give me as much time as I hoped for… how many are there, Bob?”

“There are four large energy sources approaching from behind. There are also another five from the north and three from the south.”

Zhang Dong looked at his minimap and he could see many small dots there that were following after him. After giving the bogus cultivation technique to the four people that confronted him, he made his escape.

Regretfully the old fogies were craftier than he anticipated. They alerted some of their allies that cut his escape route. Even though he went through a face swap it was hard to talk his way out of this predicament.

The next group that he passed started following him as well and now he had over ten powerful cultivators following him. They were mostly from places that he had robbed of spirit stones and other cultivation resources.

‘Why does it always have to be like this…’

There he was, close to the border between the two empires. He had to make a lot of stops and zig-zag around the area as there were many lookouts posted to welcome him. The route that he planned to use had been denied as many old fogies blocked all the best exits. Thus he found himself having to use the scenic route.

‘There is always a place like this isn’t there?’

What he was now looking at was a wall of wind and death energies. The wall between these empires was not an actual wall, it was some kind of old barrier formation that shredded anyone that wanted to pass through it.

He had gained some information from the cities that were closer to the borders. No one really could give him a clear answer but this strange ‘barrier’ between the two empires had been there since time immemorial.

This strange construct created a large wall of deathly elemental energies between these two empires. There were a couple of ‘tunnels’ that allowed passage but they were all controlled by the strongest forces in each empire.

There was some information about these passages not being open at the time being. A limited timeframe for the passages being open would explain the lack of wars between the powers.

It would take time and resources to conquer. If the aggressors could not invade and set up a stronghold for their forces it was a fool's errand. Even when they placed some of their forces there if they could not return home to get more troops and resources they would be eradicated.

This also brought up another problem, which was teleportation. If they could not make strongholds that linked them back to the original empire this also meant that teleportation gates were limited.

This caused Zhang Dong to worry even more. It was possible for his teleportation feature not to work even when he arrived in the right spot.

‘Not like I have the choice to test things out though…’

He glanced behind and saw a swarm of beasts and cultivators following him from all sides. They all clumped up into a large force that was slowly catching up to him.

“Stop this instance, there is no place to run!”

Some of them shouted at him but he ignored them. What he was looking at was the great unknown bundle of energies in front of him. The ‘wall’ spread all up into the heavens and was pushing the clouds away.

The ground was devoid of any life and looked like a desert. Elemental storms, rain, and hurricane-like winds along with twisters were everywhere. While he was not affected by the lightning energies here, there were far more elemental powers at work at this location.

Even with his current cultivation level, it was debatable if his body would not just burst into chunks when he entered this chaotic stream of energy.

“I don’t think that’s such a good idea!”

He burst forth with energy and headed towards the dead zone between the chaotic energies and the borderline. When he entered it he could feel his face and lip being cut by something. Even with his current cultivation, he was receiving damage for even being in close proximity to the elemental energies.

While he propelled himself forward the people that were following him stopped in their tracks. Some of the beast tamers were not able to halt their less intelligent familiars. The moment they entered the zones their bodies contorted in strange ways and they started exploding.

Thanks to Zhang Dong’s improved golden body that also reached the great circle stage he was somewhat able to resist the initial phase. But, even now he could feel that his body would be torn apart if he ventured in too close to the deathly black wall composed of strange energies.

‘How does it look, can I teleport yet?”

He glanced at his system screen and at his faction section. There he was trying to see if he could fast travel to his home point which was his sect.

‘The user is still out of range, the user must move a hundred meters closer.’

A hundred meters might have seemed like nothing at all but in this place, it could mean death. Behind him was a group of cultivators that was on par with nascent soul masters. In front of him was a torrent of energies that would rip any regular nascent soul master to shreds.

His body was reinforced and covered with a layer of golden glow. This was enough to keep him from exploding for now but if he ventured forward he was not sure about his survival.

There was a choice to make, should he turn back and try to fight the large group of foes? Or should he fly towards the unknown without even knowing if the teleportation option would work? One thing was clear, the longer it took him to make a decision the meeker his chances of surviving got.

‘I feel like going into this storm is certain death… but…’

Zhang Dong could not shake this strange foreboding feeling. This feeling was part of the reason for him being sloppy while returning home. If he was more careful it would have taken him longer to get here but he would have probably been able to cover his tracks.

Thus he took a step forward. It was a large stride that took him closer to the barrier and even this caused his clothes to be shredded by some incoming wind.

“What is that madman doing? Does he intend to go into the vicious elemental storm?”

The cultivators that were following him cried out in astonishment as they watched the man in the white robe stride forward. They were already astonished that he made it halfway in without dying.

He advanced forward without looking back. Soon he was unable to keep himself up in the air and had to descend onto the sandy ground. The earth was devoid of any life, when he landed his feet caused the ground to crack.

Even though the ground looked like a desert it was far from soft. He noticed a strange increase in gravity the further he went which made his feet sink into the hard compressed sand.

Ninety meters, seventy meters, fifty meters, he traded on and the further he got the slower he became. His form became one with the storm as the cultivators that were following him could not see or feel his presence anymore.

To them, he was already a lost cause. His remains would be eradicated by the elemental energies and scattered in this zone that was devoid of life. But, he kept on pushing. The memories of his children and wife keeping his spirit afloat allowed him to move through the pain.

Forty, thirty, twenty, and ten. He was close yet also quite far as his body was pushed into the ground below him.

‘Not yet, I’m not done yet…’

He pushed his body to the very limit as he crawled. It felt like he was being weighed down by a mountain and going against the stream. Still, he didn’t falter and continued, one meter at a time he pushed forward, and then when all seemed lost and his vision started getting blurry he noticed something.

Faction in range, teleport to the registered home point? Y/N

With a shaky hand, he reached out to select one of the prompts. His vision blurred and he felt like his body was about to be torn apart. Then suddenly he felt his face landing on something soft and squishy.

“Huh?”

The feeling was reminiscent of something and when he opened his eyes he realized.

“Wait, isn't this?”

He rolled over and could see a familiar-looking ceiling and the soft thing he landed in was a bed that he created himself.

“Am I back?”

“Affirmative, the user has returned to his faction's home point.”

Bob's robotic voice echoed in his head. He wanted to do nothing more than to jump up in a show of happiness but then he noticed that his body was in no condition to do this. He was naked, his body looked like it went through a shredder as he was covered in wounds and bleeding all over the place.

The room that he appeared in was his secret man cave. It was something that he made as an excuse for secluded cultivation. In reality he used it to wind down and relax. This room was secretly placed deep underground, the walls were blocking spiritual senses so no one would be able to tell that he had returned.

“Ugh… it should be somewhere here…”

This room was somewhat similar to his old room where he used to live. It wasn’t very spacious and besides the large bed, there were some monitors, a desk, and a gamer chair in the corner.

There was also a side room where he kept some of the items that he made. This was the room that he was slowly forcing himself to crawl to. In it, he was able to find some healing pills which he instantly popped into his mouth before passing out on the floor.

When his eyes opened again he felt refreshed. Through the dried-up blood that covered his body, he could tell that he had passed out for some time. This was no time to rest as he jumped up to his feet and quickly returned to the main room.

“What is that?”

With a flick of a switch, all of the monitors here turned on. On them, he could see what the sect looked like on the outside. The first thing that he noticed was that the defensive formation was turned on and that his wife was floating up to receive some unwanted visitors. This was quickly followed by a glaring alarm that was coming from deep within his own head.

“Other system holder detected in close proximity to the user, caution is advised!”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 373

“I’m getting tired of this, Tong let us just do the usual, it won’t take that long.”

“But young master, if we escalate the problem it will take valuable time. I must remind you that the Patriarch ordered us to take care of this swiftly, there is much at stake here.”

At this moment the old elder from the Soaring Dragon Sect was talking with the young master. They were both floating in front of their flagship and their conversation was private. The young master started chuckling as he replied.

“You worry too much, how long could this take? They don’t even have as many nascent soul mobs as we do?”

“I worry about their barrier, it won’t be easy to get past it, It’s not something that I expected to see from such a small sect…”

The old man narrowed his eyes as the barrier was large enough to encompass the whole city. Most of the sects would not make protective barriers this big and focus on protecting the main inner sect. This left the outer sects and cities around them mostly unprotected from actual strong opponents.

From Tong’s perspective, the large barrier that was here wasn’t far behind their own. It would take a prolonged assault to crack this large nut. They might have to use the middle sized sects and ask them for reinforcements.

This was of course something that he wished to avoid. He knew that the middle sized sects would probably stall for time and would put in the minimal effort. There was also the problem of the Azure Emperor and the other sect that they had a shaky agreement with.

If they took too long here they would be showing weakness. This could be put up to debate if their next plan would go into fruition.

“You’re worried about that?”

Tong nodded while looking at the young master who was grinding.

“Damn, it really is a powerful one… this will cost me a big chunk of my points…”

The young man started mumbling to himself about some points. The old man had witnessed the strange behaviours of this young man a long time ago. At first young master Wang hid this quirky nature away but the more power he gained the more relaxed around others he became.

It was clear that he tossed all pretense to the side and let his true nature emerge. The old man figured out some terms like ‘NPC’ to which the young master referred. It was not a gentle term that mostly stripped anyone of their humanity whenever he called them as such.

“But not like I can’t farm these points right back, I bet this sect has some fat spirit stones that I can collect and there are enough nascent soul mobs to get everything back and more!”

Tong looked at the young man wiggle his index finger in front of his own face. This was something he did from time to time as well. Most of the time nothing happened but sometimes strange things would appear out of thin air or other bizarre effects.

“Ten minutes is up, now decide mega milk? I like ya and I want ya, now we can do this the easy way or the hard way, the choice is yours! What will it be? Let me help you make the right decision!”

Suddenly the large barrier that was surrounding the whole Spirit Spring City and the sect started to rumble. Like glass, it shattered into many tiny pieces and the people that were beneath were revealed.

Tong was astonished by the craftiness of this young man. He knew that if the youth was not so enthralled by the female form he would make a great patriarch. It was clear that he had the talent and had some kind of fortunate encounter.

It took him a couple of years to achieve what took half a lifetime to lesser men. His rise to power was like a meteor that could not be stopped. Like a proper cultivator, his path was paved with the corpses of his predecessors. No one on his level remained and now he was next in line for the throne.

“How could this be, how could they disable our grand barrier? Do we have a traitor in our midst?”

The United Element Sect was in chaos, their cannons that were manned by the lesser cultivators turned aim and every battle-hardened veteran was ready to strike.

The ten nascent soul elders from the Soaring Dragon Sect pushed their palms forward and caused a massive amount of pressure to fall on the entire city. Through this, anyone below the nascent soul felt like they were at the bottom of the sea.

Some of the elders that were able to resist from the United Element side countered this effect with their own cultivation but it wasn’t enough. The Soaring Dragon Sect came prepared with many masters in the late stage.

Any of these men and women that were here could become a Patriarch of their own sect if they wanted. They still chose to remain in the middle reaches of the empire. That was the best spot for cultivation and far more enticing than a big fish in a small pond scenario.

One particular man with red hair charged out in front of the others. He was radiating a massive amount of energy. From Tong’s perspective, he was still only a middle stage nascent soul cultivator.

There was something strange about him though. The red energy surrounding his body that looked like a coat of flames felt somewhat off. Even though he was someone at the pinnacle of the nascent soul he felt like he would not come out unscathed if he touched that energy.

Thus he moved to intercept this man, it was clear that he was dangerous. Before the battle could start, they were interrupted by a booming voice of the woman that they came here for.

“Please stop! No one has to die today, I will come with you!”

Both sides stopped whatever they were doing and looked to Zhang Liena who flew forward and placed herself in front of Huo Qiang.

“Are you sure you want to do this? I say we fight… how do you expect me to face him if I just let them take you like this?”

“I know, but the lives of our people and family members are more important. Even if we win today, there is nowhere that we can hide…”

“Good, you came to a decision, let us depart then.”

Tong hovered down before the man covered in crimson flames. He still was ready for a fight, his hand clenched on his sword and weary of standing so close to two nascent soul masters.

“Don’t worry, the rumors about the young master are over-exaggerated. Your matriarch will be well cared for and any offspring will become part of the Soaring Dragon Sect.”

Tong put on a stone-cold face while talking as he knew that this was total horseshit. The woman that they would be taking with them will be lucky if she came out alive after everything was over.

Most of the women end up dried up husks of their former selves. Then if they survived they were tossed out of the young master’s peak to fend for themselves. Some remained in the sect out of necessity while others took their own lives as they were unable to cope with what had happened.

“Do you really want us to believe that?”

Huo Qiang snorted while backing off, he looked to the young master in question that was in the process of licking his lips. Soon he stood before his prize, Zhang Liena, the late Patriarch’s wife.

Tong was close by and ready, if anyone tried to pull something he would need to act. He did not like this grandson of the Patriarch but if something happened to him, then his head could roll.

Even his status might not be able to shield him from the Patriarch’s rage and he knew that the old man doted on this young master here. He was convinced that the young man was the future and if the future was gone then he feared that the Patriarch could do something drastic.

Luckily it didn’t seem that anything out of the ordinary would be happening. While the man with red hair moved slowly back the woman begrudgingly approached them. The young master Wang didn’t hide his lustful gaze. It was clear that it was fixated on the woman’s rather large chest which put most of the other concubines to shame.

Just as with any other concubine, Tong knew that the young master would not be able to show restraint. It didn’t matter that they were in public and that everyone from the United Element Sect was staring daggers at them. They could only watch as their Matriarch got harassed.

But just before the man could grasp that chest, Tong felt an attack coming from the side. It was strange as it was easy to read, he didn’t even have to move as it fizzled away into nothingness just from getting close to his nascent soul aura.

The attack was followed by an angry-looking girl. Just from the face, he could tell that the person was related to this matriarch and the chest size was quite similar. The biggest difference was the height as this girl was about a head shorter.

“Leave my sister alone!”

“Oh? Isn’t that a feisty one! They are sisters? Even better!”

Tong wanted to sigh as he saw his young master’s eyes glitter. He instantly knew that the girl that just attacked would be taken as well. Even though the girl charged forward she was restrained by the people from the United Element Sect.

It was clear that they wanted to remove her from the situation. Alas, it was too late, the young master had made his decision so he needed to follow up on it.

“Release the girl, she will also come with us.”

The young master nodded and moved his attention to the United Sect Matriarch. His hand reached out but before the fingers could sink into the goods another event interrupted them. Tong could hear a strange buzzing sound and instead of soft flesh, the grasping hand collided with something.

“What? But I used the spirit points… how could this barrier go against the system?”

It was the defensive barrier that was once again operating. Tong did not know how his master removed it in the first place but it seemed that he didn’t know why it was running either.

The barrier wasn’t the only problem as the whole city began to rumble. The floating castle in the background began to glow in a golden light and Tong could see that it started moving towards them.

“How could this be? The Patriarch’s citadel is unable to function without his presence… could this mean?”

The people from the United Element’s Sect looked to the glowing castle with wide eyes with one person in particular looking with quite the zeal.

Chapter 374

There he was, naked and woozy down on the ground. He felt like he was run over by a car which then turned around and hit him once again. Luckily for him, there were some healing pills in the room that he crawled into.

“I’m back…”

While slowly standing up he pumped his fist in the air which caused some of the wounds to sting. This he didn’t care much about as he was visibly pleased by having his long journey be at an end.

It all started on that fateful day where he fought off the third iteration of the monster. Then he was tossed into the void between worlds. This taught him secrets that he was not meant to know.

The person behind the creation of these separate dimensions was still unknown to him. It did give him valuable information about how his own world worked. The existence of higher beings that watched over these worlds became known to him. For him to not suffer an untimely death he would need to avoid them at all cost.

This was not a problem that he would need to handle yet, now he needed to rejoin his family. The simple fact that this room was in place meant that things looked well. With heavy steps he traded out of the side room, his vision was blurry but this didn’t keep him from seeing the bright monitors.

His vision focused and he could see the familiar scenery that he remembered well. The sect buildings were there, he was back home. The monitors in this room were fashioned by him and he had his own version of cameras placed around some key locations.

The first thing he noticed was the lack of people. Out in the yard at his home there was no one, he hoped to see his children playing with their mother but there was no one there. No people in the streets either, it looked like a ghost town.

His attention was drawn to a certain monitor, on it he could see movement. There he finally saw her, his beautiful wife. At the moment he was drawn into her face but soon he noticed that something was off. She looked rather perturbed and the reason behind this became apparent.

“What?”

This realization was soon followed by his AI giving him an alarm.

“Other system holder detected in close proximity to the user, caution is advised!”

“How could that be possible?”

From what he could tell there would be one person with a system summoned. Even back in the other world, Takeshi was the main system holder. All the girls that came with him were only borrowing some of its functions.

Was this person related to him? Could he have been summoned at the same time and possessed some off-shot system?

“Calculating… answer available. The possibility of a new system holder being summoned after the perceived disconnection from the source by the user is 99.99%”

“The source?”

Zhang Dong thought back to the time when his system started acting strange. It was back when he was forced down into the expedition along with his clansmen. There he suffered a near-death experience after using up all of his spiritual energy.

“Are you telling me, that this world’s overseer thinks that I’m dead and so he summoned another person to replace me?”

“Affirmative.”

“Could you explain yourself, you’re not really helping much…”

“Attempting to access the database to answer the quarry… error… error…”

“Figures…”

His little AI helped appear after he got thrown into the void. It was unknown to him how Bob really worked and if he could actually fully trust him yet. All the questions that he posed towards the people that were working in the background were met with errors.

Bob did assure him that if he reached a higher state of being that some of this information would be revealed to him. This AI was probably something that was left behind when he absorbed that first cube during the expedition.

The initial absorption cut him away from the source and altered his old system. Then when he was thrown into the gap between worlds Bob was activated. Perhaps this thing needed certain requirements to unlock its secrets.

One of these requirements was gathering more cubes and gaining more power. If there was another person with a system that was summoned to this empire. This meant that there was another cube powering a different teleportation formation as the one that brought him here.

“Wait, did this person come from my world? Why is he here then?”

It didn’t seem that a battle had broken out just yet so Zhang Dong decided to wait. He needed more information, if he bolted outside he might have just escalated everything.

“I don’t like this but maybe they can talk it out…”

The barrier was surrounding the whole area and the civilians had been evacuated. It seemed that the construction of this base had been finished and they were following his old instructions.

He never liked that other sects that used large cities as their base of operations never cared about the populace. They would mostly bunker up in their own buildings while the civilians were left to their own devices. They could just run during an attack and the outer walls were loosely protected but mostly against weaker foes.

While the situation looked to be sketchy he did have a smile on his face. It took a bit of time to move his gaze away from his wife. All the people he knew were there, Huo Qiang, Zhang Jin, and even Zhang Zhi. He did not see many people of the younger generation like Feng Nuana or his two disciples for some reason.

With a wave of his hand, he activated the monitors to search for them. He did not want to activate his spiritual sense as that could cause him to be discovered. The monitors tapped into some hidden cameras that were spread out like a net through the whole sect and city. In a few seconds, he managed to find both of his disciples.

“Wha…”

They weren’t alone though, with them there was Feng Nuana that was visibly angered at something. She was pacing back and forth while fuming and talking fast. This was not what drew in his gaze, no what he was looking at was a child that was sitting in Zhang Xue’s lap.

‘Wait is that… no…’

He took a step back as he realized that this was his son, Zhang Jun. The thing that took him aback was his size, for him not more than five to six months had passed but the child that he was looking at was far above that age.

Next to the boy he also noticed another child that was slightly bigger. This was clearly his daughter Zhang Xiu. While the boy wasn’t doing much the girl had a rather grumpy expression.

Zhang Dong quickly brought up his faction interface. He did not have time to check yet but now would be the perfect time. He zoomed on his wife and also found his children there. His eyes moved towards the age indication and his mouth opened wide.

“Five years… I was gone for five years?”

He staggered backward and onto a replica gaming chair that he had created. Five years he was gone, five years his children did not see him. While he was able to interact with his daughter this could not be said for the youngest. For all intents and purposes, he would be a stranger to the boy while the oldest might recall him existing.

‘No, what matters is that they are both fine and healthy.’

This was no time for spacing out, while his children might not recall their father it was enough for them to be alive. His wife was out there and danger loomed over the sect, this was no time for this.

The person that replaced him came into view. Right from the start, Zhang Dong could tell that something was off. When he left the ship that he was on he was surrounded by scantily clad women. It was clear from the start that this man was living the bachelor's life.

His looks were also somewhat peculiar. He clearly picked a good-looking avatar but while Matt chose to go with a more muscular version this person went with a slimmer variant. The face was of a pretty boy that would give women a run for their money.

“Wait… what did he say? Milkers?”

He thought that he might have misheard it but when he turned up the sound he could tell that this person was a bottom feeder. The more he heard him talking the more he wanted to just fly out and punch him in the face. There was far too much at stake here though and he managed to keep it cool.

Everything became apparent rather quickly, it was clear that this man wanted to violate his wife. It didn’t seem that he had many character-building encounters and was consumed by this world’s more sinful characteristics.

“Soaring Dragon Sect… I guess he went with the young master option…”

He recalled his life as Matt and how he received that strange e-mail. One of the options he could have chosen then was to become a young youth and be part of a prominent sect. This person here hit the jackpot and was now part of the big three that ruled the whole empire and it seemed that he had built himself up into a good position.

It didn’t seem that this person had the morals that he had. With so many women by his side, it felt like he should have been satisfied. There was no real reason to go to other sects and capture the wives of sect leaders. It was clear to him that this person had a screw loose.

“Or he could think that this is some kind of game…”

There was a system that allowed him to see stats. Spirit points could be gained, it worked like any role-playing game. Killing enemies gained a person more points that made them stronger. Some might lose themselves in this world, run on power, and unleash their deepest desires. This person was apparently a sexual deviant and the more he looked at him, the more this became apparent.

“If he thinks that he will get away with this, then he has another thing coming…”

Zhang Dong snapped his fingers and a wall opened up. While the elders from his sect consulted with each other he needed to prepare his counterattack.

When he entered this closer room he was greeted by glittering lights. His stack of spirit stones and other valuable resources greeted him. Weapons, armor, and untested treasures were all here.

He leaned down and picked up a handful of spirit stones. Quickly they turned to dust which fell down to his feet.

“Come to my home and try to take my wife, don’t think you can leave with your balls intact!”

Chapter 375

‘I need more time…’

There he was, sitting on the ground and hastily absorbing holy energies from some previously created pills. All of the spirit stones that he had stashed away were now gone.

The weapons that could boost his body refinement up to the great circle of core formation were now gone. All of the treasures possessing electrical energies had also been consumed in a hasty fashion that was causing him pain.

He knew that one lapse of judgment could cause him to suffer but he didn’t care. With the help of Bob and his system, he would be able to work through failures in his cultivation process.

Soon his body started exuding a new power yet he was unable to push his regular cultivation through the next step. His new tetra core cultivation method was very demanding, even more, when he tried to push it towards the great circle level.

The materials that he had stored away in this small man cave he made was also very limited. There was just not enough energy to go around. Just like before it was not equal, he needed to absorb a bit more but for this, he needed more time.

“Ten minutes is up…”

He could hear the sound coming from the other room. Most of the cameras were focused on the Soaring Dragon Sect’s flagship while the others were peeking at the room that his children were in.

From what he could tell this room was one of the safety bunkers that was deep underground. It was a specially made escape pod that could be activated and would send the people inside of it into a distant part of the forest. It was lined with special aura blocking materials so no one would be able to tell that someone was escaping.

There were a few other pods like these and he fashioned them for a limited number of people. It was supposed to carry his disciples, family, and closest friends to safety. When he returned though one person that had been there previously was missing for some reason.

He must have missed it while he was making his preparations but his disciple Zhang Liu was sprawled down on the ground. It was clear that he was still alive and just sleeping but Feng Nuana was the person that was not there anymore.

Zhang Xue on the other hand was holding both of his kids by the hands while looking at her passed-out brother. He concluded that somehow Nuana had to have put Liu to sleep for some reason while also leaving the escape pod behind.

Soon the reason became obvious as he could see her running outside. He wasn’t sure but he had a suspicion of why she was doing this.

The escape pod that they were in had similar monitors that could show the outside to them. It was clear that they had heard that sexual deviant pronounce his intentions towards his wife. While his disciples were there to keep his children, Nuana was probably more emotional towards her own sister.

‘She must have taken Liu out and made a run towards Liena…’

He wanted to smack the little sister on the head as he knew that she could not do anything worthwhile. She was only an early core formation practitioner with no way of helping out. Zhang Dong even feared that if that pervert noticed her that he would decide to take her with him as well.

Suddenly something happened that he didn’t expect. The monitors started turning red and he could feel that the large protective barrier that should have been able to last for multiple days had just turned off.

‘What the hell…?’

This barrier was made with utmost diligence and with the best materials that he could get his hands on. It should be able to resist anything that this world had to offer and the off switch was deep inside the middle of the sect. Unless someone turned it off from the inside it should not be possible.

‘The use of spirit points has been detected.’

The system gave him the answer itself. It was the young man with his own system, with its help he was able to make months of designing and years of work just vanish with a snap of the finger.

Zhang Dong now realized how people felt whenever he used his system against them. Years of hard work and planning went down the drain and the other person didn’t even need much to do it.

With even less time on his hands and more people to save he reached out with his hand towards the monitors. With a jolt from his cultivation aura, the alarms were turned off as he activated another function that was embedded into this chamber.

Through a previously set up short teleportation array, he was teleported up into his home. The gaudy castle that he was forced to live on was somewhat an eyesore. It was huge and there was far too much space in it for a small family like him to live there.

The place he appeared was right in the inner courtyard. There was a large fountain in the center that had somewhat changed in appearance. Previously it showcased a random angel with wings but now he could see that someone changed it into a statue with his appearance.

‘I guess they wanted to honor their late missing Patriarch…’

He glanced at the white statue that presented him there with a sword in hand. He moved over to it and with one swift kick the statue was sent flying to the side. Then after bending over he moved the slab of hard rock out of the way that was the base of this fountain.

While he was a bit sorry for destroying this piece of art, he needed to get to the room that was right under this statute. With the previous one removed, it didn’t seem like the opening mechanism was in place either.

It was a blunder on his part as he did not explain the full function of this system-run fortress. It was impossible to untangle some of the functions that it had from his own system. It was connected to his faction system and not one would really be able to make sense of the construction without its help.

With the fountain being thrown to the side a strange wall of metal appeared. It had various runic symbols on it that soon lit up brightly as he stood on top of it. The structure activated as a circle of about two meters in diameter around him appeared.

Soon Zhang Dong found himself moving down on this circular elevator that brought him to the insides of this large castle. While on the outside it looked like a structure fit for a king, its true functions were hidden away.

This was something that he used his years of crafting knowledge for. After absorbing all sorts of books about making treasures and upgrading them through the system he could put himself in the top five of best craftsmen that this empire had to offer.

While other masters mostly focused their skills on smaller items like weapons and pills, he had a tendency to build big. His first real step in this direction was the huge battleship that he had helped create.

The same battleship and a few other smaller similar ones were now ready and floating above the city.He could feel them activating their generators and getting ready to fire as soon as the barrier was turned off.

‘Well then, I hope this thing doesn’t just blow up on me…’

Zhang Dong found himself in some strange liquid then suddenly the light went on and he could see everything that was on the outside. He felt as if he was sitting in a pool filled with clear water but while being able to breathe.

With his eyes, he could see indicators of his troops that were part of his faction. The system was integrated into this strange room that only he would be able to operate.

During his exit from the lower room, he had also switched his clothes. He was wearing a skin-tight body suit that was similar to a wet suit. It had added armored parts on his chest and shoulders which had now cables sticking out of them that connected to the strange control room that he was in.

‘Biometric signature has been scanned, welcome administrator, would you like to activate the fortress 1?’

‘I guess it’s time to make myself known…’

“Activate all systems, activate the engines! Reactivate the shields at my command!”

While the grand formation barrier was canceled there was a way to restart it. By using up some of the stored power he could activate the reserve generators that were only accessible through his administrative privileges.

With the orders given many popup screens and loading screens turned up. The inside of the castle started to rumble as it activated as well. The outside structures started cracking as the floating fortress moved forward.

While he was saddened by the fact that he had to damage his own home that he had some fond memories in. His family was more important than material things, the kids were below ground and well protected with his disciples, they would be fine.

“The Patriarch’s castle is moving! How could this be?”

“Is the grand formation working again?”

The sect members called out at the sight of their late Patriarch’s home moving. It was a symbol that reminded them of him but most of the people here had thought him to had perished.

“People from the Soaring Dragon Sect, you are not welcome here, begone!”

His voice was heard through all the speakers that spread through the city. The large fortress that once looked like a villa started to shed its outer shell. Many cannons appeared from within and all of them were pointed at the ships and cultivators from the Soaring Dragon Sect.

“That Voice… could it really be?”

Zhang Liena backed away from the reactivated barrier and looked to her home approaching. While she wanted to believe that her husband was back, it could have been some intricate treasure with his voice.

“I’m sure you would rather do nothing more than to attack us but before we start killing ourselves I’d wish to speak with that person… yes the person called… Wang Long…”

Zhang Dong had his system so even through the computer screens he could see the man’s name floating above his head. It was clear that he went for a similar style of naming but for some reason reversed the last name with his name.

“What is that? Did we activate a hidden boss?”

The pervert called out while not even seeming alarmed by the appearance of the flying castle.

‘Bob, can you directly connect me to his system, so we can have a private conversation?’

‘Affirmative, connecting now.’

With one last try, Zhang Dong decided to try the olive branch approach. The person was not of this world, so maybe if he knew that he was interacting with another ‘player’ he might see things differently.

‘Connection established.’

“Hello there Long Wang, we need to talk…”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 376

The large floating fortress with cannons pointed in all directions halted its advance. The cultivators from the United Element Sect recognized that the voice that came from it belonged to their Patriarch.

While some of them cheered out, others were concerned. Did the Patriarch really return or was this just some pre-recorded voice line that this floating weapon possessed? There was also the problem with it being openly hostile towards the Soaring Dragon Sect.

Some of the elders were still hopeful that giving up one or two women would save the rest from bloodshed. While everyone was speculating and discussing with each other another conversation that could not be heard by anyone else was taking place.

“Long Wang huh?”

“How are you talking to me?”

“Did you think that you are the only one that has a system? Things are not how you might think, stop treating this like a game.”

“Wait? Do you have a system too? You’re a player just like me?”

Zhang Dong with the help of Bob had managed to hack his way into the communication function of Wang Long’s system. He wanted to do nothing more than to punch this guy in the face. Regretfully people's lives were at stake, if he could talk his way out of this mess he needed to try.

“Player? This is not a game, why are you attacking my sect? The woman that you are trying to take away is my wife.”

“Your wife? Are you one of those role play types or something?”

“Huh?”

“Well I did try that one time, but I was never good with those romance games, getting the correct dialogue checks was confusing.”

The man called Wang Long gave out a sigh and started going on a tangent. While listening Zhang Dong realized that this person didn’t see the people living in this world as true living beings.

It was clear that he thought that they were nothing more than a part of some program. The system allowed people to see people's stats, even alignments. It also sometimes advanced its features to suit what the user wanted.

He was a witness to such things as when he desired the teleportation feature that had just appeared there. This could have happened to this man as well, maybe his system was presenting him with emotional-related statics like affection.

Even Zhang Dong had similar stats in his faction system. He could see how well his people were doing, it was all presented to him with things like the satisfaction level of his people. If he didn’t invest in his clan as he did he might have still been thinking like this person.

“Wait... hold up, these people aren’t NPC’s, have you actually sat down and talked to one without your status looming over them?”

While Zhang Dong started out thinking in a similar way as this person. It started changing over the years, he was a more compassionate person from the start which probably caused him to see the humanity in these strange cultivators.

They all had their problems but they all had goals just like him. While they acted reserved when people with status were involved they also laughed and cried.

This he mostly learned when he was out on his travels. When he pretended to be someone else he did visit restaurants, taverns and even looked at the people in the villages. He just couldn’t see them as part of some strange program. They were certainly not soulless puppets as this person was claiming.

“Damn, are you being serious right now? You role-player types always got too much into your strange fantasies. Wait, aren't we forgetting something? How come you also have a system? could this be some trick?”

“Did you think that you were the only one? You are not the only person with a system.”

“This is bull-shit! I thought this was a single-player PVE experience! Does this mean that I have to worry about getting ganked by other players? Wait, why should I even trust you? Hah, you almost got me but I’m too smart for such an obvious trick!”

“Wait, what are you talking abou…”

It seemed that the person he was talking with was not the trusting type. He started accusing Zhang Dong of a scheme. The person was clearly a gamer that was used to playing certain player versus player-related content. Some of these games were quite toxic and people loved killing others just to troll them in any way possible.

“Damn, I didn’t know that you could go into faction versus faction combat, I bet I’ll get a massive boost in spirit points if I win this fight…”

“Wait, this isn’t what…”

“Shut up, you think that you can pull a fast one on me? Go screw yourself!”

The connection was cut off soon after and Bob reported that this Wang Long had used some of his points to set up some kind of communication barrier that would require Zhang Dong to also spend points.

‘Shit, what is this idiot even thinking? Did he lose himself to the debauchery of this world?’
While Zhang Dong had a rather reserved personality and it came hard for him to interact with women, this person seemed to be the total opposite. He treated everyone as mere NPC's in the game and probably didn’t suffer any remorse when something happened to them.

“Young master are you alright?”

He looked into the distance and could hear a member from the Soaring Dragon Sect calling out to Wang Long.

“Yes I’m fine, let us continue with the attack! They are clearly disrespecting our sect!”

The barrier was reactivated but he had to jump start it. This used up some of the power reserves which would cause it to shut down a lot sooner.

“Wang Long or Long Wang, stop this, you don’t realize what this world really is, we can still discuss it!”

While his connection to Wang Long’s system was down he could still talk through the fortress and the city speakers.

“Do you think that I’m stupid? You just want to gank me and take away all of my spirit points! I’m not going to trust some idiot in a backwater sect like this.”

“Listen to me, you idiot!”

“Screw you!”

The little back and forth between the two was clearly heard by the people around it. It didn’t seem like it was going anywhere as the two cultivators started calling themselves strange names like cucks, simps, and incels.

“Enough! Tong attack, at least I’ll be able to see if there is a respawn feature in this game! Burn the city to the ground but leave the women alive!”

It seemed that the time was up and the young master pointed out with his finger towards the barrier. The ships in the back that were prepared started gathering up energy and soon they started to assault the city.

The people from the Soaring Dragon Sect would soon discover that it would not be such a one-sided slaughter. The barrier that was created here was not like the other ones fashioned in this world. While the defensive capabilities were lowered it also possessed a certain feature.

Zhang Dong flying fort’s cannons were already ready to discharge similar spiritual bullets. Normally this would be impossible as the barrier was a two-way barrier. With some testing though he had managed to get the energies in tune with each other. Thanks to this the deathly energy-packed bullets would be able to pass through it.

Soon the energy bullets were released and they were not only coming from this flying castle. The whole city was a massive fort filled with automated weaponry. All of this firepower lit up the sky and the ships from the Soaring Dragon Sect started being suppressed.

“How is this possible? Their protective formation is still up? How can they return fire!”

Tong called out in fright while holding one of his palms forward to produce a shield of his own.

“Elders, summon your soul beast, protect the ships!”

While the automated weapons that were scattered around the whole city emerged from some buildings, the people from the sect were still confused.

“Elder Liena, is this your doing?”

“Huh? What do you mean?”

“Who else but you would profit from this chaos?”

Asked a rather angry looking man from the Huo clan.

“Be quiet father, you should know that only Senior Brother would be able to do this…”

“The Patriarch? Could he really be alive?”

Huo Qiang shrugged while looking to Zhang Liena and Zhang Jin for answers. The old man looked to the large floating fortress that was shedding its skin and revealing some kind of metal contraption underneath.

“I’m not sure, it could have been some weapon left by Dong’er that was activated when his wife was in danger…”

Zhang Jin looked at Liena who was still staring at what used to be her home crumbling into dust. Her expression that was filled with astonishment quickly changed to one of curiosity and longing.

“Nuana, stay here, the rest of you… what are you doing? It’s already too late to bargain, you heard that bastard, they are going to turn this city, our city, to cinders if we don’t stop them. Even if it’s the Soaring Dragon Sect, they are not impossible to beat, let us focus on this battle first and then deliberate on our future actions!”

After giving a little battle speech she departed towards the island that was approaching them slowly. It didn’t seem that her advance would be stopped as even when she was right next to the cannons they didn’t fire at her.

She descended onto the part that was the main courtyard. The buildings that were once her home were in tatters. The whole place was shaking as the cannon fire continued endlessly. With each shot of these cannons, more of the marble crumbled and more of the buildings crumbled.

“Husband? Are you there? Is it really you?”

She called out, her breath heavy as she was unsure of what was happening. While the conversation between the bastard that tried to take her away and this flying fortress was quite animated it didn’t mean that it was her husband.

Leaving behind part of one's memories was a technique that some cultivators could use. Her husband could very well have left a part of himself behind that could somewhat speak and reason. It would not be him if this was true.

“Zhang Dong? ZHANG DONG? Where are you?”

Her shouts were met with silence and as she was almost ready to give up hope she noticed something. A large glowing circle appeared in the spot that once had a large fountain on it.

The light was there and it was humming, without thinking much she decided to stand right on it. The moment she did, the ground under her shook slightly and she started descending.

Soon a strange feeling took over her, it was pitch black in here and she dropped into something. It felt like she was submerged in some kind of liquid. She wasn’t prepared for this so she opened her mouth and it made its way inside which caused her to panic.

“Relax, the spirit fluid won’t hurt you.”

She then heard a familiar voice which was followed by light returning to her eyes.

“You should have regained your senses, it's a strange feeling at first but you’ll get used to it.”

Once her breath returned and her vision got clear she found herself in a certain man’s lap.

“It’s been a while, hasn’t it…my wife.”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 377

While Zhang Dong was concentrating on the battle he almost didn’t notice that he had a visitor. His wife appeared in the middle of what used to be his home. While he was a bit preoccupied with what he was doing and this was not the place for a family reunion, the moment she started shouting his emotions got the better of him.

While this place he was in was not really made for more than one person, he could squeeze in one caramel beauty in. It was a little funny to see her panic when she was submerged in the special fluid but soon he found himself opening up his arms to catch her.

It took a moment for it to sink in. Watching the people through the screen wasn’t the same as actually being right next to them. He could feel her body pressing into his which made him instinctively move them around her back. It was as if he feared that she would just vanish into tiny soap bubbles if he didn’t hold her tightly.

Soon he could tell that sight had returned to his wife. She could finally see him and it was clear that she was unable to mutter a word. A tiny moment passed between the two where they just kept looking at each other without saying a word.

If it was any other time he wished that this moment could continue to eternity. But fate was cruel and the sight of explosions and the chaos outside brought Zhang Dong to his senses.

“It’s been a while…”

He called out to her, Liena looked at him with even more intent before giving an answer.

“Is… is it truly you?”

“Who else could it be?

She narrowed her eyes and he could feel that she was using her spiritual sense on him. He was glad that she was not being too gullible as he could have truly been some other entity taking the form of her husband.

It was really him though so the spiritual scan was allowed as he dropped all of his defenses. Liena would soon find out that it was indeed her husband but he was not the same as before. The largest change was his cultivation level that seemed to have regressed.

“It is truly you… but... “

“Yes, my cultivation has changed slightly but I wouldn’t consider myself much weaker than what I was before, I just need some time to recover.”

He quickly replied to at least alleviate some of the questions. While his cultivation level had decreased, the improved version of the core formation realm was close to what his old nascent soul level was. If he managed to break through into the great circle he might actually be slightly stronger than before.

“Truly my husband has returned?”
“Yes, that’s what I… is something wrong?”

Soon he could see his wife's eyes closing. If this wasn’t inside of a special pod filled with liquid he would be seeing her tears streaming down her face. She suddenly slung her arms around his neck and gave him a big hug. Her voice started getting more muddled as she started to sob.

Without being able to do much, he just returned the hug and started to rub her back. The embrace lasted for a few moments but soon he felt some resistance as she started pushing herself back. When she did he could see that her face was devoid of sadness which was now replaced by anger.

“Where were you?”

“Well… that’s going to be hard to explain…”

“You better have a good explanation!”

“My dear wife, I don’t think this is a good time to be arguing. I think we have more important matters to attend to…”

Zhang Dong backed away while trying to soothe his angry wife. It was understandable that she was angry as her husband just popped out of nowhere and seemed mostly fine. If he was in her shoes he would also be quite livid if a family member appeared out of nowhere after being seen as dead.

She looked back and could also see what was happening outside. While the automatic cannons could shoot at the invaders the other cultivators couldn’t. Without attuning their techniques to match the barrier they could just sit there and look at the enemies.

The biggest problem was the large number of nascent soul elders protecting their ships. Along with their soul beasts, they could protect those battleships from the cannon fire while also attacking the barrier.

It was turning into a battle of attrition, would the barrier give out or would the nascent soul experts run out of juice first? While Zhang Dong didn’t really know what the end plan of these attackers was, they certainly did seem like they were in a hurry.

The force that they brought over was quite large for something like this. It was excessive for going against a middle-sized sect. Either the Soaring Dragon Sect had a lot of resources to spare or they wanted to get it over with fast.

The best way to do such a thing would be to overwhelm their opponents with firepower. With ten late stage nascent soul elders and one at the great circle realm, they could steamroll any normal middle-sized sect.

They were out of luck with this one as with the system's help and Zhang Dong’s knack for crafting they were in for a prolonged siege. That was also not counting in all the buried escaped tunnels that blocked out spiritual sense from coming in. They would be in for quite a chase if they ever wanted to get to every last sect member that was here.

“I hope that you have a plan.”

“A plan…”

“If not… I could still try…”

“No.”

He shook his head while glaring at Liena that flinched.

“I’d rather die than have you go with that bastard.”

“But what about the Sect? What about…”

“What about you? What about our children? They need their mother!”

Zhang Dong shouted out but soon gave out a sigh as he caught a fearful expression in his wife.

“It doesn’t matter now, that bastard won’t let us go.”

He heard the one called Wang Long call out. It seemed that he was planning on getting rid of every male member from the sect and just taking all the women with them. Probably the less good-looking ones would follow in the footsteps of the men. The ones that made the cut could look forward to a life of slavery.

“But can we win? This is the Soaring Dragon Sect and you are also weakened!”

“Don’t worry, we have a chance of survival, luckily our opponent isn’t the brightest.”

Zhang Dong tried to calm Liena down, while it didn’t look good there was still a chance of walking out of this battle alive. This would be possible thanks to it being their home ground. The advantage was actually on their side as they were only involved in a defensive battle.

What was needed was just some bait and if their enemies took it, then victory was assured. Luckily the man in charge wasn’t really the elder at the great circle level. While he might have been the strongest of them, the person in charge was the otherworlder.

This person had many glaring flaws that could be used during this fight. It was clear to Zhang Dong that Wang Long lacked any real combat experience. Just like him before he received the system degrading he was very dependent on it.

His faction was also a big reason why he would fail. Being brought up in a powerful sect had its advantages but there were some disadvantages when being brought up as a young master. These he would now try to exploit along with the man’s pride. He knew very well how it could cause one to lose himself.

“So be it, I shall put my faith and the sect's faith in you my husband! If we fail, then we will fail together!”

He smiled at the proclamation from his lovely wife. While he was not interested in perishing here, he had a backup plan that would allow his wife and kids to survive. It was not much of a plan but at least his loved ones would be safe.

It was a strange feeling to finally have something that he wanted to protect. When he thought back to his old life that he lived in the modern world it wasn’t all that bad. While he didn’t have much going for himself he was still free and with no responsibilities other than himself.

Now, on the other hand, people's lives were dependent on his decisions. With a wave of his hand, he could decide if people lived or died. At first, he felt that he would be crushed under the weight of this responsibility but then he found something that he could fight for.

The selfish void in his heart was replaced by memories of his new family and friends. When he looked at the grinning expression of the person named Wang Long he could only pity him. The man clearly lost himself and was unable to find something that was above surface level.

The pity that he felt would not hold him back from ending his life though. He was still an opponent that made his decision.

“Hah, that’s why I love you.”

He smiled one last time before pulling Liena into a prolonged kiss. When their lips parted he could see her blushing which only made him want to protect her even more.

“While I intended to make this as a one seater, some more spiritual energy is always better.”

Zhang Dong said while stretching out his hand towards Liena.

“Will you lend me your strength?”

“Do you really need to ask?”

She just smiled and they both interlocked their fingers. Now with Liena sitting in his lap and lending him some of her spiritual energy the fortress exploded with even more energy. The cannon fire increased and the enemies from the Soaring Dragon Sect even found themselves being pushed back.

“Liena, help me talk to the other elders, they’ll probably listen to you more than me.”

Liena nodded while Zhang Dong used his connection with the system to contact Zhang Jin along with Huo Qiang. Both of them were very influential figures in their own right, with their help he would be putting his hastily put-together plan in motion.

“Hey there, gramps and you to Qiang, it’s been a while, I need you to do something for me…”

Even though he was inside this fortress and he couldn’t really see them, he could feel their gazes shooting towards the crumbling castle that he was in. It was finally time to turn this thing around, if everyone made it out alive would depend on how stupid and prideful their opponents were...

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 378

“Young master, we might have to retreat, for now, I must remind you that this is a critical moment for our sect, our time should be used elsewhere. The elders that had come with us will be needed for the coming…”

“Be quiet Tong, that can wait but this can’t!”

Elder Tong looked at the young master that had a peculiar expression on his face. This was the face of a man that was consumed by something. It was an uncommon thing to see this young master striving for something but the timing could not have been worse.

Tong could somewhat measure the defensive and offensive capabilities of the sect they were facing. They were more or less at a stalemate, they were somewhat at an advantage as the United Element’s sect was stationary.

If they kept at it long enough the defensive formation would falter but it would falter later than sooner. This elder feared that it would take up too much time and cause their enemies to go through some plans of their own.

The ten late stage nascent soul elders that they were using here was not a small number. The group here could more or less conquer the middle sized sects if they attacked them one by one all by themselves.

Tong feared that their resources could be spent elsewhere and after they were done with their main plan they could honor the young masters' conquests. Thus he decided to report this to the Patriarch, maybe he could convince the true leader of the sect to force this unruly grandson to back off for now.

They were giving a certain time window to clear things up, while this window had not passed yet he feared that they would not meet the deadline. But before he could grab the communication jade he noticed something, the barrier started faltering.

“Hm? Isn’t that a bit too early?”

The protective barrier that had stood like a solid wall of energy started flickering as if it was running out of energy. He could even see some of the spiritual bullets that were being fired from their own ships penetrating into it and some damage being caused to the buildings below.

“Hah you see that Tong? I knew that the bastard was using some tricks, the system can’t be beaten! This is our chance, everyone attack! Remember that we take the women!”

Some of the cultivators that were manning the ships shouted out in unison. Tong knew well why those people were quite ecstatic at what the young master had said.

This was not the first time that something like this was happening. There were some other lesser-known sects that were flattened by this Wang Long. Every time he would capture the women and kill the men.

Then the ones that were deemed not beautiful enough he would give away to the other sect members. They would be free to do with them as they wanted, which led mostly to a life of slavery and misery. Consumed by lust and egged on by the young master the sect members were more willing to do things that they wouldn’t normally do.

“Young master please wait, doesn’t this all feel strange? Would this grand formation just fail almost instantly right after being reactivated?”

Tong tried to reason with Wang Long as he was afraid that they could be going into a trap. While he believed that they would be able to punch through this barrier in time, it was too soon. There was also that large thing that was floating about and raining cannon fire on them.

At first, it looked like a giant castle that was situated on a giant boulder but now he could see strange metallic parts under it.

“Strange? Nothing is strange, they probably used up the remaining energy to restart the formation while trying to scare us off. They clearly failed as I called their bluff, just follow my lead old man, and let's get on with this!”

Tong was ignored and while he had his reservations what the young master said could have been true. After the reactivation of the barrier, he noticed that his young master was talking with someone.

Even without him telling the elders to act they were moving forward. He was the strongest person here but he was not the one with the most prestige. Everyone here knew that the young master would be the next sect leader, thus they were afraid to get on his bad side.

He would really need to put his foot down and threaten them if he wanted them to go against the young master’s wishes. He was nothing more than a costly bodyguard and his only mission was to keep Wang Long safe.

Thus he kept his eyes open while advancing slightly behind the other ten elders. The people from the United Element’s sect were seen by him and they were escaping to where their main sect was located.

The nascent soul elders from their side were using their soul beasts as shields while everyone else backed off. The flying fortress in the sky had also halted its advance as it started to back away slowly.

“Look at them flee, don’t let them escape, they probably have a secondary protective formation deeper!”

The cannons that were firing at them were quickly picked off by the ten nascent soul elders and their soul beasts. Along with their flying ships, they started decimating the Spirit Spring city.

It seemed like the obvious conclusion of this fight, why the Patriarch from the United Element Sect had decided to fight was unclear to Tong. The logical conclusion was to hand over his wife and be glad that they didn’t need to give up more.

To this old man, the survival of the sect far outweighs the survival of his own family members. If he could offer them up in exchange for long-lasting prosperity to his faction, it would be the greatest honor.

His hesitation was slowly fading away as it seemed that the others were just backing off and ready to make their last stand. Now he was only concerned about them all running away and them having to chase them down. It would be quite a headache if they needed to play a cat and mouse game and chase after them.

Thus he was ready to give the ten elders the order to quickly encircle the main sect and not give them space to escape. Before that could happen a flash of blue caught them off guard…

…..

Back in the flying fortress Zhang Dong and Liena were looking at the advancing enemies.

“They really took the bait as you said.”

“It looks that way, It’s time for phase two of the plan!”

Just as one of their enemies expected, this was just a ruse. There was enough energy to run the barrier for weeks even if they continued to pelt each other with spirit bullets.

Zhang Dong knew that they had a fighting chance as long as they fought at the location of his faction. He wasn’t sure about his enemy but his system did present him with a buff whenever he was at his faction’s main location.

With him present, he could activate a buff that would cause people that he had high affinity with to be stronger. This mostly included people from the old Zhang Clan like his grandfather and Zhang Zhi but also people like Huo Qiang.

Thus the problem was to keep the enemies around this specific location. This they could only achieve by entrapping them here. The barrier had not faltered and there was enough energy to activate it yet again. When the bulk of the enemy ships and all of the nascent cultivators were at the right spot, Zhang Dong sprung his trap.

The formation was reactivated and its blue light shone strongly as it encompassed the bulk of the Soaring Dragon Sect inside. The key locations of the barrier were hidden away under the rubble. It would be possible to deactivate it if their enemies managed to gain information about their locations.

Luckily this was a forceful approach with not much planning behind it. The Soaring Dragon Sect clearly wasn’t prepared for any deviations to their plan. They were assured of their own might being enough to push them through any adversity.

“Are you ready Qiang?”

“I was born ready!”

“Good, this might feel funny…”

Zhang Dong moved into his faction window and activated the buff that would enhance the strength of his faction members. Depending on their loyalty it could go all the way up to 50%.

The faction system that he had upgraded with time did not suffer as much as his crafting system. Thus it kept most of its functions with one in particular which he would need to win this battle.

He was able to select a champion from his faction, this would allow this person to gain even further enhanced capabilities along with the factionwide buff. With Qiang being the strongest person now, even outperforming Zhang Dong due to his lowered cultivation level this choice was obvious.

Huo Qiang was outside and gaining speed, he could feel his muscles twitching in anticipation of the fight he would be having. Zhang Dong had contacted him not so long ago and tasked him with holding back the nascent soul master that was at the great circle level.

At first, he thought that he would be sacrificing his life for the cause but it seemed that this wasn’t the case. Soon he realized that newfound power was entering his body, he felt strong and powerful as he exploded into a fiery inferno.

His body went through a strange transformation. It felt like he was burning up from the inside and all of his flesh was turning dark as coal. Soon it all caught flame and he felt as if he broke through into the late stage and maybe even beyond.

The change was quick and to the point. His body was covered by a dark red firmament of flames which made him look like a fire elemental. This new form gave him the feeling of being able to destroy anything in his path, even his soul beast that was right behind him expanded in size.

The fire Ifrit started looking like a devil made from molten rock. Its horns and tail expanded in size and were black as obsidian. The temperature around it caused everything that was in close proximity to instantly melt or evaporate.

He wasn’t the only one suffering from a change to their being. Zhang Zhi, who was dressed in a white robe and was wearing a snow-white katana on his side, could feel his muscles contracting. With sword in hand, he charged at one of the late stage masters, not afraid of losing.

“United Element Sect, Attack!”

Zhang Dong’s voice was heard from the flying fortress and soon the fight commenced. With the formation keeping anyone from leaving, only when the last enemy was dead would this battle end.

Chapter 379

A large object was moving through the air while receiving damage from massive amounts of spirit-filled attacks. Even though it was getting pelted from all sides it continued to fire back.

Finally, its outer shell was blasted apart and there was nothing left from the large castle that it once was. What greeted the attackers was a strange-looking shiny metallic sphere with many cannons sticking out of it.

The attackers from the Soaring Dragon Sect were doing their utmost to continue with their attacks on the giant mechanical thing and they were slowly whittling it down. It had thick armor plating that was posing a problem and the longer it took for them to pierce through the more damage did their own ships suffer.

They had gone into a trap, the whole city and part of the sky above was encased in a dome through which they could not leave. Soon after they felt a massive spike in their opponents' cultivation level, it was as if they were holding back and only now showed their true might.

Elder Tong, their best fighter at this moment, was engaged in a brutal confrontation with a man that looked to be made out of strange fire. Both of them were not riding on their soul beasts that were clashing with each other.

Huo Qiang was standing on the top of his Ifrit’s head that had gone through a size increase. Up against him was an eastern-style dragon with an emerald coat of scales. While the length of the dragon was about four times of the ifrit, it wasn’t as wide.

As the emerald dragon tried coiling itself around his opponent it received an uppercut to its head which sent it tumbling back. It released emerald bolts of lightning which were somehow absorbed by this creature that was actually made out of plasma and not fire.

“Is that all you have, great elder from the Soaring Dragon Sect?”

“You…”

Huo Qiang gave out a laugh while pushing himself towards his opponent. Both of them started crashing through the entire city and the residual shockwaves caused the buildings to crumble.

While this battle was happening the other elders from the United Element’s sect were trying to engage the other ten nascent soul elders. While they weren’t as strong, they were strong enough to cause them damage.

They weren’t alone, many of the lesser cultivators that were still at the core formation level banded together to form battle formations. These beasts made from condensed spiritual energy were as powerful as the people going against them.

Argonaut 1 the sect's flagship was already charging its main cannon to deliver a devastating blow to the enemy's huge flying vessel. While it started off bleak and with no hope, it looked like the defensive capabilities of the United Element Sect were enormous.

It was far larger than what a regular middle-sized sect should be able to produce. The longer the battle continued the more the people from the Soaring Dragon Sect realized this. They were assured of their victory when they charged in, now on the other hand they were not sure if they would be able to make it out alive.

“What are you doing? Just kill them all!”

Wang Long shouted out while using a sword to counter a peculiar-looking cultivator.

“You’re annoying, just die!”

His sword was met with another peculiar-looking one. While it was thinner and longer than the Jian it looked to be quite sharp.

This was Zhang Zhi from the United Element’s Sect that had picked out his opponent from all of the chaos. While Huo Qiang was keeping Tong busy the young master was unprotected which made it a good chance for him to capture the second biggest threat.

“Isn’t that a dai-katana?”

Wang Long called out as he was confused about seeing this type of weapon in the hand of a cultivator. He was facing off against a man that would be more fit to be in a world filled with ancient samurai.

The man didn’t reply while slicking forward. His blade started glowing and Wang Long quickly dodged to the side. The energy from the blade that was one long line started splitting apart into a thousand.

“Annoying!”

Instead of evading them, the young master used his own sword to defend himself. His Qi was gathered onto the blade, the previously white blade turned purple and bolts of lightning started shooting out from it. He performed a sideways swipe which caused the sword energies to collide with the other which in term canceled each other out.

“Stop moving around!”

The exchange continued for a moment and it was clear that the samurai was below the young master’s level in terms of power. Even then, the young man found it hard to land a clean blow as the member from the United Element sect was finding ways to dodge at the exact right moment.

“Your strength is great but your lack of technique and experience is painfully obvious!”

“Hah? Do you think I haven’t heard that before? What do I need technique for when I can kill anyone with just one shot? Now try dodging this!”

Wang Long pointed out with his finger at his opponent. A strange dark shadowy bracelet appeared on his wrist from which four chains that were covered in black energy shot out.

They traveled at an astonishing speed and were upon his opponent in a fraction of a second. The samurai used his sword energies to try to deflect this attack but as he tried he noticed that his attacks went right through these ghostly chains.

His next step was to quickly retreat but try if he might he wasn’t able to shake these chains free. They followed him everywhere and even when he tried to get behind some cover they just went through it.

“Just give up, I spend so many spirit points to get that rare binding skill!”

Wang Long laughed out and soon his opponent found himself being shackled by this skill. Both his wrists and ankles were being constrained and Zhang Zhi felt that this attack was even affecting his nascent soul. He was momentarily paralysed and unable to move, he could feel that if he had enough time he could break free but would his opponent give him that?

“Hah, it never fails to get them.”

Wang Long pointed his sword up into the sky and energy started gathering on it. Zhang Zhi could tell that the power behind this skill was massive. Normally he would be able to easily evade it but with these shackles, he was a sitting duck.

“Another one bites the dust!”

Wang Long started swinging his sword down, the massive torrent of energy was about to get discharged but right before he could complete his sword technique another blast of energy approached him.

“What the?”

Wang Long was submerged in a blast that came from the side.

“Young Master!”

“It’s not wise to look away during a fight, old man.”

Elder Tong noticed that Wang Long had been directly hit by a blast coming from the large flying fortress. But as he tried to move to help the young lord he was interrupted by Huo Qiang’s fist which he had to block.

“I’m fine old man, no need to scream like a little girl.”

Zhang Zhi was finally able to get himself out of the strange ethereal shackles but the young man that he was facing was clearly alive. After the beam attack subsided his form covered by a thin flickering barrier could be seen. One of the rings he was wearing that was previously quite bright had its gem become cloudy after this attack was received.

“Protective treasures? Did you buy them in the system store or did you receive them from your own sect? Must be nice to go with the easiest starting location.”

The voice of a certain man came from the side and when people turned to it they saw someone that they didn’t expect to ever see again, Zhang Dong the Sect Patriarch. Zhang Zhi’s eyes went wide and some of the other cultivators that were busy fighting stopped in their tracks.

“From the shop of course? Why would I use the items they give me when I can get better ones from the cash shop… what the hell are you even wearing, first the samurai now armor? What are you supposed to be, a power ranger?”

Zhang Dong approached slowly from the skies. The item he was wearing looked like a more modernized suit of armor that snuggly clung to his body. It was white with golden outlines and had his sect's insignia written out on his back.

“Something like that, it’s not too late to leave, I’m sure you could talk to your people and make this blow over.”

“My people? I think you’ve been living with these NPC’s for too long and lost it.”

Zhang Dong frowned as he heard the reply. It didn’t feel right to go against someone from his original world but the man was not giving him much choice. It was clear that he was taking this like some kind of elaborate game that came down to gaining points. Even now he was probably wondering if he would get a special bonus for killing an actual system holder.

“I think you are the one that has lost it, fine… Have it your way.”

Liena at this moment was left inside of the large fortress and was giving it some of her spiritual energy to run it. He had given her a crash course about piloting it, only when the attackers managed to blast through its plating was she to leave.

While their reuniting was brief he needed to do this himself. Liena would do more by piloting the large orb of cannons as it could easily keep the enemy ships and some of the nascent cultivators at bay.

“Why would I have it any other way? This is just a playground for me, but you seem to have a different idea… and what’s this? Ha ha…”

Wang Long started laughing after Zhang Dong placed a helmet over his face. But it didn’t look like his armor was the true reason he was laughing.

“Core formation? You are still only at the core formation level? How am I to get any points if you’re below my level?”

Just like Zhang Dong, Wang Long could see his enemies stats and realms. He knew the weakness of that approach though. The system did disclose the realms but this could be misleading if someone like him was involved.
His response was not in words but with a fist to Wang Long's face. The armor that he was wearing started giving out a golden hue and his power was boosted to a new level.

The young master from the Soaring Dragon Sect made a nice arc and landed five hundred meters away. His body slammed into a yet not destroyed building that now crumbled and dropped down on him.

“Go help the other elders Zhang Zhi, leave this idiot to me.”

“As you wish, Patriarch!”

Zhang Zhi nodded and then flew away. He knew that Zhang Dong would be able to bring victory to the sect like he always did. Even if it meant to go against the Azure Emperor he would follow his Patriarch all till the end.

Chapter 380

There they stood, two people from a different world that now came together on the battlefield. Zhang Dong was on one side wearing a somewhat uncharacteristic white and golden armor. It made him look like a certain metallic superhero from a comic book that he used to read when he was younger.

On the other side, there was Wang Long, a person that he just met. Both of them might have come from the same world and might have even had similar backgrounds. While one chose to succumb to the carnal pleasures of this world where power was paramount, the other managed to retain some of his core values.

“Were you one of those cringe weebs or something?”

“I guess talking sense into you will be impossible…”

Zhang Dong raised his sword up over his head and was ready to deliver a strike.

“Do you think you can win against me? With such a low cultivation level? You really didn’t use your time well to grind for points.”

Wang Long laughed while waving his own sword around. From his perspective, he had a clear advantage. Zhang Dong could also see that his opponent was at the nascent soul stage and in the middle realm of it.

The time he was gone has given the man time to catch up but from Zhang Dong’s perspective, his level was somewhat low. He was a member of a prestigious clan but he only managed to get to the same point that he did before he was ejected from this world.

This person’s progress was somewhat slow but there were a few explanations. When he was looking at how he behaved it was somewhat clear to him why.

“Low cultivation huh?”

He replied while also quickly swinging his sword downward. Wang Long just snorted and released a blast from his own sword which turned purple. The two surges of energies collided with each other and canceled themselves out.

There was a clear surprise on Wang Long’s face as he probably expected to overpower Zhang Dong’s strike with pure cultivation power. But this moment of confusion would not be wasted by his enemy.

Zhang Dong’s body faded away as the area that he was previously in had only an after image left behind. Wang Long’s reaction was somewhat slow as a protective barrier around his body appeared and he finally turned to the side. There he saw a blade being pressed against this barrier that was protecting him.

“You little shit!”

He swung back but his opponent quickly dodged in a strange fashion. His heightened senses pointed him to where he vanished to but when he swung his blade towards that spot it was as if Zhang Dong knew that the attack was going and was able to parry.

The two fighters started clashing through the sky and one of them was obviously coming out on top. Soon the exchange ended and Wang Long’s face started contorting into an ugly frown.

“How the hell… it’s that armor isn’t it?”

Zhang Dong didn’t reply as he was done with the talking. The diplomatic approach had been refused by Wang Long so he would not give him an opportunity to back out now.

‘This guy clearly doesn’t know how to fight.’

After the couple exchanges, Zhang Dong came to this conclusion. Wang Long’s cultivation was high and if he tried to pit power against power, Zhang Dong would be on the losing end. This he was able to counter with his superior battle scene which he gained through experience.

It was clear that Wang Long was a protected young master. While he might have had to prove himself somewhat at the lower realms, it was clear that he had not advanced past a certain threshold.

Battling at the foundation establishment and core formation level was quite different from the nascent soul level. The enhanced spiritual sense that a nascent soul master had could be used in certain ways to read your opponent's movements.

The two masters would pit it against each other to affect the flow battle. For some reason, this Wang Long was not very good at doing this so he could read him like an open book. After progressing to this level it was obvious that he didn’t study the techniques that were available to him.

With his status of Soaring Dragon Sect's future Patriarch, he had a big shield around him. No one in their right mind would try to offend him or ask him for a sparring match. Thus Zhang Dong believed that his opponent didn’t actually know how to fully use his current abilities.

The system was also probably responsible. He remembered the days when he was also dependent on it. Instead of learning the techniques himself he spent his days using points on skills that sounded cool and had a good rating.

Some points were used on abilities that were not even that good or somewhat similar to others that he already had. After the system store went away he was forced to actually train his skills up but then he finally noticed that being proficient in his skills was actually better.

It was much better to train in a certain sword art that he could also later upgrade with his system than to buy a new sword skill from the store. This was probably what this man he was facing doing. When he was done with the lower level skill he just replaced it with a new version that might not particularly go well with his own fighting style.

‘It would be nice if that was the case but I’m not doing much to him either way…’

While he didn’t find it hard to land a few hits here and there, he wasn’t able to do any damage. Any time he went in for the kill a protective barrier surrounded Wang Long’s whole body. It was as if he had an intelligent defensive formation on his body that sprung up every time he was in danger.

“Don’t get ahead of yourself, this fight has almost started, let me show you the difference in levels!”

Wang Long called out while being surrounded by a haze of purple energy that also was lightning-based. Zhang Dong backed away as he was unsure of what was coming but soon he realized that his opponent was bringing out one of his trump cards, his soul beast.

“Wait… isn’t that…”

He was a bit surprised by the appearance of this soul beast that Wang Long summoned. The purple energy that he was covered with and the lightning strikes also felt familiar. The moment the soul beast was revealed it all made sense.

“A black lightning dragon?”

There it was before him, it was not quite as big as his own soul beast golden dragon but it wasn’t far behind. During the exchanges that he had with the man, he also noticed the peculiar element that he was using was very similar to his own.

It looked like both of them went with the lightning element when it came to making their character. The only difference was that Wang Long went with the purple lightning that offered more attacking power while he went with the golden variant that was more universal and added healing.

“That armor might be making you stronger but without a soul beast you are just like a trash mob!”

Wang Long laughed while pointing with his finger, this caused the large black dragon to howl in anger and discharge purple lightning bolts towards Zhang Dong. His body was submerged in this strange purple lightning energy as he was not able to dodge.

“Yeah, that’s what I’m talking about, now give me all of your spirit points!”

The laughs continued for a while but soon Wang Long noticed that something was off. His enemy was being surrounded by electrical energy but he was not screaming. It was as if the attack wasn’t affecting him at all.

“Dragon, crank it up, use your breath attack!”
Wang Long pointed out with his hand and the dragon opened up its large toothy maw. In front of it, the lightning energy started to condense into a shape of a circle before it was fired off towards Zhang Dong.

If Wang Long had any battle sense in him, he would know that something wasn’t right. His opponent didn’t even try escaping after the first attack was broken and he did nothing to dodge this one either.

The torrent of energy connected and everyone was greeted with a magnificent light show. The elders that were fighting in the distance looked to the side and even some from the United Element’s Sect cried out in fright.

Zhang Dong that was inside of this torrent of energy on the other hand didn’t move a muscle. He just let this energy flow through him while concentrating. The terrifying energy blast that was just pure condensed lightning energy instead of increasing started to slowly falter and vanish.

“What? Dragon what are you doing, kill him!”

The Soul-Beast listened to its master and continued to inject more of its spiritual energy into the breath attack. Even when it did, the blast continued to diminish the moment it connected with Zhang Dong.

After the prolonged discharge, even Wang Long started getting tired as the energy source for the soul beast was directly him.

“What? Is that all?”

Soon Zhang Dong’s armored form was revealed to be there and without damage. His whole body was radiating newfound power as he managed to absorb all of the lightning energy that came his way into his lightning core.

“You probably didn’t go past the cultivation upgrading part that was provided by your system, did you?”

“Huh? What are you talking about, I picked the best cultivation upgrade that there is!”

Zhang Dong wanted to smile as he knew that he had gone in a different direction by focusing on his crafting abode upgrades. He had pushed his own cultivation past the initial upgrade offered by his system by grinding crafting upgrade points.

Wang Long on the other hand was content on just going with the highest upgrade available to him at the given point. Without anything to strive for he didn’t try to find any other ways to improve his cultivation past what the system was giving him.

Thus he was not able to fathom how Zhang Dong was just able to absorb all of the lightning energies into himself and take no damage.

“I must thank you, I wasn’t sure where I could get enough lightning energy to charge my lightning core.”

Zhang Dong had absorbed all of the spirit crystals, holy weapons, and items that he could get his hands on but there was a certain lack of electric energy to get. When he was a nascent soul master he mostly used natural storms as cultivation aid and didn’t stock up on anything like lightning crystals.

Thanks to this lightning-based attack though he was all filled up. The nascent soul that he absorbed previously covered his soul core and the spirit crystals and holy herbs that he managed to get, were enough to fill up his golden core. It was time to skip a realm and finally reach the great circle of core formation.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 381

Zhang Dong was floating up in the sky, a shroud of purple lightning energy was still swirling around him. This residual energy was getting quickly absorbed by him and to others, it looked as if a tiny circle inside of his chest was sucking it all in.

Wang Long with his soul beast in front was perplexed to see his enemy somehow using his own attack to power himself. This didn’t mean that he was in a state of panic, to him this only meant that there would be more points to be gained.

“So what if you bought a few good tricks? Don’t think that you are the only one with a system to back you up!”

He called out while slapping his spatial ring. When he did a burst of sword energies flew out along with hundreds of swords. These swords quickly shot in all directions and started to dance around. Their flight patterns painted the sky red and produced a phantom image of a red lotus.

The blades continued to fly at such a speed that the figure of the lotus remained intact and moved towards Zhang Dong’s location. Before he could react he found himself surrounded by thousands of sharp swords.

“I’ll shred you into minced meat!”

The swarm of sharp objects descended towards Zhang Dong before he could continue with his cultivation breakthrough. Even though he had absorbed enough energy to push him to the other level he would need some time to cultivate.

“Swords huh?”

Luckily for him, he was on his home territory, a place in which he created many treasures. Many of which were perfect for this occasion. With a loud clap, his aura spread through the entire Spirit Spring City and the Sect.

From his spatial ring, a massive swarm of various flying weapons escaped, and even more, appeared from the sides. The metallic objects all rose from the ground, from the destroyed buildings, and even from people that had already fallen in this battle of the sects.

“Did you know that when a master craftsman creates a weapon that a slither of their will remains in them? Even if the weapon chooses a master if the will is strong enough it will always listen to its creator instead.”

The flying sword formation that was about to devour him was soon intercepted by a torrent of metal. Zhang Dong’s counter formation was not only made from swords. If one looked closely they could see various other weapons like maces, axes, and polearms being absorbed into a grand flying weapon formation.

“Now give me a moment…”

While the two weapon formations were collying with each other, Zhang Dong used this as a chance to slip away. The torrent of energy and the loud sound of metal grinding against metal made spotting him quite difficult.

“Do you think you can hide from me?”

Wang Long had momentarily lost his opponent but he had ways of finding him. With the aid of his own system and the mapping function, he was quickly able to find Zhang Dong that had hidden himself away in some rubble.

“There you are!”

Wang Long moved his hands together and started to focus. A small ball of purple energy appeared in the middle that started to get progressively bigger. The energies that he was gathering quickly became chaotic and he raised them above his head.

“Take this.”

He shouted while lobbing the ball of energy towards the area that his system map was showing him. When the ball of spiritual energy collided with the ground a giant explosion was made.

The half-destroyed building where Zhang Dong was supposedly hiding in was incinerated. The explosion pushed debris in all directions while also melting anything that was directly in the spot that was hit.

“Hm?”

Wang Long was waiting with a sword in hand and had already his next attack ready but something was off. He expects Zhang Dong to dodge out of the way of that large attack and his aim was to then cut him. Instead, the whole explosion only caused more dust to be blown up which lowered the visibility even further.

“Did he get hit by that?”

“Hah, you must be joking. Do you really think that I’m not aware of the system’s mapping function?”

Zhang Dong’s voice echoed through the area. To Wang Long, it seemed as if he was somewhere close but also somewhere far away. When he looked at the map once more to lock onto Zhang Dong’s unique power signature he spotted a problem.

His system map that he had relied upon was showing him more than one location in which his opponent could be. It was as if he was fighting a small troop of Zhang Dong’s that were hiding from him.

“Maybe if you learned how to use your spiritual sense correctly you would be able to find me~”

“Screw you! I’ll just blow up everything!”

Wang Long’s expression became full of malice as he gathered even more energy. His soul beast roared out loudly and did the same. Soon both of them started blasting everything in the vicinity but mostly aimed at the locations on the map.

At this exact moment, Zhang Dong was actually quite far away. He used a hiding technique to slip away while also leaving some dummy spiritual ghosts behind. These spiritual avatars were created from a special technique he learned and could even fool the system’s mapping feature.

While taking his time to build up his sect Zhang Dong didn’t stop studying the techniques that he found in the secret ground. He focused a lot of his time on ones that would allow him to escape from stronger opponents or ones that were good for spying. Some of them when leveled up could even fool his system.

He put his hands together as if he was praying and a thin layer of energy surrounded his body. This was a sound canceling technique that would give him some time during his breakthrough.

While he set up many dummies of his aura signature around the area, this didn’t mean that his opponent would not be able to find him. Thus he started circulating his energies throughout his body and pushing his cores to their apex in an attempt to breakthrough.

The great circle realm was somewhat harder to transform into than the previous two realms. When he attempted it now he could feel similar pain to when he pushed through into the foundation establishment realm.

This step was a bit different as the great circle realm was more or less a transitional period between the smaller and higher realm. Regular core formation masters at the great circle could access some nascent soul only techniques like lesser flight that allowed them to float without a flying sword.

His great circle core formation realm was a lot different though as it would bring him closer to an enhanced version of the nascent soul realm. He was already able to fight masters at the middle stage, how strong would he actually be if he rose to that level of power?

“ARGHhhh…”

“Why is this so painful, it's as if my body is trying to reject this transformation…”

Zhang Dong felt like if he made a mistake he would explode right here. It was as if this world was rejecting him from achieving these breakthroughs. If this continued he feared that he would lose his mind when he actually attempted a breakthrough into the nascent soul level.

“There you are!”

Due to this painful transformation, he was soon discovered by Wang Long. The man might not have been the best fighter but Zhang Dong knew that he would not be able to take many hits. He was still in a somewhat pseudo nascent soul state and his opponent had bought superior skills through the system.

The only reason he was able to continue fighting was due to his battle experience. If the battle continued for too long, Wang Long could very well shorten that gap to land a critical blow.

‘Shit, he was a lot faster than I expected, did he use the system to find me?’

There was also the system. There was an unknown number of points that his opponent still had, he only used them to cancel out the barrier but how much he could do was unknown. Zhang Dong’s old system store allowed a person many functions that even he didn’t have time to discover during his travels.

Soon he found himself below a large ball of concentrated spiritual energy. This time around Wang Long had done some alterations as the spiritual energy was not aligned to any particular element like before.

“It’s time to die!”

He pointed with his fingers and a dark purple orb that was about ten meters in diameter descended. Zhang Dong was now left with the options of either remaining here and taking the hit or escaping.

Both choices would put him under a different amount of strain. One would cause him to suffer cultivation backlash as he was attempting a breakthrough while the other one would expose him to Wang Long’s energy attack.

“Oh no, you don’t!”

He heard a very familiar voice not far from where he was. This was followed by hurricane light winds and an emerald glow that collided with the purple energy balls. This collision of spiritual energies caused everything to rumble and also revealed the spot that he was hiding in.

“It’s you? Have you come to beg for mercy?”

Who appeared was a certain busty woman with caramel skin and light pink hair. It was Zhang Liena riding on her emerald soul beast that had managed to intercept the blast coming towards Zhang Dong’s location.

“Beg? It is you that is going to beg!”

“Hah, I like girls with some spice, I’ll be sure to give you a good time when we return.”

Wang Long licked his lips while laughing, even now he was convinced that he would be returning victorious. While he was fixated on a certain part of Liena Zhang Dong used this chance to converse with his wife.

‘What are you doing here, I told you to remain in the fortress. It can't function without a person piloting it!’

Zhang Dong was concerned that without the fortress that the sect would not be able to achieve victory. There were just too many nascent soul masters on the other side.

‘Fear not my husband, someone else is using that construct!’

‘Someone else?’

Zhang Dong peeked into the distance and could see the fortress continuing to fire. It was a bit slower than before but it was still operational. From it, he could also hear an older man’s voice that he also recalled.

“Do you think you can attack my grandson’s sect and live?”

“Gramps?”

Chapter 382

‘“How is gramps in the fortress?’

Zhang Dong was a bit confused as he had not had much time to explain how the large creation worked. The GUI that it had was quite easy to read through as he had made it to mirror game graphical interfaces that he remembered from the old days.

Liena quickly explained how she managed to call the old man over. When he approached the same spot that she did before an icon started glowing. She just needed to push it to let Zhang Jin drop into the pilot section.

It seemed that Liena had studied up on the creations that he had built. He made sure to make everything streamlined and easy to understand. This fortress was also running on an old operating system that was made to make things easy.

Thus it was plausible for his wife to figure out a way to get Zhang Jin inside. Though the fortress was acting a bit strange after the pilot switch. It was somewhat zig zagging all over the place as if the old man was hitting random prompts while in the pilot seat.

‘This isn’t the time for questions my husband, I will hold this good-for-nothing animal off!’

Zhang Liena took off in a burst of emerald energy. The feathers from her soul beast kicked up a storm and flew at the dark purple dragon as if they were homing missiles. While her cultivation wasn’t that high she had one more trump card left behind by her dear husband.

One of the rings on her finger started glowing and quickly encased her in pure green light. Wang Long was a bit surprised by the sudden counter attack so he decided to back off for a moment. His eyes were on his system as he tried to measure his new opponent's strength.

“Wait, isn’t that?”

Wang Long’s eyes went wide after the emerald light subsided. The woman was covered in a strange form-fitting armor. It looked as if it was made from some kind of green metal and had strange glowing runic patterns that were glowing.

The first thing he did was to look at the system indicator. His enemy didn’t seem to have gotten stronger as it still only showed her as an early realm nascent soul cultivator. But for some reason, he felt that her strength had increased.

Liena noticed that her opponent was a bit stunned by her armored appearance. This item that she was wearing was a high heaven grade item that Zhang Dong had managed to finish before his disappearance.

He called it ‘power armor’ and it was a fitting name as it did enhance her spiritual levels and strength levels. It was as if she was wearing something akin to a weapon that changed her body into something fearsome.

She didn’t skip a beat as she charged at Wang Long along with her soul beast. The two collided with each other and it turned into close-range combat. While her emerald phoenix was tussling with the dragon she was exchanging blows with the man that tried to capture her.

It was clear to her that he was not versed in combat tactics as his reaction time was somewhat sluggish. Even then, she couldn’t really do much damage as a strange force field continued to bounce off any deep hitting attacks that she produced.

If she landed ten good hits, he returned one that caused her to retreat. With time the armor that she was wearing started to receive some dents from the man’s kicks and punches and she was forced back without really causing much long lasting damage.

“Hah, you’re quite feisty, can’t wait to peel that thing off you, how about we make your whole sect watch as we have some fun?”

Liena scoffed at the man’s words. It was clear to her that this person had a screw loose. The things that he said were truly vile and despicable. She wanted nothing more than to rip the vile thing from between this man’s legs and beat him to death. But it seemed that she could only stall for time as this young master was not such a simple opponent.

Zhang Dong’s first reaction was to jump in to save his wife but he needed to use this time to cultivate. If he didn’t manage to break through soon, this whole battle could turn in their opponent's direction.

Above him, he could hear massive explosions. The ground he was sitting in was constantly shaking and blasts of condensed spiritual energy were constantly raining around the whole city. The elders from his sect were giving it their all but they were up against a large force from a mighty foe.

‘I must join them…let’s do this.’

He closed his eyes and concentrated on his three cores. They were all pulsating as if they would crack at any moment. This felt quite different from when he only had a singular core. That one had just gone through the motions as he cultivated and then was transformed into his nascent soul in a rather simple way.

Here on the other hand he was dealing with three separate cores. Was he supposed to fuse them into one large core or turn them into three nascent souls instead. When concentrating he noticed that the cores were moving away from each other while a strange power started to form in the middle.

‘What is this… could a nascent soul be forming… no this is something else…’

At first, he thought that perhaps a nascent soul was starting to form but he was mistaken. It felt different and grander. He could feel that the Dao’s that he had picked up throughout the years of his travels were being excluded from the three cores. They were all traveling into the center to form something, some kind of strange-looking seed.

He had to really concentrate to be able to feel it. The size of the core was far greater, it was as if he was comparing a moon to a tennis ball. But, the more he focused on this strange pure white seed, the more it continued to grow.

After it reached a certain size the growth was halted and he felt like his body was burning up. It was time, the great circle of this strange core formation was being reached.

“Got ya!”

Liena at this moment had been caught by some strange chains and was unable to move. Her emerald phoenix was being subdued by the purple lightning dragon that was strangely similar to her husband’s golden dragon. It looked like this was as far as she could go, even the armor treasure that she was wearing had been damaged enough to reveal her face.

“I still need to have my fun with you, You’ll look nice with a collar around your neck.”

Wang Long laughed while taking out a black slave collar from his spatial ring.

“Now hold still, I don’t want to cripple you before I had my fun, normal girls break so easily but on the other hand, you should be able to take it."

“I will never submit to someone like you!”

Zhang Liena screamed out while trying to use her spiritual energy to break free. Struggle she did but even then the slave collar continued to approach. Normally restraining collars like those would not work on nascent soul masters. But for some reason she felt her cultivation being suppressed, she could tell that if that thing went around her neck something disastrous would happen.

Before this could happen a strange aura appeared out of nowhere. Both Liena and Wang Long looked to this phenomenon as from it a bright pillar of light appeared that jabbed itself right into the clouds.

These two weren’t the only ones that felt this strange aura being spread throughout the whole battlefield. All of the lower and higher masters could feel something in their very being. No one knew what it was about but to the people from the Soaring Dragon Sect, it felt very ominous.

On the other hand, the cultivators from the United Element Sect felt something entirely different. It was a strange warm fuzzy feeling as if they had just drank some warm tea.

Before anyone could realize that it was Zhang Dong going through a realm change it was already too late. The pillar of light pierced through the massive protective barrier and caused the clouds to disappear and the sun to shine in.

The rays that illuminated the world started being absorbed into this pillar of light. Soon the entire area was bathed in a wondrous golden-white color. It could not be stopped and it could not be resisted as it passed through each and every one of the cultivators that were gathered here.

Just as soon as it appeared the light was gone. It was as if it was sucked into one certain point that was still radiating light while the rest of the area was shrouded in darkness.

Like moths drawn to the fire, everyone looked to this lit-up spot. There they discovered a certain white-haired Sect Leader. The light was coming from his dantian and for a moment some of the onlookers could see the light take the form of a bright white seed.

While everyone was staring, Zhang Dong found himself outside of his armor. It had shattered into many tiny pieces the moment he managed to breakthrough. This was quite surprising as it was supposed to be able to last through a regular late stage nascent soul master’s attacks without much of a dent.

He circulated his energies through his body to check if everything was in order. The three cores were still there but there was the addition of the tiny seed in the middle. He could feel that the energies from the cores were all flowing into this seed. Even if by a tiny fraction, it continued to grow, he felt that when it finally sprouted, something astonishing would happen.

……….

“Hmmm?”

A man opened their eyes while looking in a certain direction. He was sitting on a large golden throne that was adorned with various gems. His eyes were a dark sapphire blue and matched his long sky blue hair.

“My, Emperor. Is something wrong?”

The man turned his head to the womanly voice that called out to him. It was a beautiful woman that was sitting to his left on a slightly smaller throne that wasn’t as magnificent as his.

“Mmm… it must be my imagination.”

Soon he turned his face towards a hall filled with many other powerful cultivators and raised his hand.

“Let us get this over with.”

When he gave the signal the large door leading to this throne room was opened and soon a small group of cultivators emerged from it. At the helm were two old men dressed up in magnificent robes.

The man on the left was taller and his robe was mostly white. On the back, there was an elaborate crane embroiling. The man on the right on the other hand was a bit more imposing and a somewhat familiar-looking flying dragon adorned his robe...

Chapter 383

Name :

|

Zhang Dong

Affiliation :

|

Zhang Clan, United Element Sect

Cultivation Base Qi :

|

Ç̴̩̦̱̩̞̣͕͙̲̘͕̥͑̇̐̉͛̔o̶̼̖͇͈͚͈̠̼͈̠͔̽̎r̶͇̱̮͈̽̈́̃̿͑͗̚e̷̛̲͇͐́̈̎̿̇̇͊͑̌͝͠ ̵̗̣̹̻͐̽̌̌́̃̕F̷̛͍͕̼͜ơ̷͈̫̭̖͋̽̒̽̀̐̀̾̓̽ṙ̸̡̨̯̤͈̥̙̯̰̝̖͉̞̂̓̑̀̕͝m̷̧̮̳̙̗͉̳͕̭̱̫͈̩̋͂͋̋͐̈̇̈̌a̸̧̧̢̨̤̣̻̩̯͙̭̽̆͝ṭ̵͖͇̻͐̎̉̍̓̉̏̆͌͘į̶͙͙̝͓̫͎͕̥͓͎̹̅͛̔͒͘̕ó̴̡̤̘̭̩͖͚͚̟͚ņ̸̤̙̱̞͙̙̬̱͚̺̲̫̟̀̾̋̕͜ [ ?????????????] [ $@#%#@$^#$ S@#$FGD @#$Es ]

Cultivation Base Body :

|

Core Formation [ Great Circle 95 %] ( Ascended Golden Body )

Zhang Dong was hovering in the air, out of curiosity he glanced at his own status screen and discovered something strange. While most of it was fine, for the first time he saw some glitched text at the spot for his Qi cultivation.

He could somewhat make out that ‘Core Formation’ was written there but all of the other text was just a bunch of random symbols. It was as if this supposedly goldy system that had all the answers didn’t know what to make of his cultivation.

While looking at the tiny seed that was inside of him, he noticed that it was radiating quite a bit of energy. It was connected to all three cores, at first, he thought it was just sucking energy from them but he wasn’t quite right.

The energy flow existed both ways, while it was being energized by these three cores it continued to increase in size. Even a tiny increase in size was causing it to radiate more power, a power that he could utilize.

If it was a different time and place he would be sure to test his new cultivation realm out. Instead, he moved with haste by pushing his new spiritual energy into his body. While he was attempting to intercept Wang Long’s attempt on collaring his wife, the amount of energy that he had access to proved to exceed his expectations.

His intention was to either grab Wang Long’s hand that was holding the slave collar. Instead, he crashed into his opponent and tumbled with him to the side. Wang’s protective shield activated instantly as both of them were pushed in opposite directions.

While the shield was activated one of the rings on his fingers shattered into many tiny pieces. The young man was embedded into a rocky pillar that he had to use his Qi to get out of. He was clearly pissed as he had almost been able to place a collar on the woman he came here for.

“The hell?”

Wang Long called out as he was still surprised at how he was unable to react to this attack. He clearly saw Zhang Dong going through the change and he prepared for the counterattack but he couldn’t see it at all.

“Did that bastard ascend to another realm?”

He looked to his own system window and tried to answer this question for himself. While previously Zhang Dong had ‘Late Stage Core Formation’ written down in his stats, this time it was some glitched-out text.

While Wang Long was trying to figure out what the problem was and cursing up a storm, Zhang Dong removed himself from some rubble that he flew into. It appeared that the boost in power was far more dramatic than he had expected.

Before this fight started he put himself at around the middle stage of nascent soul at most. Even when he could tie with a nascent soul master he was missing a key part, a soul beast. Without it around he would need to be a lot stronger than his opponent to counter this disability.

Zhang Dong was hoping to tie Wang Long’s cultivation after ascending but he went much further. It was time to test his theory and if it was true, then this fight might be a lot easier than he realized.

“Liena, are you okay?”

He moved next to his wife who was breathing hard. Her soul beast was in a bad state as it was still being torn into by the dark purple dragon beast of Wang Long.

“I’m fine.”

She nodded but he could tell that she was tired.

“Leave him to me and go help the other elders instead.”

“But…”

“No buts, I’ll be fine.”

He smiled at her and then promptly vanished which took her by surprise. Liena then noticed a loud explosion in the distance and turned to it. There she saw the purple dragon being kicked away from her Emerald Phoenix. Her soul beast quickly retreated while she recovered some strength.

She could tell that Zhang Dong’s kick wasn’t that simple. The Qi that he had infused into it was somewhat different from the golden lightning one that he usually used. His form also looked different, instead of the usual golden hue, it was a faint white one. While it didn’t look as flashy, it somewhat felt a lot more imposing than before.

“Take care of yourself…”

Liena nodded and slowly removed herself from this fight. While she would still participate in protecting the sect she would be helping out against the other Soaring Dragon Sect elders instead.

“Where do you think you’re going, I didn’t give you the permission!”

Wang Long’s face contorted into a truly ugly expression. The woman he was after didn’t even pay attention to him and the look she gave her ‘husband’ was the thing that broke the camel’s back.

There were a few things that Wang Long could not deal with. One of them was couples that had a deeper connection than the surface ones that he aimed for. He could not stand people like that as he thought them to be massive hypocrites that were just acting out a fantasy.

Due to this there was nothing more that he liked more than to break those couples up. There were various ways that he approached these people. Sometimes he offered them money and power to see them break it off with their spouse. Other Times he threatened them with violence and laughed as he saw their relationship break into pieces.

“Oh, but I did.”

Before he could pounce on the fleeing woman he heard a voice next to him. When he turned his face towards it he saw a fist covered in some white aura shooting like a meteor towards his face. He was unable to raise his defenses but a thin shield still covered his body to take the hit.

“Useless, you will never defeat me!”

He screamed out in indignation after recovering from this blow that sent him to the ground.

“Is that so? I don’t think you have that many lives left though…”

Zhang Dong was there to meet his gaze. He pointed to his hand and when he did one of the rings that were there quickly burst.

“What? With just one hit? How is this possible?”

Zhang Dong had noticed that his hits weren’t really leaving an impact on Wang Long. Even though his opponent was losing, he had yet to take any proper damage. This was all due to the rings that covered his hands. They were clearly a sort of defensive treasure that was activated whenever its wearer was in trouble.

This was either a store-bought item, or something that he received from the Soaring Dragon Sect for protection. Since the battle started this was the third ring that had been destroyed. It also looked like Wang Long only had nine of those defensive rings on his fingers while the tenth was a regular spatial ring.

“Nine lives huh? Similar to a cat, but now you only have six…”

“Shut up, so what if you gained some power? Don’t think this is over!”

Wang Long gritted his teeth while also using the phantom chain attack that he previously used on Liena and Zhang Zhi. This time around, instead of his enemy being captured he saw something strange.

Zhang Dong opened his mouth and started breathing in. A massive suction force was created that caused the shackles to fly towards his mouth. The dark chains of ghostly energy were then promptly devoured by his soul core that was a perfect counter for this type of attack that actually went for a person’s astral form and not their physical form.

Without saying much Zhang Dong plunged himself into battle. It was quite one-sided as Wang Long found himself getting punched and kicked in all directions. His soul beast that attempted to shield its master was also quickly dispatched by a well-placed smack.

“Protect the young master!”

Wang Long wasn’t alone though, elder Tong’s voice boomed through the whole battlefield as the old master noticed his struggles. The elder was still facing off against Huo Qiang who looked quite injured.

Tong instantly tried forcing his way towards Wang Long but Zhang Liena with her soul beast stood in his way. This moment of emotion gave Huo Qiang enough time to attack and cause the old man to retreat. Unable to help the young master, it was up to the other elders to rise to the occasion.

Two of them quickly appeared from the side. Their robes were slightly damaged but the two were clearly still in good condition. Their opponent Zhang Dong was forced to momentarily halt his advance towards the young man as he evaded the spiritual attacks coming his way.

One man performed a devastating attack with their spear which produced a massive trench. The second one was using an Axe that cleaved in the other direction that caused the earth to be split in two.

Even then, the two late-stage nascent soul masters found themselves unable to contend with Zhang Dong’s speed. Both of them felt something connecting with their stomachs as they received a hard blow from the white-haired United Element Sect Patriarch.

“Useless old farts, what are you doing? Kill him!”

The enraged Wang Long dived into battle, while still having the protection of his ring treasures he didn’t feel any fear. A battle between four nascent soul masters ensued, while the three were busy trying to connect with their attacks on Zhang Dong the others weren’t doing so well.

With two nascent soul masters now missing, the flying cannon fortress had an easier time piercing through the defenses. Soon all of the flying ships from the Soaring Dragon Sect were up in flames. The explosions that the falling flying vessels produced river bedded through the lands and caused even more craters to appear on the surface.

The three versus one soon turned into a two against one and then back to a one on one as Zhang Dong was able to dispatch the nascent soul masters. His new cultivation was clearly giving him enough power to outpace experienced late stage cultivators without much problem.

Wang Long soon found himself suffering his first real blow as Zhang Dong’s fist connected with his nose and sent him flying into the distance. A fountain of blood followed soon after as the young master’s nose was shattered.

“Young master, I’m coming!”

Elder Tong finally managed to break himself free of his fight and was able to catch Wang Long that was smacked away by Zhang Dong’s fist.

“Surrender now!”

Zhang Dong shouted out while looking at Elder Tong. While killing them would be easy, having a political prisoner in the shape of Tong and Wang Long would be much better. It would give them some time to come up with a battle plan, otherwise, the Soaring Dragon Sect would just bare their fangs on them instantly.

“My face… the fucker broke my nose…”

Wang Long was visibly shaken up as he covered his bloodied nose with both his hands while muttering profanities.

“Surrender? You dare go against the Soaring Dragon Sect?”

Tong called out while also being enraged but after looking around he realized that they were losing. Some of their nascent soul elders had already suffered defeat and all of their flying ships were down on the ground and burning up.

“Young Master, think we will have to surrender, for now, they will not be brazen enough to hurt you, I’m sure the Patriarch will come to rescue us.”

Tong turned to Wang Long who was right next to him and placed his hand on the young man’s shoulder. Soon their eyes met and he could see the madness and rage in the young master’s eyes.

“Surrender?... I have a better idea…”

Before he could react he felt something sharp being pushed through his body. When looking down he could see Wang Long holding a dark dagger that was going right through his heart.

“Young m-master, w-why…”

Chapter 384

“Y-young master Wang… w-what are you doing?”

“I never liked you Tong, you were also a major cock-blocker…”

Zhang Dong and the others flinched the moment they saw the Soaring Dragon Sect’s young master plunge a demonic-looking dagger through his retainer’s chest. The old man had been tasked with the young man’s protection for quite some time, but he never thought that he would be capable of doing such a thing.

“What is that maniac doing, why would he attack one of his own?”

One of the elders from Zhang Dong’s side called out as they were all slowly edging the Soaring Dragon Sect members to the edge of the barrier through which they were unable to leave.

“Dang… he really only sees these people as spirit points.”

Zhang Dong quickly realized what was the purpose of Wang Long’s action. While normally it would be hard to instantly kill a nascent soul master, Elder Tong let his guard down and was focusing on the enemies in front of him. The dagger that Wang Long was using was also not a simple item as he could feel Tong’s nascent divinity fading quickly as he died.

“...Wang L-long… y-you…”

“Don’t think this is over you fucker, I’ll remember this!”

Wang Long pointed at Zhang Dong with the dagger while his figure started flickering. It was clear that he had killed the nascent soul master to get more points and activated a teleportation feature.

Zhang Dong’s own system had several teleportation options like these. All of them required points to be spent and probably the one Wang Long was using required far more than he had.

‘Bob, can you stop him from teleporting!’

‘Not enough spirit points to comply with the request.’

Was his AI’s reply as Wang Long vanished into the ether. The young master from the Soaring Dragon Sect was sure to flip the bird toward’s Zhang Dong who charged at him but was too slow.

He had managed to go through all those blasted wings but only landed one good hit. Wang Long’s nasty face remained embedded in his mind as he knew that he would be a troublesome foe.

With the system on his side, there was no way of knowing what he could do. The otherworldler was not against killing his own people for points and Zhang Dong feared what that crazy person would do now.

‘He must have teleported back to his own home point.'

Zhang Dong knew well how the people in this world operated but this Wang Long was a big mystery. There was no way of knowing how he would react, would they instantly bring over more people to attack their sect or would they be calmer?

Even though the Soaring Dragon Sect was a huge one, this didn’t mean that they had unlimited resources. The ten late stage nascent soul elders that were here would not be coming back, neither would be the strongest Elder Tong from them all.

This should be a big hit that they would not be able to bounce back that easily. If it was a normal encounter it was even possible for the Soaring Dragon Sect to not do anything out of fear of losing more resources.

It would be easy for their enemies to attack if they diverted their elders towards this sect. They would require more powerful elders of the late and great circle nascent soul level for the next attack as the United Element Sect had shown that they would not go down without a fight.

From his point of view, their enemies would probably petition the other middle sized sects for aid and go into a long-lasting battle while also watching. Their enemies on the other hand could very well contact Zhang Dong’s sect to aid and prolong the fights which would give them well-needed time to advance further.

While these thoughts went through his head he looked to the side. There he saw the remaining late stage nascent soul elders that witnessed their young master murdering their own. Zhang Dong knew that these old men and women here didn’t come here out of their own volition but they were also fine with murdering his whole sect.

“People of the Soaring Dragon Sect, surrender now and we will spare your lives.”

Even then, he felt like giving them an option was the right thing to do.

“Surrender to a lowly sect like you? Don’t listen to them my brothers and sisters, they are but a puny...Ugh…”

Before the old man with the long gray beard could continue he found someone's hand grasping his abdomen. This was Zhang Dong that in a fraction of a second traveled over to him and was now successfully sapping away all of his strength.

“I will not repeat myself, either you surrender or you all will die. You might think that you have a chance of victory but I assure you that you don’t!”

The old man started screaming while his vitality was sucked away. What Zhang Dong was doing might have seemed cruel but he had to show that he was being serious. Thus with the help of his soul core, he started absorbing the man’s nascent soul while the elder was still alive.

This caused the soul beast that belonged to this cultivator to just vanish into oblivion. The remaining group of nascent soul elders were quick to jump in to help their comrade and the battle continued.

He had hoped for a peaceful resolution but it was clear that these people would rather die than have their cultivation be removed. As someone that lived a large chunk of his life as a regular human, this was not something that he understood. There were many things like creating a family and living a fulfilling life that a person could strive for even without being a cultivator.

So the battle continued and with Zhang Dong’s increased strength it was soon over. With more time on his hands, he was able to come to terms with his new power. He was not sure how he would stack about the top experts on the continent but a regular great circle nascent soul master would not give him that much trouble.

With this in mind, he was expecting his next realm to be something entirely different than before. Whatever this small white seed was, it continued to grow and when it sprouted he might have access to something totally different than the nascent soul level.

Due to him visiting the other empire he knew that there were other ways of achieving similar power levels. There were many things that he didn’t know and his system was also unable to recognize where he was heading.

When all was said and done Zhang Dong was left floating up in the sky and looking down on the destroyed remains of Spirit Spring City. This was his home that he helped to create with his own two hands.

While he was saddened by this fact it was fine. What was important were the people that lived in the city. They had been previously evacuated and with some time even this city would be able to recover.

They were also left with a mostly intact defensive system that would allow them to fight back against more intruders. After everyone realized that their sect had managed to fight off ten late stage nascent soul monsters and one in the great circle, they would think twice about attacking.

“Hey, Dong’er… how do I get out of this thing?”

He snapped back to reality as he heard Zhang Jin’s voice calling out to him. The grandfather was still in the large fortress and even to this moment the cannon blasts were going off.

“I’ll be right back…”

“I’ll come with you then.”

Liena moved over next to him and the two flew over to the flying orb of cannons. For some reason, his wife had moved into shoulder-rubbing distance as the two continued with their flight.

“I’m not going to vanish…”

He realized what this was about almost instantly. It was not strange for her to be a bit more clingy, he was gone for five years and the woman was probably still digesting this fact.

“You don’t know that!”

She replied while grabbing part of his robe as if he was really going to disappear. Instead of backing away he just smiled and grasped his wife’s hand. The two then descended down to the entrance, there he used his spiritual energy to activate the mechanism that would eject Zhang Jin from the cockpit.

“Dong’er, it’s really you, I knew you were alive!”

The elevator came up with the old man, now that he was looking at him Zhang Dong noticed that the old man seemed somewhat smaller. It seemed that past these five years he had aged somewhat.

“Yes, it’s good to see you too, gramps.”

Both of them smiled at each other but soon the question came.

“But where were you all these years? We looked for you but could never find a clue, it was as if you vanished from this world.”

Both Liena and Jin looked at him for answers. Before he could reply though a third person appeared from the side and caused quite the rumble.

“Yes, you have a lot of explaining to do, where were you?”

It was Huo Qiang that was covered in the blood of his enemies. There were various wounds all over his body and face included but the large man didn’t seem to care at all.

“I guess I owe you all an explanation but I’m not sure that this is the best moment to do this…”

Zhang Dong looked around and could feel many eyes and ears upon him. While they were in one sect he could not really disclose his secrets easily. He had thought for a long time and finally decided to come clean about his true identity as a person from another world.

While he trusted Huo Qiang, Liena, and his grandfather he was not sure about the other elders from his sect. This was more of a family matter to him and he would like to also inform his disciples about this.

“I need to handle a couple of things first, gather the elders and we will discuss everything soon…”

“Wait… what could be more important than the sect?”

Before Zhang Dong could take Liena to take care of some family business he heard a voice calling out to him. It came from a burly-looking man that resembled his friend Qiang. Behind him were other various elders probably with many other questions on their minds.

“Are you really the Patriarch? We need to…”

This time around Zhang Dong was not really interested in the diplomatic resolution. He could tell that Qiang’s father was unconvinced of Zhang Dong’s disposition as he had been gone for five whole years. While he wasn’t here for that period of time, he was convinced that a power struggle between the sect members was taking place.

“What we need to do, I will decide, now gather up the elders and help the injured!”

Before anyone else could react they felt a massive oppressive aura wash over the whole area. All of them were forced down to their knees as they realized that this Patriarch was a lot more imposing than he was before.

“O-of course Patriarch, we will do as you command.”

With that being taken care of, Zhang Dong looked to Liena. Both of them nodded at each other as they descended from this flying fortress, their next destination being their children.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 385

“Big sister! You are alright, I thought you’d be taken away by that monster.”

Zhang Dong smiled a bit as he saw a smaller girl with pink hair pounce on his wife.

“Calm down Nuana, I’m fine.”

The two started hugging for a moment while the younger one cried. Luckily he managed to get here in time, if not both of them would have been on the flying ship along with that perverted Wang Long.

“Big brother, is that really you?”

Zhang Dong twitched a bit as he looked down at his ‘younger sister’. The girl was always a bit strange and clingy when he was involved. While he didn’t care that much, he did spoil her just so that she would leave him alone.

“Yes, it’s me, you… haven’t really grown much since I’ve last seen you, have you been eating right?”

He moved over to the two hugging girls. While a lot of time had passed the bodies of cultivators aged slowly. Nuana was just as short as she was before but perhaps her chest had gotten slightly bigger from the last time he saw it.

“Hey! That’s mean!.”

The young girl started pouting but only received a flick to the forehead from Zhang Dong as he came over. While this was a nice moment there were other people that he wanted to see.

“Next time, you should remain in the escape pod, you could have gotten yourself and others killed.”

Nuana flinched a bit as she saw Zhang Dong frowning. He still remembered how she knocked out Zhang Liu and rushed here to help her older sister Liena. If he didn’t come along her fate would have been sealed along with her sister’s.

“I’m sorry…”

She rubbed her forehead that was somewhat red, soon all three of them descended below what used to be his home. Directly below this spot was the entrance to the Patriarch’s escape tunnels. Through them, Zhang Xue, Liu, and Feng Nuana were supposed to escape.

Before going down Zhang Dong glanced at the entire sect ground. While almost all of the city was destroyed in the large-scale battle, more than half of the sect remained intact. Its most important part that was the hidden away secret ground had already been moved along with the junior sect members.

The pocket dimension that had increased in size was large enough to house all of the young men and women that were too weak to help. The people that stayed behind were mostly the core formation elders and veteran warriors that could man the various spirit canons.

In the battles that ensued, there were casualties. It was impossible to save everyone and they were already lucky to be alive. This was mostly thanks to Zhang Dong’s faction-building feature of the system that allowed him to build up strong defenses that even a large force could not take out.

Regretfully it would be hard to repeat this task again as most of the defensive cannons had been destroyed in the large-scale battle. The floating fortress that could somewhat match a nascent soul master at the great circle level proved pivotal in holding the ten late stage nascent soul cultivators back.

It didn’t come out unscathed and repairing it would prove difficult. Zhang Dong’s crafting abode had been reset while he was shot into another world which would only make things more difficult.

Previously he would be able to copy parts in it which would make things easy, now he would be forced to do it by hand while slowly leveling up the crafting abode’s old features.

Finally, they descended below into the tunnels. While Zhang Dong knew about these tunnels as he helped design them with his mapping function, this was the first time physically being here.

This whole area was built like a maze. There were many long corridors and dead ends that were in place to confuse any pursuers. The walls were reinforced with special materials which would even give the nascent soul master some trouble to get through.

Luckily this escape route was still intact and would not require any repairs. That is if Zhang Dong decided that it was a good idea to remain here. While walking through the corridors he began to think about the future.

There were mostly two options left for him. One would be to remain here, repair the sect, and bunker down. Due to them being able to take out ten nascent soul masters, they would be considered a serious threat.

Such a threat that the Soaring Dragon Sect would actually have to use a large chunk of their resources to have a realistic chance to go against them. Luckily for Zhang Dong, his enemies also had their own problems.

The first one was the Azure Emperor that was considered the strongest cultivator in this empire. He occupied the best cultivation spot that this land had to offer. His clan might not have been the largest but they went for quality over quantity and were a force to be reckoned with.

The second was the Heavenly Crane Pavillion. They were quite a power that mirrored the strength of the Soaring Dragon Sect. For decades these big three had remained in power while never really going all out against each other out of fear of getting eradicated.

If two of them would engage in combat, there was a realistic threat of the third party using this chance to take a crown for themselves. When two sides are fighting, the third always profits. It was an old proverb from his old world and this was very true in this situation.

‘The problem remains that idiot…’

He thought while increasing his pace. Wang Long was someone whose actions he could not predict. The cultivation nuts were easy to read as they always acted in the same way. This man on the other hand could even show up the next day with a similar sized force and not care if they would all die in the process.

Him just giving up after getting socked in the face and being humiliated made a peaceful resolution mostly impossible. Zhang Dong realized that Wang Long was too far gone, he was clearly not taking this world seriously.

While he was hard to read if he counted in this world's morals, he was somewhat predictable if he accounted for his emotional outbursts. He was still a person from another world but he acted similar to the other young masters from this world. If this was some side effect of the system or his original personality was not something he knew though.

“M-master is that you?”

While going through the tunnels that were made without any shortcuts in mind, they came upon a familiar face.

“Liu, it has been a while, you look well.”

Zhang Dong smiled while nodding his head at his disciple. The handsome youth didn’t age that much due to his high core formation cultivation realm but his eyes did look somewhat sharper.

“Master, it’s really you!”

“Who else could it be!”

The one to reply was Feng Nuana that popped out from behind Zhang Dong. She quickly shrunk back though as Liu gave her quite the death glare. This made Zhang Dong remember how she knocked his disciple out cold to go ‘save’ her older sister.

“What, are you mad? It all worked out well… help big brother, Zhang Liu is bullying me!”

Liu continued to glare at Nuana who quickly ducked behind Zhang Dong. Luckily for him, his wife was close and delivered a nice blow to her younger sister’s head.

“Stop that behavior!”

“Ow… why would you hit me, big sis?”

Zhang Liena moved between Nuana and Zhang Dong. At first, he thought she was just helping him out with the silly situation but then his wife started hugging his arm while yanking him to the side. It looked like she was mad about the way her younger sister was clinging to him while hiding from Zhang Liu.

While this would normally cause him to rub his eyebrows in indignation. This time around it caused him to laugh out loud. He placed his hand on Nuana’s head and ruffled up her hair, then he moved over to Liu to give him a firm smack on the shoulder.

“Hah, never change you two.”

The two looked at Zhang Dong with big eyes as he wasn’t acting too much as a Patriarch. While he had mellowed down when interacting with his wife he mostly kept his more laid-back character in the bedroom. When he interacted with the cultivators outside he still tried to act like a proper leader.

“Is Xue together with…”

He looked to Liu who moved himself a step behind Zhang Liena as they continued down the path. Xue, his other disciple, still remained with his children. The way these walls blocked spiritual energy was even making it hard for his enhanced senses but he could somewhat feel that his kids were near.

“Yes master, she is together with little Jun and little Xue.”

“Is that so…”

While he wanted to do nothing more than to see his kids, there was a certain something that was making him slow down his pace. It had been five years since they last saw him. For him, it was only about half a year which wasn’t all that much.

For his children, on the other hand, they have lived for more than they ever saw their father. Deep inside he was worried that they would not recognize him nor accept him as their father as he was gone out of their life for far too long.

The more that he walked the heavier his legs became. It was as if someone was placing shackles on his feet the closer he got to the escape pod in which his family members were waiting for him.

Then he finally saw it, the large door behind where his children would be. It was circular in shape and was really thick. Behind it was a large straight tunnel through which the people in the pod would be shot out.

While at first it might have looked like a simple high-speed escape tunnel, there was more to it. After it went through a certain range it would accelerate and then be teleported to another location which left a dummy pod behind. The idea was to make the enemies chase after this high-speed decoy while the actual pod was transported to another location entirely.

“It’s okay, I’m with you.”

Zhang Dong spaced out for a moment and it was noticed by his wife. Liena hugged him tightly while pulling him over towards the entrance. Without resisting he nodded at his wife, while he was concerned about how his children saw him, it was more important that they were safe.

He was still their father and he would always be that. Even if they didn’t accept him at first, that didn’t mean that he didn’t love them. His task was not to be their friend but to be their father and this was something that he intended to do.

Thus with a wave of his hand, the entrance was opened up and there he saw them. Two little munchkins hugging his second disciple...

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 386

There they were, Zhang Dong’s children. While he had been thrown into another world they had been a lot smaller. The older child, Zhang Xiu was about a year and a half when he left. She had grown quite a bit and he was having a hard time recognizing her.

Then there was Zhang Jun, the younger of the two. When Zhang Dong left to fight the monster the boy wasn’t even a month old, he was a newborn child. Now he was five years old and didn’t look any close to what he remembered. He was the first one to enter the escape pod area and Zhang Xue was ecstatic to greet him.

“Master, It’s really you, I knew that you would return to us!”

She was quick to move before him while leaving the two children behind. All things considered, they weren’t all that young anymore. In his world children at the age of his daughter were already going to first grade in some countries.

While normally he would have done nothing more than to catch up with his disciples, he was a bit preoccupied with his own problems. It felt like there was a giant chasm between him and his own children. He was not sure how he should greet them thus he just froze in place while staring at the two kids in the back.

As he was trying to speak up, Liena his wife moved forward. The moment the two kids saw her they instantly jumped up from their seats.

“Mother!”

Xiu shouted while bolting towards her mother. Liena at this moment was clinging to Zhang Dong’s arm so she had to accept the tackle to her legs.

“Mommy!”

Jun the younger called out while approaching at a more reserved pace. He looked a bit more scared as his eyes were focused on the man that his mother was clinging to. Zhang Dong noticed this and tried smiling at the child. This caused an adverse reaction as the young boy started backing away while hiding behind Xue.

“What are you doing Jun?”

While he was a bit shaken by the fact that his own son was afraid of him, he heard a cute voice call out. This was his cute daughter Xiu that was now looking at her brother while clinging to her mother’s hips.

“B-but... “

“Stop acting like a little brat, you’re supposed to be a man!”

Liena started giggling somewhat as the girl started shaking her fist at her younger brother. It seemed that the older sibling was the one in charge. Jun on the other hand cowered even more as he hid behind Xue that wasn’t sure what she should do.
“That’s enough Xiu.”

The fight between siblings was halted rather fast as both of them jumped up the moment Liena lowered her voice in a more commanding way.

“Liu, Xue I must thank you for keeping my children safe, I’m sure you have many questions you’d like to ask my husband but for now please give us some privacy.”

Liena turned to Xue while Liu remained outside the room with Nuana. Xue just nodded while looking at the boy behind her. She placed her hand on Jun’s head while giving him a smile.

“Aunty needs to go now but your mother is with you now, so you don’t need to be scared.”

“Mother… where is everyone going?”

Asked little Xiu while everyone left the escape pod. This was not the best place to have a family reunion but it was better than having everyone from the sect stare at them outside.

“Xue, Liu, please pay respect to your father.”

“Father?”

After they were alone Liena stepped away from Zhang Dong. She pointed to him with her palm while wanting to have her children greet him. He on the other hand was trying to keep a somewhat friendly face but this just caused him to have an awkward smile.

In this world, men were still considered the leaders of the household. His position was above the mothers and the kids would normally be ought to respect both their elders and their father. It would also fall to him to discipline the kids if they ever did something wrong.

This position fell to the other men in the family when the father was gone. In this particular situation, it would fall either to Zhang Jin or Zhang Liu that had a closer relationship with the Patriarch.

Zhang Xiu looked up to her with her big eyes that looked like bright emeralds. Her hair was quite long and her facial features were somewhat similar to Liena’s younger sister. The child continued to look at Zhang Dong’s face for a moment with a frown on her face.

“Daddy!”

As if she recalled something this frown turned into a bright smile and he received a tackle to his own thigh.

“Y-yes it’s me, your daddy!”

Zhang Dong stuttered a bit as he uttered the words. It seemed that his daughter still somewhat remembered his face.

“D-daddy! Where were you! Xue waited and waited but you never came back”

While she was hugging his leg she started to cry. The sounds of her sobbing could even be heard by the three people waiting outside.

“It’s okay daddy's here.”

Without much reservation, he leaned down and picked his daughter up, and started hugging her against his chest. He could still remember the days of his strolling around the sect with her perched on his shoulder.

This almost made him shed a tear at this very moment. His child was crying her little heart out while being in his arms. Liena started to tear up as well as she watched the whole scene with a smile on her face. But as the pillar of this family, he had to hold it in at least for now.

“Let me take a good look at you.”

To change the mood he decided to hoist up his daughter with both his hands into the air. He looked at her with a big grin on his face and started laughing.

“You’ve sure have gotten big but aren’t those cheeks a bit too plump?”

“Xue’s cheeks aren’t plump!”

“Yes, they are.”

With a little poke to one of those cheeks, he caused Xue to pout a little bit but soon she started laughing loudly when he started to tickle her. The father-daughter reunion was then interrupted by a somewhat painful pinch to his thigh from the side.

There he saw Liena looking at him with a forced smile on her face. Soon he realized what the problem was as he glanced down to where his son was standing.

“Jun, why don’t you greet your father together with your sister?”

Zhang Dong placed the laughing Xiu down on the ground but was instantly tackled once more. It seemed that his daughter was energetic as always, she had gotten even more energetic with age. On the other hand, his son seemed the exact opposite of his older sister.

“Zhang Jun greets father…”

The greeting lacked any sort of emotion behind it. It was as if he was greeting an elder from the sect rather than his own father. While Xiu had some old memories with her father, Jun was far too young to remember him in any good light.

What the child was left with were stories from his other parent and from the people around him. While he didn’t think that anyone from them would badmouth him, there could have been other people that might have.
There was no way of him knowing what Jun was thinking. He was already at an age where he could understand many things. His children were also somewhat special in the way as they both came from a nascent soul master.

They were naturally smarter than a regular child and developed sooner. This he noticed by the way this son acted as if he had practiced interacting with elders and knew proper decorum.

“You don’t need to be so stiff.”

While this wasn’t anything out of the ordinary around this world, he didn’t really want to bring up his kids in such a way. All the respect and fear of the elder generation that was beaten into each generation here was something that he never liked. At least with his own close family members, he would like to have a less strenuous relationship.

Thus he placed his hand on the boy’s head and gave him a good fatherly pat.

“You are my son, when we are alone you can act as you wish, being a bit spoiled is also allowed, just look at your big sister.”

Zhang Jun looked to Xiu, who was obviously wanting to be picked up. While he set her back down due to Liena giving him the starte, he was forced to pick her back up as the child didn’t relent. He held her with one hand as she was still rather small, the moment Xiu's face brightened up but it also caused Liena to sigh out.

“You’re spoiling her too much….”

“It’s fine, it’s a father’s obligation to spoil their daughters!”

Liena frowned a bit but she didn’t reply to the answer. Xiu on the other hand realized with this little exchange that there was someone above her mother in the family hierarchy now. This realization would cause some friction between the mother and daughter combo but that was a story for another time.

“I… I’ll try father.”

Jun on the other hand was still somewhat reserved. This was fine as Zhang Dong knew that a relationship like this needed some time. This was something that the two could work on after they were safe. For now, Liena took Jun’s hand and the four walked out from the escape pod to meet up with the people outside.

“Master.”

“Master.”

“Big Brother!”

He was greeted by his disciples again, Nuana was also there and she gave him a big bright smile. It seemed as if she wanted something from him and that was probably related to the way Zhang Liu was glaring at her. She had knocked him out to get outside but that was not something that he wanted to get involved in.

“We will return to the sect, I’ll have to ask you to take care of the children for now.”

“No, daddy, stay!”

While he was talking, Xiu instantly cut him off and started crying.

“Uh… no, daddy just has to go talk to the elders, It won’t even take that long…”

“No, don’t leave Xiu, you can’t!”

While Jun didn’t seem affected by his father leaving, his older sister continued to cry. It was clear to him that the child was afraid that her father would disappear as he did before. Problematic as it was, he could not take the small child to the meeting with the elders. They would be discussing the future of the sect, not something fit for her ears.

‘This might be a problem…’

He turned to Liena for help but his wife instead of helping him out started to sob as well.

“Wait, not you too…”

“I’m sorry but It’s just been so long…”

It seemed that his wife had also not gotten over the fact that he had returned. Soon all three members of his family started to cry, Jun included.

‘Oh, jeez…’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 387

“How much of the sect has been affected?”

“Not that much Patriarch, most of the destruction was spread through the city but the sect buildings have remained mostly intact.”

“Good.”

Zhang Dong nodded while walking together with a man that he hadn’t seen in a while. It was Zhang Kuo that was one of his trusted retainers. His cultivation had advanced into the middle core formation stage and his face didn’t change much even though he had aged by a whole five years.

At this moment in time, he was walking through the large halls of his own sect. While normally there would be many disciples running around, the halls remained mostly empty.

“So, all of the disciples have been evacuated to the dimensional regalia?”

“Yes Patriarch, Zhang Ya is with them along with a core group of elders.”

Thanks to the treasure that he had discovered on his travels the sect was able to evacuate all of their disciples. There was enough space in that pocket dimension to house everyone. The treasure took the form of a medallion so transporting it was rather rudimentary.

The person holding this treasure was inside a similar escape pod-like his children were. Just as they, the person holding the medallion had not yet left and been on standby. During the meeting of the elders, he would need to decide if they would be remaining here or if they would be moving towards a different destination.

“Well done.”

He nodded and was glad that the escape pods were still unused. When activated the tunnels would explode later on and the whole construction would have been unusable. All in all, they didn’t suffer that many casualties and were rewarded with the treasures in the spatial rings of the eleven nascent soul masters.

“Thank you, Patriarch!”

Kuo replied with vigor which took him by surprise. This man was usually the more cold and calculating type but after a while, he had also become a father which might have altered his way of thinking.

His own daughter was hard to peel off after he informed her about the elder meeting. For the time being, they were with their mother but he was to return to them as soon as possible. While little Xiu had opened up fully back to him, this wasn’t the same for his youngest Jun. It would probably take some time for the boy to open up to him but for now, it was fine for him to be healthy.

“Zhang Zhi, greets Patriarch.”

Before the large meeting hall stood Zhang Zhi with a large samurai sword strapped to his hip. Next to him was a somewhat large woman that looked like a battle-hardened amazon. This was the man’s wife who was also part of the old Feng Clan.

“Glad to see you, I have to thank you for taking care of the sect while I was away.”

“I am but a humble servant my lord, I did it all for the sect!”

It didn’t look that this man had gotten over Zhang Dong quite yet. Even now he could see that samurai lookalike’s eyes sparkling during their conversation. Normally Zhang Dong would only cringe at these sparkly eyes and try to hide but now after not sleeping his number one fan for so long, he didn’t mind.

“Keep up the good work then, maybe if we have some time I could impart a new technique to you.”

“I am unworthy of such praise!”

Zhang Zhi just lowered his head but Zhang Dong could tell that when he mentioned the improved technique the man became a bit giddy. Soon all four of them entered through the door and were greeted by a room filled with many sect elders. Everyone was already waiting for him and some of them had less than stellar looks on their faces.

“We greet the Patriarch.”

Huo Qiao called out from the side which made everyone bow their heads to Zhang Dong. This was someone that he hadn’t interacted much since the old days but it seemed that the old elder was still friendly with his friend Huo Qiang.

Both of them were sitting quite closely while Qiang’s father still looked rather uncomfortable. Even though he didn’t look like he approved, he did bow his head. Zhang Dong’s performance and boost in power spoke volumes and he could not be denied.

“I’m sure you’d like to know where I’ve been for all of those years but that will have to wait, we must decide on our next move.”

Everyone nodded as they knew that if they came to the wrong decision they would be eradicated.

“Hah, the moment senior brother returns all hell breaks loose, there is never a boring moment if you are there, I’m glad that you are back!”

Huo Qiang called out while laughing, it seemed that he wasn’t taking this that seriously. Even now he was not at full health after facing Elder Tong but this only made him itch for the next challenge.

“I’m glad to be back, I must thank you all for taking good care of the sect while I was away. Now let us discuss the matter at hand, does anyone want to make a proposition about our next step?”

While he was still the Patriarch and the decision-making was up to him, he always liked to hear out the people from his own sect. Their lives were at stake as well, even more than his as he had ways of hiding himself along with his family if he ever needed to.

“What can we do? We offended the Soaring Dragon Sect!”

One of the elders called out while the others nodded their heads.

“This is similar to the time when we offended the Dark Palm Sect!”

Zhang Zhi was the one that commented that from his point of view this was not the first time that they were against less than favorable odds.

“You want to compare the Dark Palm Sect to the Soaring Dragon Sect? It’s like comparing a toad to a phoenix!”

Soon the elders started to shout at each other as the opinions were somewhat split. While some still believed that there was hope to get out of this alive others wanted to flee. Zhang Dong remained silent for the time being as it had been a while since he had seen the elders be so rowdy.

“That’s enough.”

While normally he enjoyed when the oldies were at each other's throats this didn’t get them anywhere. They needed to make a decision and they needed to do it fast.

“I can see that at least you all agree on one issue, there is no peaceful resolution to this problem we face.”

Zhang Dong said as he noticed that no elder in the room made a proposition of bribing the Soaring Dragon Sect to appease their anger. Everyone here seemed to be in agreement that it would be strange if that sect just let things be after they killed so many prominent elders from their side.

“If I may speak, Patriarch?”

Huo Qiao spoke out and Zhang Dong just nodded with his head.

“Brothers and sisters, it might look dire but there is still hope. We have managed to push their assault, this was not a small force that the Soaring Dragon Sect had amassed, it is not something they can just ignore, they can not ignore our potential might!”

“Are you implying that the Soaring Dragon Sect will be fearful of us and not go through with an immediate attack?”

Zhang Dong asked as he was not sure what their enemies would try to do. Normally a huge force like that would not take something like this lying down. They killed ten of their late stage nascent soul masters and most of them fell to his blade.

On the other hand, they did manage to slay these ten monsters that each could be the Patriarch of their own middle sized sect. This showed people that the United Element Sect was to be feared.

Those middle sized sects in the region would probably not want to have anything to do with this conflict. They might even choose to flee instead of answering the call to arms that the Soaring Dragon Sect would normally send them.

“Not afraid but unable to.”

Huo Qiao continued with his train of thought.

“The Soaring Dragon Sect is but one of the powers that rule this empire, they still have to answer to both the Azure Emperor and The Heavenly Crane Sect.”

The Heavenly Crane Sect in particular could see this as a chance to strike. Ten late stage nascent soul masters didn’t just pop out of nowhere. It was clear that Wang Long miscalculated by bringing over such a big force.

It was clear that there were so many of them for the intimidation factor and they weren’t really planning on fighting. Even then those cultivators didn’t expect the amount of resistance that the United Element Sect offered.

“That is a possibility, the tunnels and facilities for the sect's evacuation are still undamaged.”

More people started talking, it seemed that even if they remained, all of the teleportation formations and intricate mechanisms for their escape were still in place. The defensive formation was still there and with Zhang Dong here now it could be fully utilized.

“We have two options, either we stay here or abandon the sect to a life of constant flight.”

Zhang Dong gave his opinion as well. While it wouldn’t be that hard to flee, that would be for the sect. It would be impossible to keep as one tight-knit group. They would probably split into two sides, one going with the Huo Clan while the other going with his side. Some might even try to establish their own small clans in the other sect territories.

By not staying together they would have no chance of ever fighting back if the Soaring Dragon Sect decided to search for them. On the other hand, it would be a lot easier to hide in smaller groups and they could infiltrate other cities and lay low.

While survival was more probable with the second option, they would never recover their old prestige nor would they be able to progress as cultivators as they did.

“Patriarch, do you believe that we have a fighting chance?”

Everyone looked to Zhang Dong, it was all up to him to decide. While the old him would have probably chosen flight, the man that he now was different.

“Yes, I do believe that we have a fighting chance… tell me, how many masters at the great circle of core formation do we have to spare?”

“Patriarch, do you mean?”

Zhang Dong nodded with a little grin on his face. While his system was not fully in working order with his new realm that was more powerful than the old one it gave him his old method of raising his people up. It had been five years since he was here, in that time his people had to have made some progress.

“Yes, the more the better, we will put the resources that were left to good use!”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 388

“What do you think is happening outside?”

“According to the evacuation order, we should arrive at a safe location in a few days, then the elders will notify us if we are free to leave…”

“Cheng Yun… do you think that the sect is really done for?”

“I don’t know Yang Rong but it didn’t look good, I could see the confusion and fear in the senior’s eyes… it's never good when the Soaring Dragon Sect is involved…”

Two youths were sitting together by the window of their dorm room. Their names were Yang Rong and Cheng Yun and they were both outer sect disciples from the United Element sect.

They had been at the sect for many years and both had managed to pass the foundation establishment threshold after long days of trial and training. They were soon expected to be promoted to inner sect disciples as their cultivation was progressing smoothly but now that dream might be at an end.

“This is bullcrap! This great Yang Rong was supposed to be a core elder and marry at least ten sect sisters!”

Yang Rong started shouting in indignation through the opened window while looking into the vast expanse of this pocket dimension. Both of them were inside the dimensional regalia treasure that was able to house all of the disciples for the evacuation.

“Be quiet you idiot, I’m trying to sleep!”

“Who was that? Who dares call this Yang Rong an idiot! Come out so I can shove my fist in your face!”

Cheng Yun gave out a sigh as he heard his friend arguing with some other disciples that were stuck in this pocket dimension. It hasn’t been that long but it was long enough to make them worry,

While the news of the approaching Soaring Dragon Sect was still fresh and they haven’t been here for long. Cheng Yun was still worried as if everything went well outside they would have been allowed to go back to the sect. It had already been a full day which could mean that the person with the regalia was actually heading towards the secret hideout.

“Yang Rong, is it you again? Stop causing troubles for your seniors, go to sleep or meditate!”

“Elder Fei! It’s an honor that you have graced these eyes of mine with your beautiful form!”

Yun peeked out from the window and could see a rather beautiful woman down on the ground. She was holding a whip which was promptly used to deliver a strike to Yang Rong’s forehead.

“ACK!”

“Be quiet you stinky junior, now stop causing trouble for everyone here!”

“I’m sorry elder Fei, he just needs some sleep!”

Cheng Yun quickly closed the window while bowing his head at the woman. While she was one of the prominent beauties around the whole sect, everyone feared that whip. There were certain rumors that many disciples and elders alike fell to it when trying to court the busty beauty.

While she was shapely and beautiful, she was also very strong. There weren’t many people that could keep up with her which meant that it was hard to make her settle down. She had already progressed past the foundation establishment realm and was one of the inner sect elders at quite the young age.

“Rong, you should stop that… you’re going to die one day…”

“Hah, this is but a scratch, it's nothing in the pursuit of love! Did you see how she didn’t even pull any punches, look at how my forehead bleeds, it is truly a mark of our love!”

Cheng Yun squinted with his eyes, he was not sure what was wrong with this sect brother of his. If he didn’t know that he was actually a good person that would put his life on the line for his sect sisters and brothers, he would probably evade him like the plague.

‘What’s wrong with these people…’

Lan Fei gave out a sigh while walking away from the large building that housed hundreds of people in it. This was but one of the structures that had been created in this pocket dimension and there were many more spread around it. This one in particular was given to her to watch over as she had been promoted to an inner sect elder not so long ago.

‘That old crow isn’t telling the whole truth… I know she knows something…’

Lan Fei walked away from the dorm after it had quieted down. She entered a separate building where some other elders gathered along with the one in charge, an old granny that looked like a potato that had been out in the sun for too long.

“Little Fei? I hope that the children aren’t causing too much trouble for you.”

“Junior greets elder.”

Her name was Feng Maling and she was the grandmother of the current matriarch. While her cultivation level wasn’t all that high compared to the other elders, she still had a lot of backing. Even elders at the nascent soul level feared offending her in any way.

“It’s just one trouble maker, nothing the senior should worry about.”

The building they were in was in the middle while the dorms spread out like flower petals in all directions. The one she was responsible for was the closest one so she spent most of her time here.

Feng Maling was the person with the right to opening this pocket dimension. Without her approval, nothing could get in or get out. Lan Fei along with the other elders didn’t really know what was happening outside as everything went through this old lady.

‘She has to know something…’

Even when the information didn’t go through she did spot the old elder talking with someone through a communication jade recently. No information did get through so the state that the sect was in was a mystery.

‘Is the sect really done for? They would have let us out by now if everything was fine, I don’t like this…’

Lan Fei had been living in this sect for many years now. At first, she wasn’t sure if she made the right decision of coming here as she did have a history with its Patriarch. In the beginning, she thought that it would be a boon but then she realized that the man she was chasing was already married.

With nothing else to do she remained and quickly found out that this sect had quite the prestigious disciple program. With the merit-based system and her already high cultivation, she managed to progress through the ranks quite fast. From an outer sect elder all the way up to the inner sect elder.

With some more work, she was even hoping to get into the core elder position and attain the nascent soul prestige. But when she was so close to her goal, this strange event with the Soaring Dragon Sect transpired and she was now stuck babysitting kids.

‘Should I just make a run for it when we reach the sanctuary?’

She looked at the old lady that was smiling and drinking some green tea. She knew the evacuation procedures that they were going through. The elder with the medallion would reach a certain spot and place the medallion there. Only then they would be allowed to leave this place.

While leaving was limited to the elder generation she with her current status would be allowed to leave. Then she could decide if it was smart to remain in this sect or if they had offended the Soaring Dragon Sect to the point of no return.

Even though that was the best way to survive she somewhat felt that it would not be the correct choice. She owed the sect quite a bit, all of her current strength was all thanks to them and their Patriarch.

The same man that she had a fling with. During the years in the sect she could see him from a distance performing some speeches but the two never really interacted with each other again. The biggest problem was Feng Liena, his wife that she was afraid of.

She feared that if that woman ever found out about her husband's encounter with her she would be done for. Even though this was something that happened before the two met, she wasn’t so sure if Liena would care much for it.

‘Did he really perish? If he is really dead then there might be no future left for this sect.’

While she liked her current position she didn’t like it more than her life. Without Zhang Dong being in the lead she feared that it would go down in the wrong direction. The debacle with the Soaring Dragon Sect might just be the straw that broke the camel's back.

If she could go back in time she wished that she could grab the man called Zhang Dong for herself. To this day she regretted that she let someone like that slip through her fingers.

“Huh? Right now?”

Fei was about to go do another round around the dorm to check if the troublemakers were still at it. Before she could stand up though, the old grandma spit out her tea.

“Elder? Is everything alright?”

She asked while Feng Maling fumbled around with her communication jade, it seemed that something had happened outside and it didn’t look like anything good.

‘Could have we really angered the Soaring Dragon Sect?’

She asked herself while her legs quaked slightly. Even though she was thinking about leaving when the coast was clear she was still responsible enough to help the juniors first. If it was really required she would do her duty to protect them.

“Alright? Well…”

The old lady stood up from her seat and started to slowly walk outside. Lan Fei along with some other elders that were here remained half a step behind the old lady while being curious of what this was about.

‘That is…’

They ended up before the teleportation area through which people that were given access to the regalia could come in. The old lady just smiled while waiting here and soon someone started to appear before her.

“Why does it always take a crisis for you to show up?”

The old lady asked as a certain white-haired Patriarch appeared before everyone. His looks were known by everyone here as it was hard not to notice all of the statues in the sect.

“Hey granny, I hope that you have been well, I need to borrow this place for a while…”

As soon as he spoke more and more people started appearing behind him. All of them were of various ages but they had one thing in common, they were all at the great circle of core formation.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord

Chapter 389

‘This place did get larger, glad that they continued to feed it more energy.’

Zhang Dong looked into the wide expanse that was the pocket dimension of the dimensional regalia. This place actually had a nice cool breeze running through it after they went through applying some elemental treasures.

This allowed them to fashion several biomes with different temperatures which helped certain herbs to grow. With the help of this dimension, they were able to grow rare herbs without the knowledge of other sects and the Soaring Dragon Sect overlords.

‘It seems that even without me around they were prospering…’

He had left behind quite the treasure trove which would allow his people to progress even without him. After these five years of absence, there was no one that had step foot into the nascent soul stage but Huo Qiang had managed to reach the middle stage. If he had stayed then perhaps his wife would have been able to advance as well.

The first person he noticed was his grandmother, Feng Maling. She still looked like a baked potato. It seemed that she wasn’t aging so well either.

“I didn’t want to believe it, but it is truly you.”

“Good to see you too, granny, you seem to be doing fine.”

“Hah, that old bat is too stubborn to die, she also got the easy mission of protecting the kids.”

“I’ll never die before an old fart like you Zhang Jin.”

Zhang Dong came along with a group of great circle cultivators and his grandfather. The moment they arrived the once old couple were at their throats yet again. While he found the two grandparents bickering with each other there was no time to lose. The sect's existence was at stake, with every minute spent bickering they were at risk of being eradicated.

“Enough, both of you. We don’t have time for your lovers' squabbles we need to prepare the elders for their advancement and you two are going to be the first to go through the change.”

Feng Maling and Zhang Jin almost fell over after he mentioned that they were bickering like an old married couple. While Zhang Jin’s old cultivation had been quite messy, it had been revitalized by the new teachings and better cultivation methods. Now even this old man that was a great circle master could have his body cleansed from all impurities before progressing into the nascent soul level.

“My boy, this old lady is far too old, I’m not sure my body will be able to go through a change like this… but if the sect and the young ones can be saved, I am willing to try.”

From the perspective of these old cultivators like Feng Maling, there was a very slim chance of surviving the transformation into the higher realm. The nascent soul stage was quite dangerous to attempt and it had claimed the most lives from any realm progressions.
Lucky for everyone here, they had Zhang Dong with them. With his extensive knowledge and his system, he would be able to choose the right cultivation method for everyone.

A large portion of the lives that this transformation claimed was due to the incorrect usage of the cultivator’s talents. It was similar to Zhang Zhi’s situation when he had chosen the wrong weapon to focus his talents on. Without Zhang Dong’s involvement, the man would probably never have reached his true potential.

“Don’t worry granny, you’ll live, gramps will be fine too.”

Soon more people started to appear, it was hard to count but almost fifty great circle core formation experts were now here. With the help of the improved cultivation methods and the right resources, the people from this sect could go through the realms at an astonishing speed.

Even without his help, it would be possible for all of the younger cultivators at this level to probably ascend into the nascent soul level before they reached the age of a hundred. This would cause quite the uproar through the empire though as even the giant sects like the Soaring Dragon Sect could not progress this fast while being at an area with the highest spirit energy density.

“I haven’t been here in a while, can someone lead us to a secluded spot that is far away from the disciples.”

Zhang Dong looked out into the distance and could feel many eyes on him. It was clear to him that he had been spotted by the young ones. He did not really hide himself from then and his aura was even more powerful than it was before. His intent was to give everyone a morale boost, with their beloved Patriarch back at the sect, they would be fearless.

“Ah yes, little Fei come over here.”

Zhang Dong looked to the side of where this little Fei was supposed to be. There he saw someone peeking out from behind the corner while somewhat hiding themselves.

“Fei? What has gotten into you, pay respect to the Patriarch!”

Granny Maling lowered her voice which caused the person that was hiding to emerge. The moment he saw the woman he realized the reason why she was hiding. While the hair was a bit different he would not forget the set of assets that were jiggling with every move that this woman took.

“...Lan Fei greets the Patriarch, forgive me, I’ll be your guide.”

It was Lan Fei, the woman that had popped his cherry. He knew that she had come to his sect but after a few months he stopped paying attention to her as he focused on his wife and then the first child. It was still hard for a man to fully forget their first time.

While any feelings for the woman had evaporated a long time ago, he still felt somewhat strange while talking to her. With a little glance, he examined her deposition, which put her on the level of a recent middle stage core formation expert. This was quite the achievement but it would not be enough for her to progress towards the nascent soul stage.

“Let us depart now, time is of the essence and there are many brothers and sisters that require my help.”

The disciple's Cheng Yun and Yang Rong included were greeted by a large group of flying elders. The whole sect dorm became loud as everyone noticed the peculiar white-haired Patriarch at the helm of their formation.

“W-was that the Patriarch?”

“It was, he looks the same as he did, I remember him from the entrance speech!”

“What is happening outside? What of the Soaring Dragon Sect?”

The disciples here had even more questions now. What had happened to the evacuation attempt, why was their dead Patriarch here and why were all of those prominent elders here with him.

While everyone had question marks above their heads Zhang Dong was flying towards a distant destination. Lan Fei brought them to a secluded mountain range that was built for combat training in mind. The disciples were many kilometers away from this destination and would not get in the way of the training.

“Good, please keep the disciples away from this area, for now, they will remain here.”

While the sect was mostly intact the protective formation needed some work. The whole city was destroyed and some of the formation lines had to be redone. Before everything was fully fixed he didn’t feel like putting disciples that were weak out there.

The enemies could arrive at any moment so the dimensional regalia needed to be ready for shipping at any time. It was still an immortal grade treasure that could not be damaged by anyone, even masters at the nascent soul level.

The only way to enter this pocket dimension was to either kill the current owner or somehow breach through the treasures defenses. He didn’t really think that there was any craftsman that would be able to do that and killing him would also not be that easy. Thus the disciples were safer here than outside.

“Little Fei, forward the Patriarch’s orders to the others, be sure that we don’t get bothered by those rascals!”

There were a few disciples that would probably attempt to get to the bottom of what was happening. It was dangerous to interrupt people that were trying to pass into the nascent soul level as they could fail. It was also dangerous for a weak cultivator to be around someone that was a nascent soul master. They would release a devastating amount of Qi which could cause death to anyone below a certain level of power.

Zhang Dong looked at Lan Fei and bowed her head while also somewhat evading his gaze. It was clear to him that she was feeling awkward about this whole thing as well.

“Hm… Dong’er… you and that girly… you sly fox!”

His gaze trailed a little bit too long on the busty woman and he was noticed by his grandfather. Zhang Jin was a known womanizer so he had a keen eye for such things, he could instantly see that there was something going on.

“What are you talking about gramps?”

He got elbowed to the side by the old man who had a strange silly look on his face. Zhang Dong to this day didn’t know how a person like this could score so many women. Even after hundreds of years, he could not keep his lower brain in check and his family number constantly grew each year but at least one.

“Don’t worry, I won’t tell your wife, grandpa understands, I knew you had it in you! You’re just like your grandfather.”

“I’m not anything like you, you old fart!”

Before Zhang Jin could continue he received a smack to the back of his head. If there weren’t so many people here Zhang Dong could see himself choking his grandfather out at this very moment. Alas, he needed to remain cool and collected.

“Patriarch?”

Feng Maling turned to the unfolding scene along with the other core formation experts that were here. Everyone was a bit perplexed about the reason of the Patriarch hitting his own grandfather out of the blue.

“Hey, why did you smack me? Grandpa is going to be sad when his favorite grandchild acts like this!”

Zhang Jin started rubbing his face while trying to act cute. Though he was someone that was far above the age of a hundred, so even when he tried the puppy dog eyes, Zhang Dong could only cringe.

“Excuse me…”

Zhang Dong turned around while coughing into his fist. It was time to get these elders up a notch. He wasn’t sure if all of them could make the jump to the next level but the more he got up there the better their chances at survival were.

“Well then, I think you know how it goes gramps, you’ve gone through the process before…”

“Uh… Dong’er… please be gentle with this old man…”

“Don’t worry, I’m always gentle.”

Zhang Dong cracked his knuckles while bringing up his sect’s window. It was time to cleanse everyone’s body from impurities and then use some of those spirit stones they got from their attackers to push their power levels towards a new level.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 390

“Fucking shit, If that shithead cares about those bots so much I’m going to tear them limb from limb while he watches!”

A certain young master’s shouts filled one of the peaks at the Soaring Dragon Sect. All of the women that attended to his needs had fled outside while he was demolishing his own living quarters. It was so bad that other sect elders had to get involved, only ones at the level of elder Tong dared to approach.

While the scared beauties waited outside Wang Long looked at his system window. He continued to examine it as he could tell that something was wrong. The person called Zhang Dong was clearly only a core formation expert, he saw it on his system screen.

“How did he do it? Did he find some kind of exploit? Is there some kind of bug? His info got jumbled up after that change…”

Wang Long was still a gamer, thus he tried applying gamer logic to what transpired at the battle. From his perspective, the man he fought was somehow abusing the system that they were given.

“Did he buy something to fake his status screen? Maybe he was already above my realm when we started?”

Wang Long started to calm down while also looking around. The room he was in had previously been a huge chamber with many lovely ladies. He had grown bored of this world after going through all the other young masters that the sect had to offer.

Without any internet or television, there was nothing else for him to do here. He never really aspired to be the leader of this sect. It was even quite the bothersome occasion that would require him to attend long boring meetings. He would rather leave that task up to the old man that was supposedly his grandfather.

He was slowly starting to grow bored of this world. There was nothing more for him to achieve as he was already in the most prominent sect. The only two factions that they were up against would not interfere with them either.

He felt that in time he would be able to take over as the new Azure Emperor if he just continued to level. But after achieving the nascent soul level it had become quite the grind. There weren’t that many nascent soul bearings that he could kill and he got almost no spirit points for things below it.

With longevity being on his side he didn’t really see any reason to try so hard anymore. He would at least live a thousand years but his body was that of a twenty-year-old. Signs of him aging wouldn’t even be visible before he reached the age of a hundred.

‘I need something to drink.’

“Hey, where is everyone? One of you better brings over some wine!”

Wang Long shouted out loudly, his voice echoed through the whole peak that he was the master of. In a matter of seconds, three girls appeared with various items in their hands.

“There you are, took you long enough.”

They were momentarily stunned by the way that this place looked. Fist marks and small craters riddled this previously gorgeous room. The fountain that once gave out a radiant glow of fresh spirit water was now but rubble. All of the furniture was broken and Wang Long had nothing else to sit on than a large throne-like chair that somehow survived his onslaught.

“Well, what are you waiting for?”

“E-excuse our rudeness, young master.”

The three scantily clad girls were quick to attend to their master. Wang Long was a bit irked so he continued to stare at the three women. He could tell that they were afraid of him, one of them even stumbled for a moment and was quick to bow her head before him.

He continued to glance at these three ‘people’ while they served him the wine and some spirit fruits. One of them started to even give him a shoulder massage which was actually quite relaxing. But as soon as his rage was subsiding he started recalling a large fist that connected with his nose.

It was a rare moment in his life, after he joined this place he had never really suffered through a real setback. His position as a young master gave him certain prestige. Even though there were other young masters before him, thanks to the system he was able to leave them in the dust quite fast.

He had long forgotten how it felt to actually lose a battle as after figuring out the system shop he had never lost. The only thing that he needed to do when he was up against a stronger foe was to visit a place with slightly weaker enemies and farm them for points. He was also given more and more spirit stones with each victory from the sect which made things even easier.

When the memories of the fight that he lost and the face of the man responsible for it came up, he felt the rage built up again. His hand pushed into the large throne-like chair and caused the armrest to burst.

“Ack.”

“Eeek.”

The girls that were tending to him closed their eyes as the splinters from the special chair exploded everywhere.

“God damn that fucker, I’m going to kill him, damn NPC lover, what’s so good about these AI’s”

Wang Long looked at one of the girls that had fallen down on the ground and pointed out at her.

“You there, bark like a dog.”

The grown woman hesitated for a moment but was quick to follow the order that this young master had given here.

“You, balance yourself on one leg and start juggling.”

The second girl was ordered to perform some acts while the third one continued with the shoulder massage.

‘Nothing but lifeless drones, they just do what they are told, what does that guy even see in them?’

Wang Long was confused about Zhang Dong’s way of acting. It looked like he actually cared about the NPCs from this world that to him were nothing more than tools for his pleasure and amusement. Tools that would be used and then thrown away.

After he was bored with giving them orders he called one of the girls over. With an empty expression on his face, he pointed out with his finger towards this woman.

The poor girl didn’t even have enough time to blink before a large bright ray of light escaped from Wang Long’s digit. It instantly evaporated her into fine particles while causing the two other girls that were in the room to jump to the side in fright.

“Not even enough points to use teleportation…”

Wang Long was more interested in the feeble amount of spirit points that he received from his system. The woman was a great circle foundation establishment cultivator but the number he got was just ten spirit points.

Ever since he achieved the nascent soul level, the number of points he was given had declined drastically. It was clear that the system wouldn’t allow him to grind too much on the weaker mobs in this world.

‘Unless I kill something close to my level I barely get enough points…’

This was mostly the reason that he had stagnated for the past years. Nascent Soul cultivators were quite rare and beasts of the same level were even rarer. One reason he went after large sects was also the points, when he couldn’t hunt the nascent soul masters the volume of the kills mattered.

But this grinding trick that he knew also started going away the moment he achieved the middle stage. At this point, he was not getting any points from people below the foundation establishment level and even a great circle veteran gave him ten points.

“What are you looking at? Just go away.”

While contemplating where he could get more points he spotted the cowering girls. Growing bored with the two he just waved with his hand and the two were able to leave.

With the realization that there was another player in this world, Wang Long had a lot to think about. Previously he thought that this was just a big playground given to him that he was the main character in.

A single-player sandbox game for him to do whatever he wanted and whenever he wanted.One that would not really progress if he didn’t act.

With Zhang Dong being there he started to feel threatened. He already lost to him in an open fight and he didn’t feel like he would be able to win in the short term. It seemed that his opponent was somehow gaining the system and hiding the real numbers from him.

“I need to level up… that bastard also got those idiot elders… they were all late stage… at least I managed to ks Tong before he got to him.”

While the biggest reason that elder Tong was stabbed by him was to get away from there, he also knew that he would be getting the most spirit points from him. The ten late stage elders when put together would probably give a bit more points but it was close.

“Also I need to lure him out somewhere, fighting in his faction was probably giving his forces buffs and where did he get that flying fortress from?”

Wang Long started going through his system store but anything at the level of that flying castle would cost him an arm and a leg. He wasn’t really someone that was interested in crafting so he didn’t realize that there were other ways that one could get stronger without buying everything off the store.

“Young master, please explain yourself! Why can’t we reach elder Tong? Where are the ships, where are all the elders!”

While Wang Long was talking to himself an angry-looking old man entered the room that he was staying in. He was wearing an identical robe to Tong’s and was clearly not concerned by this young man’s position.

“Explain yourself? What happened?”

“Could you shut up, I need to think, Chao.”

“You…”

The old man scoffed at the quick reply and then started looking around the room. He could feel that spiritual energy had been used to kill someone which angered him even more.

“I don’t care that you are the grandson of the current Patriarch, you will explain yourself, even you are not above the sect!”

The old man approached Wang Long while exuding an oppressive aura that caused him to stagger a bit.

“Leave me alone, old fart, I need to get more spirit points or else…”

Wang Long looked at the man in front of him. The system showed that he was clearly a person at the great circle stage of nascent soul.

“Chao… this sect does possess quite a few nascent soul elders… doesn’t it?”

“What are you babbling about? Quickly explain yourself, what happened at that United Element’s sect.”

Wang Long moved his hand back so that this man could not see it and a black dagger appeared in his hand...

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 391

“Dong’er are you sure that this is safe…”

“I’m not sure… I guess half and a half?”

“Only half? Maybe we should try it on another sect member that isn’t as old as this old man.”

“Just be quiet and let me concentrate, I need to do it with someone that I’m more familiar with before I continue with the other sect members…”

“P-please be gentle…”

“Don’t worry I will… this might feel a bit strange so please bear with it…”

“Ahhh… it tingles…”

“...”

“What are you two doing in there!”

A confused-looking Zhang Liena burst into a hastily manufactured cave opening. There she saw her husband and his grandfather. The old man was bare-chested and in a lotus position and Zhang Dong had his hand on his back.

“Oh…”

“Is something wrong Liena? Is the Soaring Dragon Sect attacking?”

Zhang Dong called out while breaking his concentration. He had managed to cleanse every expert's impurities with the help of his system. This didn’t mean that everyone would be able to reach the next level just like that.

Normally what they would do, was to give a person that could potentially progress some pills and also time. But time was not something that they had as they could be attacked at any moment. Thus Zhang Dong decided to lend his energies to help people progress faster.

Zhang Jin was part of their inner circle and his body was similar to his own. Through these similarities, he wished to test how well he would be able to nourish his cultivation up. It seemed that he had forgotten that he had promised to give his wife a call when he was finished with the initial cleansing stage.

“I’m sorry, I was just too busy with work, how are you?”

Liena started blushing a bit, he wasn’t sure what this was about but it seemed that she misunderstood something. Zhang Dong could just move over to place his hand on her cheek.

“Don’t worry, I won’t vanish like last time.”

“It wasn’t like I was worried or anything…”

She started blushing even more and Zhang Dong could feel that his wife’s body heat was increasing. But before he could lean in for a hug and maybe something extra he heard someone chuckling from the side.

“Oh, don’t mind me, pray continue with what you were doing, I bet you two have a lot of catching up to do, don’t mind this old man being here!”

Liena quickly moved away from Zhang Dong after hearing Zhang Jin commenting from the side. The old man just started laughing which caused the matriarch to stare at him with intent. To diffuse the situation Zhang Dong decided to quickly speak up as he didn’t want to have his grandfather being mutilated by his lovely wife.

“Um, I’ll be stuck here for a little bit, is there any word from the spies outside…”

“That is the surprising part, it doesn’t look like they are attempting anything but we didn’t have any spies placed directly in their sect, the closest one was by a nearby sect but it has been quiet…”

“That does sound odd… you’d think that they would be making a big deal out of losing so many elders and ships, could they be silencing the news so that they don’t lose face?”

Zhang Dong asked while contemplating. A few days have passed since the attack but no news of any retaliation had reached them. If another large force would be getting formed it would not go unnoticed.

At most, the Soaring Dragon Sect could teleport through a gate to a closer location before attacking. Such a large undertaking would be noticed before they reached their borders as the sect had done well at placing their people at strategic locations throughout the whole empire.

“That’s a possibility, maybe the word hasn’t reached them? Wang Long vanished without losing a trace and we took care of the rest, we even managed to catch all the stragglers that fled into the forest.”

Zhang Jin chimed in while Zhang Dong tried to come to a conclusion. What would be the reason that would make that sect wait?

“Maybe they want to act, but can’t for some reason? Maybe they truly fear the Azure Emperor and the Heavenly Crane sect…”

This was the only logical conclusion that he could come up with. If it was true then he would not need to worry about being attacked any time soon. Maybe if Wang Long was the sect leader they would be attacking instantly but he didn’t seem like someone that worked well in a team. To him, his sect brothers and sisters were nothing but pawns.

The Patriarch that was his grandfather would probably think everything through before coming to a decision. Blindly going against someone that managed to slay that many nascent soul masters was not something that should be taken lightly.

“What worries me is what the Azure Emperor and the Heavenly Crane Sect will do, gramps do you think they might aid each other?”

“I don’t think that’s a possibility, the great three never saw eye to eye, they would sooner aid us before giving a hand to the Soaring Dragon Sect.”

Zhang Dong nodded, the more turmoil that they caused for the Soaring Dragon Sect the happier the other two would be. They probably wished to snatch the mainlands that were in the center of the empire for themselves and only then worry about the United Element Sect.

“Well, there is no use to worry, we can only look towards the future, gramps get back into position, we need to get you into the nascent soul level, or was there something else?”

Zhang Dong looked at his wife and just shook her head. While he was glad that she was worried about him to the point of paying him a visit here, it was not the time for a family get-together.

Soon Liena left the cave and was greeted by her grandmother.

“See, I told you that he would return, my husband, isn’t so easily killed. It’s best that you don’t mention that you wanted me to remarry.”

“Yes, that would be best...”

Feng Maling nodded while also sweating a bit. She had gone through this cleansing procedure about five years before but this one felt a bit more intense. The other elders that were in the great circle level were all on the ground and meditating.

“But Liena, do you really think that it's wise to stay? I understand that you want to listen to your husband but I worry about the future of this sect, what if we…”

“No, he is the Patriarch, without him there would be no sect, if you doubt him then you can just leave, no one will stop you.”

Feng Maling was glared down by her granddaughter and started chuckling.

“Your love for him didn’t waver one bit, it might have only gotten stronger, fine I’ll put my faith into the young Patriarch, if we falter then we shall pass on from this world together.”

The old woman nodded and was about to join the other core formation experts before feeling something. She together with all the others looked to the cave into which Zhang Dong and Zhang Jin vanished.

“What is that…”

The ground started to rumble and the cave opening that was being guarded lit up in blue. There was clearly something happening inside but no one dared to enter. They were told by the Patriarch that there would be strong energy fluctuations during the change and that they should not interrupt the process or it might cost Zhang Jin his life.

“Everyone, let us give the Patriarch some space.”

Feng Maling called out to the people that were sitting around and trying to get their own cultivation in check. They all nodded and quickly put some space between themselves and the small mountain that they had set up their training camp.

A tremendous amount of energy filled the area and it continued to rise well past the levels of what a core formation expert would be able to produce.

“By the ancestors, is that old idiot really going to progress?”

Feng Maling’s eyes bulged out as she hovered next to her granddaughter that had helped her move out of the range of this energy.

“If my husband said that he would be able to do it, then he will be able to do it!”

Liena on the other hand just nodded while smiling. She started looking around to see a forest of astonished faces. Everyone’s jaws were agape at the demonstration here. It was clear that they weren’t sure if the Patriarch’s plan would work. After five long years, a chunk of them had forgotten how big of a miracle worker Zhang Dong was.

They would remember after this day that their leader had the golden touch. The mountain exploded with another burst of energy that approached the level of a nascent soul master. This wasn’t a gentle transformation, no, from inside the mountain Zhang Jin’s screams could soon be heard.

“Bare with it, we are almost there!”

Shouted Zhang Dong before the closed-off mountain blew its top. A pillar of deep blue escaped from it that formed a fountain of water. This burst of clear blue transformed into a mighty serpent with wings that gave out a mighty roar.

“H-he did it!”

The old grandma could not believe what she was seeing. Inside of this water dragon stood a half-naked Zhang Jin. His age started getting to him these past five years but now he looked like a new man. Even some color returned to his hair after he achieved this new level of power.

When they looked up they could see Zhang Jin floating up in the air. Behind him was Zhang Dong who still had his palm on his grandfather’s shoulder. It looked like he was constantly helping the old man with his new transformation and only pulled back after it was done.

“T-this… I feel a hundred years younger!”

Zhang Jin was ecstatic as he shouted out. His aura spread through the area and brought the core formation elders to their knees. Luckily Liena was there to block it, otherwise, some of them would have blacked out instantly.

“You old fool, get a hold of yourself, you’re not the only one here!”

Feng Maling shouted out in anger but only when Zhang Jin got smacked to the back of the head by Zhang Dong did he realize what he was doing.

“Oh… excuse this old man, I must have lost myself…”

“Yeah… you should go meditate and check if your cultivation is stable, it does look like your nascent soul is stable but you’ll need some time before you can make your soul beast appear.”

Zhang Dong nodded and then looked down at Feng Mailing.

“Okay granny, you’re next, then I’ll start with the rest of the elders, please decide on the order yourself.”

Everyone nodded while looking with sparkly eyes at the floating Zhang Jin. To them it was a miracle in the making, to allow them to reach this level of power Zhang Dong was a true saint to them.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 392

“Elder Wang? Is there a problem?”

“You must apologize for my behavior, Lord Qing Long but I need to tend to some family problems.”

“Is that so?”

Three men were drinking spirit alcohol with each other in a wide-open room. All of them were holding small cups made from white jade in which there was some glowing liquid inside. This was the purest spirit that would be quite deadly if drunk by an ordinary cultivator.

One of them was the Soaring Dragon Sect’s Patriarch, Xuan Wang. He was a man known throughout the whole empire as he was part of one of the big three. Next to him sat someone that was his equal, Tao Guan the Patriarch of the Heavenly Crane Sect.

The two were both having a conversation with the leading cultivator, the Azure Emperor Qing Long. While this conversation continued the Soaring Dragon Patriarch was given a transmission through his communication jade.

“Lord Xuan, Can’t this family matter not wait? Isn’t it rude to bring such matters up while we are discussing our alliance?”

Tao Guan commented while covering part of his face with a fan. On the back, there was an intricate pink design of a crane that was the staple of his sect.

“Lord Tao, it’s fine, family is very important, I’m sure Lord Xuan wouldn’t bring this to our ears if it wasn’t important.”

The man called the Azure Emperor just waved with his hand in a bored fashion. He looked the youngest from the group of three but this didn’t mean that he wasn’t just as old as the other two top cultivators in the empire.

Wang Xuan’s face twitched slightly but he was able to hold it in. For a moment he looked at the old man holding the fan. It looked like he wanted to say something but with the Azure Emperor being so close he decided not to. Soon the old man from the Soaring Dragon Sect went away which left the other two behind.

“With lord Xuan’s absence, I propose that we postpone the talks for a few days.”

While the Azure Emperor asked this, it was clear that he wasn’t really hoping to get any confirmation from the other cultivator next to him. He was clearly already standing up to leave even as he gave his preposition.

“Then I will return to my quarters.”

Tao Guan nodded as it seemed to be over and along with everyone else in this wide chamber he began to leave. While the three top cultivators were discussing their retainers were spread out through this large chamber. Only when their leaders walked over to them could they stand up and leave with them.

“Patriarch.”

A group of scholarly men in similar white robes greeted the old man. It was clear that this Patriarch of theirs was slightly maddened by the way the Soaring Dragon Patriarch acted.

“What is that idiot thinking, what is so important that he would make such a scene?”

He posed this question to the group with the intent of them giving him an answer. One of the scholarly men walked up and started whispering into the Patriarch’s ear. After a moment the old Patriarch moved the fan over his mouth and nodded at the group before leaving without giving a reply.

As the two elders were walking away the Azure Emperor retreated behind his throne and back to his own room. Inside he found his wife that was in the process of feeding a baby.

“Are you finished, my Emperor?”

“Not quite my love.”

“Is there something wrong? Are they perhaps plotting something to bring my Emperor down?”

The woman smiled at the blue-haired man while holding their offspring in her hand. The man’s stone-cold expression seemed to melt away the moment he laid eyes on his wife and the future of his clan that she was holding in her hand.

“Hah, when are they not plotting to bring me down? Still, Wang’s outburst was strange indeed, what could shake that old monster up so much?”

“Wahhhh….”

While the Azure Emperor was talking the baby started crying. The man revered by the whole empire looked at the small child. He started fumbling about in a panicked state while not knowing what was the reason for such an outburst.

“My Emperor, it might not be the right moment to bring up politics while the child is trying to eat.”

“You speak the truth, my wife, I should consult the royal guard.”

The woman just smiled while picking the small boy up and cradling him around. Soon the man walked away to perform his duties. The royal guard was just the word for his inner circle of retainers. He needed to get to the bottom of this strange predicament. Was the Soaring Dragon Sect in some trouble and if this could potentially endanger the empire’s future.

“Ah, whatever would I do without you my wife~”

The Emperor chuckled while giving his wife and crying child a big hug. Then he soon left to get to the bottom of this debacle. The empire was his to run and he needed to know everything that went on in it.

“My Emperor, I am here to serve.”

In another chamber, a group of powerful cultivators was assembled. The Emperor took a seat to overlook his men and the meeting started.

“I don’t think I have to remind you about the dire times we face. The barrier between empires is wavering, we don’t have time, we need to know where their allegiance lies.”

War was coming and the Azure Emperor was aware of this. This was information that very few had knowledge of, it was something that was left behind by the other Azure Emperors that came before him. Now it was finally up to him to make use of it.

For many hundreds of years, he had made preparations. The other two sects might have been strong but the Azure Empire had been here long before those two came to power.

Once every hundred thousand years the barrier between worlds would come undone. He knew that his was not the only Empire in this large world. There were others and they would come to test them.

It was an old prophecy passed around through time immemorial. It had survived to this day and after certain predictions came true it was clear that the day that the massive war started was upon them.

While the people here were fearful of the unknown empires that could emerge from other sides of this barrier there were also hopeful. There was a limit to what they could learn here and the top cultivators felt that they were at an impasse that they could not go through.

The nascent soul level had not been broken but the knowledge of a stage above it was widespread. It had become nothing more than a legend that sometimes was confirmed due to the existence of a handful of immortal grade treasures.

The knowledge to progress into this legendary immortal stage had been long lost. The nascent soul masters had tried everything but to no avail. Even those that turned to demonic rituals were unable to place their foot inside this fabled realm.

Now they were somewhat hopeful that the answers would be given to them in the other empires. Maybe if they gained the knowledge from other places it could complete the piece of the puzzle that they were trying to finish for all these millennia.

For this to work, they needed to overwhelm their enemies with their might. While the Azure Dragon Clan had been training for all these thousands of years for this very day, it didn’t mean that they wanted to do everything themselves.

There were other forces in this empire that they would utilize first before they used their trump cards. First came the lower level sects that were situated closer to these barriers between empires. They would be the vanguard and would test their enemies first.

They knew that the curious cultivators would be unable to resist the temptation of journeying into the unknown lands. If they managed to battle their way inside without much resistance it would just show that the other side was ill-prepared.

On the other hand, if the opposition showed itself to be far above their predictions they might have to choose a more reserved battle strategy. The middle reaches that they resided would be almost impossible to breach by any force.

The old grand formations left by the ancestors dipped their toes into the immortal stage, unless the opposition could match their defensive capabilities they would be able to outlast any prolonged siege. Even if the empire crumbled around them, they would be secure in their lands where they could sustain themselves indefinitely.

The borders would close up in time and then they could establish themselves as the leading force once again. They would either conquer or be forced to be watchers while their own empire crumbled into dust and their people became nothing more than slaves.

This would be something that the Azure Emperor was willing to risk. As long as the Long Clan survived the empire could flourish again in the future.

While the secret meeting continued, in another location a certain angry-looking Patriarch was looking at a peculiar message.

“How could this be? What has transpired back at the sect?”

“We don’t know Patriarch, our communications attempts have not been fruitful, it is as if …”

“As if what? There is no one there to answer? Did that bastard crane lie to me? Is he and the Azure Emperor working together against my Sect?”

The old man asked while kicking over a table. An attendant that was standing next to him continued to speak.

“Our ships have not been seized, there has not been any increased military activity in the vicinity of the Long Clan, It does not seem that they are aware of this either.”

The man tried to calm the Patriarch down as it was now, they had not been attacked by any of the other two great powers. Their large armada of ships was still on standby outside and their powerful nascent soul elders were still ready to engage in combat if there was an order by the Patriarch.

“Our defensive formations are impenetrable, even if a spy made his way inside our sect they would be unable to work the formation, only the Patriarch and the next in line can…”

“Wait, what did you say?”

The man was grabbed by his shoulders by the old Patriarch that started shaking him around.

“P-Patriarch? Only you can work the grand formation fully… Did I say something that offended you?”

“No, the latter part!”

“A-about your successor? But the young master would never…”

The Patriarch pushed the man out of the way while looking out into the distance a bad feeling washing over his old bones as he looked at a certain communication jade that he didn’t use yet. This one connected him to his grandson that had been pledged in as the next in line to the sect’s throne, Wang Long.

Chapter 393

“Please, take a break, it has already been a week, you look pale…”

“I’m fine but you might be right… if the enemies come I won’t be able to offer them much resistance like this…”

A somewhat shriveled-up Zhang Dong was looking at his lovely wife Zhang Liena. She had come bearing some homemade cooking with spirit energy-packed foods.

“Elders, we will postpone the transcendence till tomorrow, I must rest.”

Zhang Dong looked at a smaller group of elders that was composed of less than twenty. He had been working hard on helping most of them pass into the nascent soul stage but he was slowly reaching his limit. The white seed that now powered his cultivation gave him a lot of energy but it also had its limits.

“We understand Patriarch, we will await your return.”

All of them were still in the pocket dimension. After blowing up several mountain tops with the nascent soul realm boost they decided to set up an open-air version. He would just sit with the cultivator in the middle of a special formation on an altar and boost them up.

The process was not really that hard as somehow his new cultivation allowed him to forcefully insert his dao into people. This Dao would mix with his target's cultivation and fill out the holes in it.

He wasn’t sure why but the Dao Seed inside him had those properties. It was able to boost the lesser Nascent Souls to flourishing and only required a set of spiritual energy. Through this, he was already able to create thirty new nascent soul elders from the core formation experts that they brought here.

They were still only early stage cultivators but their foundation was solid. Thanks to the system’s cleansing feature and the high grade cultivation methods that their sect possessed, the elders would be much stronger than regular nascent soul masters.

They would be able to rival middle stage nascent soul masters in a one-on-one battle. Then due to the sheer number, they would be able to team up in formation attacks to compete with stronger foes.

“Thank you, whatever would I do without you… but uh… you don’t need to feed me yourself…”

Zhang Dong had returned outside the dimensional regalia. With the castle that they lived in having been destroyed and replaced by a metallic fortress of cannons, they found a different villa to stay in for now. At this very moment, he had his wife sitting in his lap while trying to feed him a piece of fruit.

“Yes I do!”

Without wanting to argue about this he opened wide and the airplane made its way into his mouth. He chomped down on the sweet treat and started chewing.

“Now me! I want to feed daddy like a baby too!”

He looked to the other side and there was his almost seven year old daughter. She had another fruit in her hand and was holding it out with some chopsticks. With a smile on his face, he just nodded and opened up to get fed.

While the two girls were all over him, the other male from the family remained seated away from the group. Zhang Dong could see him peeking out from the corner of the eye as if he wanted to say something but the moment he turned his gaze to meet his son’s eyes, he averted it.

It seemed that his wife and oldest child had become quite clingy. Whenever he went they were there. If he wanted to go into the garden to meditate, they would plop down next to him and do the same.

If he wanted to eat, they would try to feed them. If he wanted to put some clothes on, they would be there to pick out the right robe for him to wear. He would not even get peace in the bathroom as they would start to bang on the door if he locked it.

While he liked that his family was showing him love and affection it was starting to get annoying. He needed to recover his spiritual energy to push his elders to the next level as their life depended on it.

“Daddy has had enough for now, how about you go play with your brother.”

He petted his daughter on the head while pointing over to Zhang Jun. The moment Zhang Xiu saw her younger brother she pouted a bit.

“Jun, why are you still there, you are being rude!”

She charged off the couch that the three were sitting on and started chasing after her younger brother.

“They sure are energetic…”

While the small girl continued to chase her brother and he continued to run away, Liena still remained on top of his lap. He was finding her childish behavior quite cute but for things, to last they needed to get stronger.

“That Soaring Dragon Sect… what are they doing… they should have tried something by now…”

After a moment of silence between the two, he decided to speak out. The Soaring Dragon Sect was a big problem that required solving. Since Wang Long’s appearance already a week had passed and in this week he was able to strengthen his sect to new heights.
Even though they all expected the giant sect to react in some way, they didn’t. There was no declaration of war, they didn’t try to get the other middle sized sects involved in their struggle nor did they send anyone to make any demands.

“It is unbecoming of them… did something happen? You seem to know that man called Wang Long, did he perhaps come from that other world you mentioned before?”

“Yes, he did but I’m not sure I can talk him out of this anymore....”

His wife was already aware of his otherworlder status as he had come clean to her while the first child was on the way. While that time he kept it vague she knew Zhang Dong’s true name which was Matthew.

At this point in time, Matt didn’t think that his fellow earthling would be able to see the error of his ways. He was convinced that this was some kind of virtual reality experience in some kind of supercomputer. On the other hand, he knew that there was more to this than a simple game.

There were many other worlds that he had seen as he tumbled through that rift in space in time. He had only visited one of them but it was enough to get the general idea of what was happening here. The question was why did these words place people from earth on them just to give them a cheat system.

“That’s fine with me, let us not give him a swift death!”

Zhang Dong’s eyes jumped up a bit as he noticed that his wife was clearly still mad. He wasn’t sure what she was thinking but probably being almost forcefully taken by some random person was not something a prideful cultivator woman like her took lightly.

“It would probably be better to get rid of him when we get the chance, I’m not sure if it will be that easy to get rid of him.”

His Ai Bob was still silent about the reason for this. The only clue he had to figure this out was the strange person he saw when he absorbed the first cube-shaped nucleus. He burned through almost all of the cubes he received from the other world so he needed a recharge.

‘I wonder if I could go check that place out for some answers… but is now a good time for it?’

He thought of the place that started this all, the place where he became untethered from the main system. It was the strange secret ground that he almost died in. It was still a mystery to him and there was still that large door that he never visited.

With the demise of the dark palm sect, he would now be able to go check it out. Even though it was in the vicinity of the other sects he was strong enough to force his way there.

He was brought on to speed about the other medium sized sects after he returned. The Limitless Sword Society had lost its leader and had been declining for a while now. The other sects saw them as an easier target and were forcing them back into their mainlands.

On the other hand, his own United Element Sect remained strong. Word of his disappearance was only getting out recently but now he could show himself again to keep everyone at bay.

He wanted to pay that secret ground a visit. Now with Bob with him, he might be able to figure out some things when he got there. Some answers and also some helpful items could be behind that large gate.

With his current strength, he might be able to get through whatever was inside. The biggest problem would be opening it back up. His sect was now much stronger so they would probably be able to get through those old monsters and tower defense stage without much of a problem if he explained the rules.

The question was if he would even need to go that far. There could be ways to get around this trial phase as he already had gone through it before.

“You are too soft my husband, such demons need to be punished! He even murdered one of his own sect elders just to flee, how could such a person be the next Patriarch.”

“Hm?... yes how could he… wait…”

While thinking about the secret ground his wife continued to talk. She brought up the murder of that elder Tong that happened. Zhang Dong knew that he did it for spirit points but what if there was more to it now?

“Wait… the Soaring Dragon Sect has been quiet for some time right?”

“Yes? Our spies are unable to confirm anything, the areas around the main city are being rightly guarded so they weren’t able to slip by.”

He started to get a bad premonition. As Wang Long has already slain one elder for points, what if he decided to continue with the trend? While the system mostly worked as a cash shop it was also able to directly increase one's cultivation. What better place to get points than at a massive sect with many nascent soul masters, treasures, and beast alike?

“That bastard wouldn’t… right?”

Zhang Dong mumbled to himself while getting up. If he was right with his theory the person that he had thought a week ago might be going through a massive strength increase. While he was trying to increase his sect's all-around strength the enemy went for a different approach.

“He wouldn’t? Is there something wrong?”

“I don’t know yet… I need to talk to Zhang Kuo!”

Chapter 394

“H-how could you do this… hundreds of years of planning…”

“Oh hey there old fart, do you like what I did with the place? Give me a moment, I just need a little sip.”

Wang Long was holding a person’s head in his hand while staring deep into their eyes. The person was motionless and by the robe, he was wearing it was clear that he was of high status.

A ray of dark purple light escaped from Wang Long’s eyes and entered the man’s eye sockets. His body started convulsing and spasming in random directions as the dark light took over it. In a matter of seconds, his body turned into a dried-up husk that quickly dropped down to the ground next to other similar husks that were once powerful cultivators.

The dark light that escaped Wang Long’s eyes soon returned to its master. It entered back through his mouth and revitalized his body increasing his cultivation by a small fraction in the process.

“Ah, I should have gone with the demonic cultivation a long time ago, do you know how much easier it is to cultivate with it? Just a little suck and I improve, no more pesky meditation for this guy!”

Wang Long chuckled while looking at Wang Xuan, the current Soaring Dragon Patriarch. The old man’s face was pale as he looked around. Above him was a giant black dragon whose wings were glowing in dark purple light. Even now he could feel his own nascent soul being drawn to these wings as his grandson’s soul beast was clearly absorbing the souls of everyone in the vicinity.

“Why Long’er… why would you destroy the Sect that brought you up? We were meant to be the new Emperors!”

Wang Long stuck a finger into his nose as the old man continued to talk but it didn’t seem that he cared much.

“That old questline? I never liked it in the first place, I didn't think it would have worked anyway, I was always better at playing solo.”

Wang Long laughed while looking at the large number of points he had gathered through this short period of time. After the Patriarch left the sect he had decided to get rid of his faction. There were no rules against killing your own people for points and points is what he needed.

There was not much to it, he was a trusted sect member feared by all. His plan consisted of having the strongest elders visit his peak one by one till almost all of them were dead. Before they could figure out that he was killing them it was already too late.

The sect reserves, the council of old elders was also there. It was composed of the oldest nascent soul elders that had retired from the sect life. They were there to only act as a last resort as their life energy was slowly fading.

Luckily for Wang Long, they were put in an induced slumber to keep them alive for long. They would only be awoken to perform battle tasks that required a large powerful force before returning back into the underground below the sect grounds.

With some secret techniques that the Patriarch had given him, he was able to operate the grand formation. This formation was also responsible for awakening these old monsters and also keeping them hidden away.

The large chamber where they slumbered was something that was shown to him by the current Patriarch, Wang Xuan. This show of faith would be this Sect’s undoing as the only people that had a reasonable chance to take him out, would not even get a chance to fight.

When the deed was done and almost all of the powerful elders were taken out, he continued with phase two of his plan. He ordered everyone to return to the sect at once, with the help of the formation he would be able to trap them here, and with his newfound strength that he gained from killing so many monstrous cultivators he could not be stopped.

The points that he had received were spent to gain some new and improved immortal grade abilities. He threw away his old method that was similar to his enemies. After seeing Zhang Dong absorb his lightning he knew that it would be an uphill battle anytime they met.

Instead, he decided to go with one of the demonic techniques. The one he chose was the Abyssal Devouring Scripture. It allowed him to feed on people’s souls and Qi to make them his own. With every devoured soul his soul beast would increase in size and his cultivation would be pushed towards a new point.

After going through his whole sect he was already on equal footing with the strongest cultivators that this empire had to offer. This didn’t mean that he was going to stop, there were more people living here, he could still get much stronger before fighting his opponent.

“Questline? What are you talking about… Tong was right about you… I should have never trusted you.”

“Blah blah, you just figured that out, old man? I have to thank you though, if you never left the sect I would have probably never been able to go through this plan so easily, thanks for giving me the keys to the formation, it came in handy.”

The old Soaring Dragon Patriarch looked around himself and could see thousands of bodies on the ground. All of them were dried-up corpses of his fellow sect members. Women, children the elderly, no one was spared from Wang Long’s demonic technique.

“You damn monster! I will not show any mercy to a foul wretch like you, as long as I live the Soaring Dragon Sect can recover!”

His cultivation exploded causing the ground to rumble and split apart. Wang Xuan’s cultivation peak was at the great circle of the nascent soul. He along with the Azure Emperor and the Patriarch from the Heavenly Crane sect were believed to be the top three cultivators of this empire. Even when going against Wang Long he didn’t show fear as he still believed to be stronger.

“Haha, not so fast old man, do you really think that I wouldn’t come prepared for you?”

Wang Long had learned from the previous encounter that there was strength in traps. While his new cultivation level was strong he was not that eager to test it out against an opponent as strong as this Soaring Dragon Sect leader.

The spot that he had lured him over was something that he prepared beforehand. With so many points that he gained, he had a myriad of choices that he could pick from. Most of his spirit points were burned through into his own main cultivation level.

The system had a bad ratio if a person wanted to go with that path but it was not impossible. Wang Long was not someone that worried about life so from his perspective he could always grind for some more spirit points and ignore regular cultivation altogether.

“Activate, abyssal prison!”

Wang Long pointed at the ground and before Wang Xuan could power up fully he was tossed into a strange demonic dimension. The whole area around him went dark and shackles made of dark purple energy started appearing from all directions.

“Where did you learn this? Did you partake in some demonic teachings?”

Wang Xuan let his cultivation explode in an attempt to force these shackles made of demonic energy away. Behind him a dragon made of pure gold appeared, its size even larger than the soul beast that Wang Long was controlling.

The soul beast gave out a large roar which was followed by an explosion of golden heavenly light. This energy blast causes the shackles to burst into tiny particles of dark light.

“Hah, do you think that this was all?”

Wang Long’s voice echoed through this dark dimension that Wang Xuan was trapped in. The shackles made of demonic energy continued to come at him from all sides.

The shackles had various tips, some were in the shape of sickles, while others looked like rusted over nails. The golden dragon continued to radiate the heavenly light but with time the sharp shackles started connecting with its scales. The nails rammed themselves into the beast’s flesh while others wrapped themselves around its appendages.

Quickly Wang Xuan felt strength leaving him, he realized too late that this strange dimension was sapping away at his vitality. Now with his soul beast shackled he was unable to exert more of his energy to getaway. He realized that if he noticed sooner and just prioritized escaping there would be a chance but now it was too late.

“Wang Long!”

He called out in anger as he flew towards where his grandson’s figure flashed. A giant spear in his hand appeared while his whole body was surrounded by a golden glow.

“What are you looking at? I’m over here.”

The spear connected with something and the darkness subsided. What it was embedded in was a leftover steel statue of one of the older Patriarch’s. Just as it was split apart he felt something grab his shoulder from behind.

This was followed by all of his strength leaving him as Wang Long activated his energy absorbing technique that he had bought from the System Store.

The old man’s dried-up husk slowly fell to the ground. Along with it came the statue under which he was buried. The last thing that he saw before his death were the vacant eyes of his grandson that he had fostered to this day.

This signaled the end of the Soaring Dragon Sect, its Patriarch slain by his own kin. There were still a few leftover members in the further regions of the empire that were not able to return but their base of power was in ruin.

Wang Long floated over the landscape slowly while taking in the sights. All of the peaks were in ruins and there were no people left alive to tell the tale. The plan to take over the Empire was over and it died along with Wang Xuan.

“Hm, that went better than I expected, what should I do now…”

The grand formation that was shrouding the whole sect came undone and revealed the destruction within. He knew that in time people would realize what he did but would probably not be able to point fingers at him.

“This sect is done but there is still more…”

With a little nod and soon his body vanished from this silent battlefield. The massive dragon that was hovering above ground was nowhere to be seen and nothing but death and destruction was left.

Soon the news of the behemoth of a sect vanishing in just a few days would reach the ears of every important party around the empire...

Chapter 395

“Is this information correct?”

“Yes Patriarch, our spies have been on the site of the incident and this information is slowly spreading through the Soaring Dragon Sect’s lands…”

“Is that so… you can leave.”

“As you command, Patriarch!”

Zhang Dong looked at an information jade with the intelligence report of what transpired at the Soaring Dragon Sect. It had been already two weeks since the incident with Wang Long and to this day he did not return.

The preparations that his sect was performing for another battle seemingly went to waste as one of the big three was no more. It was all in this report, the place where the sect used to stand was nothing more than a ghost town.

It was apparently covered in some dark demonic energy that was hard to pass. The scouts from his sect had fake identities as members of some local clans or merchants. They couldn’t get too close due to their lack of cultivation but the word was spreading fast.

It was clear to Zhang Dong that this had been something orchestrated by his fellow earthling, Wang Long.

‘That bastard must have switched to demonic arts to quickly increase his cultivation…’

He was aware of what his counterpart was doing. The system shop was known to him and he had gone through its sections to know what kind of abilities Wang Long picked up.

While he had ignored that certain demonic art section, Wang Long certainly didn’t. Those arts allowed a person to suck away their opponent's vitality while making part of it their own.

These arts were clearly designed to level up faster if a person didn’t have any moral qualm in killing everything around themselves. These abilities incentivized wanton slaughter but also became weaker if the user didn’t perform enough heinous acts.

Being a person that likes to sleep at night he ignored that section of the system shop. He went in the opposite direction with the holy arts and his current divine cultivation method.

‘Previously that idiot had a similar cultivation method as I did before, he just went with the more offensive lightning variant…How many spirit points did he have to spend to totally redo his own cultivation?’

This was probably another reason why Wang Long went with the demonic cultivator variant. As he stood before he wouldn’t be able to harm Zhang Dong with any lightning-based attacks. On the other hand, Zhang Dong didn’t have any way to absorb evil dark energy which Wang Long was probably using.

Holy arts and Dark arts were opposite to each other. While he could purify demonic beings and was resistant to the corrosive nature of those energies, it was the same for Dark practitioners.

Wang Long would be able to counter his holy Qi with his newly gained dark Qi. In the end, the stronger one would win as both of these energies countered each other. That is if he ever got to fight him as it stood now there was no sign of the murderous young master that had caused the demise of his own sect.

“They are starting to call him the demonic dragon.”

While Zhang Dong was thinking Zhang Jin commented from the side. His wife and his red-haired friend Huo Qiang were also there as well as a certain granny that used to look like a baked potato. Ever since she stepped through into the nascent soul level her looks got revitalized.

A nascent soul master could live up to a thousand years. Sometimes longer if they used life-improving techniques. Whenever one that was old made it through this cultivation wall they regained some of their previous looks. It wasn’t that much but the old woman now looked
more as if she was in her late fifties than the late seventies as she did before.

“Do we need to be worried about this renegade? The whole empire will be after him, he will have to escape to the fringes of the empire unless he wants to be chased till the end of his life.”

Zhang Jin continued as he saw this as an absolute win. From his perspective, the sect was the true enemy that they needed to face. With it gone, the single demonic cultivator didn’t pose much of a threat.

“That would be nice but I don’t think our little demonic friend will be that easy to find…”

In Zhang Dong's mind, it was safer when Wang Long acted in a larger group as his location was known. Now on the other hand he would be impossible to find as he also had access to a myriad of disguising techniques that the system store could give him.

“Does he possess a similar technique to the one that you taught me?”

Zhang Dong nodded at Zhang Jin’s question which made the old man rethink his old stance.

“But even if he can hide, not like he can get through into our sect while you are here, isn’t that right Dong’er?”

“I should be able to detect his presence if he ever entered the range of our sect, that is true but…”

While it was true that his faction system was able to detect invaders he had to actually be here for that to work. Then there was the problem of his enemy being able to farm an almost unlimited number of spirit points by killing the citizens of this empire.

If he just decided to bunker up then Wang Long could reach an immense amount of power. If he could contend with such a strong demonic cultivator was not something he wanted to bet his trust into. His new cultivation was kind of strange and he wasn’t sure how to progress it without absorbing an astronomical amount of spirit stones, souls, and lightning energy.

“Is there something bothering you, my husband?”

Asked his wife as she was not really aware of Wang Long’s strange system. To them, the enemy would need to hide himself for many years for this to blow over. Even if he was to emerge with the current state of their sect there was nothing to fear.

“You worry too much senior brother, with so many elders achieving a breakthrough, not even the Azure Emperor could take us likely!”

Huo Qiang also put in a word in this small tactical meeting. He continued to help the elders with their breakthroughs and now they possessed a large force to be reckoned with.

“I’m not sure if having these many nascent soul elders will be such an asset if this Wang Long is in the picture.”

“What do you mean by this?”

They asked while Zhang Dong started explaining.

“We aren’t going against a simple foe, Wang Long possesses a strange technique that allows him to absorb the strength of the enemies that he slays. Through this he can reach new heights in a short amount of time, this is also why he was able to eradicate a huge sect like that so quickly.”

The reports that they were getting didn’t really mention how the young master managed to destroy the whole sect. They could only speculate that he had prepared some demonic ritual beforehand or that he was some old monster in disguise that devoured the sect from inside while the Patriarch was at the meeting with the Azure Emperor.

Zhang Dong knew the truth though, he had done it mostly by brute-forcing his way and getting spirit points from killing all those elders. The new demonic cultivation helped but it was all thanks to the system that he was able to do it quickly.

Now his own United Element Sect had a large number of nascent soul masters. He knew that if he just let them fly around the empire they would just be harvested for spirit points by his enemy.

“Such a technique exists? He must have really made a pact with some kind of demon… or might he be some kind of demonic rebirth?”

While the others speculated he just nodded as he was really unsure of what he should do. Either he would remain here and help his sect members get stronger or he needed to head out to hunt this monster down.

The new improved cultivation that he had made him stronger than a regular great circle nascent soul master. His opponent managed to slay the Soaring Dragon Sect’s Patriarch who was one of the most praised masters in the whole empire.

Demonic arts were quite strong against traditional cultivators. Zhang Dong that was able to not be affected by a large chunk of those techniques would have a better chance than someone that wasn’t versed in the holy arts, even when they were slightly stronger than him.

“The sect formation has been reinforced and the elders are progressing, I will aid them in materializing their soul beasts but then…”

He stopped himself while looking at his wife. While he wanted to head out in search of this demon before it was too late, he was still a father. What if he died or was wounded in the process of his chase? What if his sect that was looking suspicious was attacked by the two other leftover powerhouses in the empire.

Wang Long was a big threat but there was also the Azure Emperor and the Heavenly Crane sect that he needed to watch out for. With how they were able to counter the Soaring Dragon Sect’s attack they had also gained infamy. Wang Long’s name was spreading like wildfire but so was his.

Even though they wanted to keep it hidden word spread that Wang Long set out to the United Element’s Sect. A lot of people saw the parade of flying ships going to one location but they never made it back. It didn’t take them long to put two and two together.

The name Wang Long was infamous throughout this empire. Many beauties fell to this man’s lustful ways and never made it back to their own homes. Now that Wang Long was a wanted man, people weren’t afraid to make their run-ins with him public.

Even now he was getting reports of people popping up even in his own region that had a bone to pick with him. People even started to pull in a reward for anyone that would be willing to take the demonic cultivator out. Wang Long was slowly becoming the most notorious criminal throughout the whole empire.

“First let me help the elders with their soul beast, then we’ll decide on our next step.”

He rubbed his chin and was about to stand up from his chair but without warning, Zhang Kuo burst in through the door. Before he could be reprimanded by the people inside, he started shouting out.

“Patriarch you must forgive me for my rudeness but this is the direst situation. The … The Azure Emperor wishes to speak with you!”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 396

‘Well, this is an interesting turn of events… I have to go, don’t I?’

Zhang Dong was sitting in his office that had managed to survive the last attack on the Sect. On his table was an actual parchment that was handwritten with quite the formal invitation. The place that he was invited to was the Azure Emperor citadel, a huge castle in the middle of this country.

His own little sect ground was at the far reaches of this whole empire. It was a place mostly ignored by other sects and only with his knowledge he had turned it into a high quality cultivation spot.

This was all thanks due to the large spirit vein that they were harnessing down under this ground. They had managed to keep this secret under wraps and didn’t suffer any attacks from the other sects.

The Azure Emperor’s castle was right under a similar spiritual vein. He and the other large sects were in close proximity to it. All three of them had divided this spot amongst each other while also placing a huge dividing wall in between their lands. Due to this barricade, the other sects were not aware of the Soaring Dragon Sect’s fall until it was too late.

‘Is this going to be another trap or are they trying to seek a new ally?’

From Zhang Dong’s perspective, he was being called over there for the sole reason of being able to defend himself from the abrupt attack. They were also the last faction to be in contact with Wang Long before he lost his marbles.

‘Could they be thinking that I did something to Wang Long that made him turn into a demonic cultivator or something?’

This would be a dire situation for him and the whole sect. If the other two giants got the idea that he was somewhat able to turn someone into a demonic cultivator, they could try to eradicate them. There was no proof that something like that happened though so it was somewhat a far-fetched idea.

‘I still need to have some kind of escape strategy… there is no telling what these cultivators will blow out of proportions.’

Strength was still paramount in this world. If they judged him to be a threat to them, they could come up with any strange excuse for conflict. As long as they looked like the just side they could go through with an attack. He would not be surprised if he found himself in some trapped formation after he arrived at the Azure Emperor's house.

‘Though if they are planning to capture me, they will probably strike before I get close to their base.’

From his perspective the two leftover superpowers weren’t yet taking him seriously. This would be something to measure his and his sect’s worth. Thus if he managed to arrive at the castle he would probably be safe as he didn’t think that the Azure Emperor would bring an active threat over to his own throne room. That is unless he was trying to lure him into his home ground and was seriously thinking of taking him out right there.

‘I still have my escape feature, I should be able to escape from there even if they activate some trapping formations, isn’t that right, Bob?’

‘Affirmative.’

‘You sure haven’t been talking much lately or have been that useful since I got back to my sect…’

Bob his AI partner, didn't seem to do much besides answering his rudimentary questions. Then when he asked something more specific he never did seem to have a proper answer. In the world of sword and magic, he was more helpful.

This was somewhat understandable as Bob was a new function of his system. His system was depowered after a while and even with his new cultivation realm, it wasn’t quite recovered.

“Your thoughts?”

“You mustn't go, it must be a trap!”

Replied his lovely wife that had also gone through the letter.

“That’s a possibility but we can’t go against the Azure Emperor’s wishes, his decrees are final in this Empire and you know this.”

Commented Zhang Jin as a rebuttal to Zhang Liena’s outcry. It was clear to the old man that after Zhang Dong had returned his wife didn’t wish for him to leave again.

“I don’t like to agree with the old fart but there is not much that we can do…”

“Not you too granny…”

Feng Maling was also here as she was part of the family. He had asked all three of them to come here as he needed to reach a decision. The letter stated that he was to come alone and that after he arrived at the capital city he would be escorted by someone inside.

“If I don’t go they will see it as treason, I’m not sure our sect can handle Wang Long and both the Azure Emperor’s wrath at the same time.”

While the Soaring Dragon Sect was gone, there was always the danger of Wang Long popping up unannounced. This would be a good chance to get some friends in high places. If he could somehow get the strongest cultivator in the Empire to aid him, it would be very reassuring.

“But what if they throw you into a dungeon, try to torture you for information, what if…”
“Liena please stop, I get it… but I don’t think I can talk myself out of this.”

Zhang Dong stood up from his seat and moved over to his worried wife.

“If I don’t do this we will be forced into a defensive battle with the whole Empire, if there is a chance for a diplomatic resolution of our problem, don’t you think that we should try?”

“But…”

“Don’t get me wrong, I don’t trust that Azure Emperor either I’m not going in blind, if something happens I intend to escape.”

“You intend to escape from the Azure Citadel? I know that you have improved since you were gone, but even you wouldn’t be able to take the whole Long clan on…”

Added Zhang Jin as he wasn’t convinced that his great-grandson would be able to easily escape from.

“Do you remember the time you encountered that elder from the Dark Palm sect?”

“Elder Ming?”

“Yes, that one, what do you think of my arrival at that time?”

“Yes, you did materialize through a strange portal...”

Zhang Jin looked at Zhang Dong with a raised eyebrow as he tried to recall that encounter. His grandson did somewhat appear in a strange fashion through an even more mysterious portal. It did not seem to require any formation to work but he rationalized it by his grandson’s crafting knowledge.

“Do you mean?”

“Yes, I do have a way of escaping and now I don’t really need a portal.”

To convince his family that he would be fine he decided to bring out a monitor that was thankfully in his office. On it, he brought up a room where his disciple Zhang Xue and his children were.

“Can you see that doll little Xiu is holding?”

The screen was quite large and the group of adults could clearly see a very intricately made doll that looked like a small jade beauty in Zhang Xiu’s hand.

“Yes, I see it but what do you intend to…”

Before Zhang Jin could ask the question Zhang Dong vanished from the spot before him. Liena and him flinched a bit as they could tell that he used some strange technique to disappear.

They started looking around and soon discovered that the screen was showing another person. This person was Zhang Dong and he was waving at the camera.

“I didn’t feel that any Qi was used, how did he do that?”

The life in the sect had been somewhat peaceful so Zhang Dong never had to use the system’s teleportation feature before. It was a waste of spirit points as he could already fly and travel anywhere within minutes. Thus his wife had never experienced him teleporting anywhere in such a fashion and was also confused.

“Here, Xiu’er said that she wanted to eat some cookies also here.”

Before the people inside Zhang Dong’s office could speculate on how he got in the room where his daughter was, he returned.

“Hm?”

Liena looked down at the item that her husband was holding and recognized it as the toy that her daughter was playing with. This little demonstration demonstrated his teleportation ability which he intended to use if he ever needed to escape.

“I don’t require gates to teleport, if there is trouble I will instantly flee before they can activate any trap formations. Even if they do, this technique isn’t affected by regular teleportation jammers.”

Teleportation wasn’t something new in this world and there were ways to insulate buildings from such techniques. This didn’t take the system’s feature into consideration as it could go through such places with a small increase to the spirit points it required.

“I plan to use the Argonaut for this journey. The ship will stay afloat outside the Long Clan’s land and if something falls through during that meeting I will escape into the ship.”

He started explaining that his technique had some limitations and he would be able to escape into his flag ship. He didn’t go into detail but thanks to his faction system he was able to teleport himself to large flagships like the Argonaut.

The closer it was to him the fewer points he would need to escape. He had no idea how many anty-teleportation formations the Azure Emperor had so he needed to lower the spirit point cost to the absolute minimum.

“I hope that this will give you some peace of mind.”

Liena looked at the doll in her hand and had to agree that it was the one that her daughter was using. Soon a consensus was reached of him going into the lion’s den.
He was to leave quickly as the meeting was in a week. With the Argonaut’s speed, this would be about the amount of time that he would require to get there. Even with the ship's high speed, the Empire was huge and traveling was still a hassle.

After getting everything ready he started packing. Zhang Liu would be coming with him on the voyage as he was also someone that he could teleport to. On the off chance that something went wrong with the faction teleportation feature, he would go with the portal he had used all those years before.

“Take care.”

“I will.”

Without alerting their children and while keeping the fact that the Azure Emperor gave a decree to meet with Zhang Dong he boarded the ship.

‘I hope this goes well, why can’t I ever catch a break…’

Zhang Dong frowned as he thought his luck was abysmal. People in this world could live for a thousand years and everything that has happened to him didn’t even take ten. Now with new problems arising he wasn’t sure that he would have any more peaceful days ahead of him, not until he got rid of Wang Long.

Chapter 397

“Master, we will be arriving at the location in thirty minutes.”

Zhang Liu delivered the message to his master as he was glancing outside the window. After a moment of silence, Zhang Dong began to speak.

“Liu, if for some reason I don’t make it back, I’ll leave my family in your care.”

Liu was taken aback by his master’s words and he instantly started panicking.

“What do you mean master, of course, you will return and you will lead our sect to victory as you always do!”

The young man raised his fist and Zhang Dong could see that unreasonable amount of faith that Zhang Liu was putting into him. He would probably not get to him if he wanted to explain his system and that it was mostly just pure luck that he was alive at this moment of time.

It all started that fateful day in the secret ground. If he didn’t succumb to his own pride and inflated ego after gaining some strength that he didn’t work for they wouldn’t be here. His system went bonkers as he barely survived that encounter which in turn brought Wang Long over here.

If he managed to finish that test then he would have been able to live his life peacefully. Though he would be still quite ignorant to the real ways of this world. The cubes would have not been discovered and other disasters could have been triggered.

Now on the other hand the system bearer was Wang Long. The creator of this system and world was ignorant of his existence. The question now was if the watcher of this world would get involved if Wang Long went on a rampage.

‘I can’t really wait and see, god knows how many people would die before this character decided to show up.’

There was also the possibility of a world reset. The demon lord from the world his summoner friend was in almost went through it. If Wang Long caused a world upheaval the person watching this world could come to the decision of restarting it.

What that really meant was not something Zhang Dong knew but he was sure that the lives of his loved ones would be at stake. That was not something that he could allow, the problem was getting to a level above what this world was limited to. He saw it in that other world and he was lucky enough to come from one that had a higher ceiling.

Now with a new kind of cultivation, he was hoping to bust through that ceiling. When he did that he would probably not need to fear any of those overseers.

He had a little theory of why he was able to achieve this new breakthrough in power. One of the reasons was that he was able to increase the size of his soul which allowed him to fuel some of it. The other reason was his little expedition into the other worlds.

When tumbling through that connection through worlds he came in contact with some strange energies. These energies were purer than what he could see in this world or in the other. During his travels, he might have absorbed some of this energy which was now being focused in that white seed.

His body had been transformed through the years of cultivation as well as was his soul. It craved energy to grow stronger and even without him focusing on cultivation it would try to absorb ambient Qi from the area it was in. Some of that could have made it into his body and it had altered the cultivation he now had.

Now he only needed to foster and cultivate that seedling till it could sprout. What was inside this little seed was a mystery but it would certainly be something that put him above the nascent soul level, a new undiscovered cultivation realm.

“Don’t misunderstand me, Liu. I don’t intend to just lie down and die but you are the only person I can trust with this… I’d mention it to Qiang but he would never retreat from a fight.”

Zhang Liu wasn’t the strongest cultivator but he could trust him to follow his orders. Huo Qiang would probably go down faster in a fight than try to flee himself. His wife was already strong but she would also prioritize the children over fighting. That left a few other people that he wished to join them if push came to shove.

“Just follow the escape route that I prepared for you, at the safe house you’ll be able to survive for hundreds of years.”

The place that he prepared for his closest family was buried underground. After some testing, he was able to gather some samples from the wall that was blocking off the cube that he found under his sect.

He was then able to produce some small samples that would even block out his system. It wasn’t perfect but as long as the system user didn’t get too close, he would be unable to see anything.

The possibility of Wang Long flying around to look for things deep underground wasn’t that high. There they would be able to remain without the need to go outside for a very long time. Still, if the world was reset then his idea would only give his family some time before the unavoidable end.

For this reason, he had to go see the Azure Emperor. He needed some help, it was impossible for him to go around this giant empire to search for one man. Wang Long probably already had some kind of disguise that would make him hard to find.

The only thing he could look for would be the disappearance of young women. His counterpart would probably not be able to get over his sexual addiction so where there were beauties he would probably go there. This was also something that he wanted to bring up with the Emperor.

“But master…”

“No buts, I hope that you will follow your master’s wishes.”

Zhang Dong smiled at Zhang Liu who could only cup his fists together and bow. Luckily the master-disciple relationship was paramount here and he could trust Liu to honor his wishes. The young man was quite strong for his age, with time he would also be one of the most powerful cultivators in this whole empire. That is if he had enough time to spread his wings.

“Well then, let us not keep the Azure Emperor waiting. Tell the captain to remain on standby and not cross into the Long clan region under any circumstance!”

“Yes, master!”

When he was trapped and unable to teleport back into the ship, it would be unwise for his sect members to try to rescue him. Even with this large battleship, they wouldn’t make it far inside.

The ship’s large engines started to give out less of a hum as they started to power down. The flying ship that was cutting through the skies like a massive sword soon emerged. It descended and showed itself but was quickly halted.

“So those are the fabled Azure Gates? They sure like to build them big in this world…”

Before Zhang Dong stood a massive wall that stretched all the way up into the clouds. Even someone that was capable of flight would have a hard time getting over this barricade that was the entrance to the Long Clan’s lands.

The Long clan was more or less the equivalent of the royal line in this Empire. They would decide on every new Azure Emperor that would be trained to become the strongest cultivator here. With their superior techniques and cultivation materials, they were able to hold onto the crown for many millennia.

No one even remembered the time when someone other than a member of the Long clan was the Emperor. To them there would never come anyone close to the current Emperor, the two other large sects might change but the one leading the country would not.

“I will be off then…”

“Please be careful, master, we will remain here as you ordered!”

Zhang Dong nodded at his disciple while slowly rising up into the air. The walls that went up into the sky had strange depictions of some mythical beasts and dragons that were in a battle for dominance.

Now when he arrived there was a large gate. Below this gate was a whole bustling city filled with millions of people on this side and even more on the other. This was the border city through which he needed to get through first before he arrived at his true destination.

The massive ship that just appeared out of the clouds was sure to attract a lot of eyes. Even though this city was part of the Long Clan, the ship that Zhang Dong was able to produce with his sect was a marvel of engineering. The sight of the massive metal airship was something to behold and everyone down below could not avert their gazes from it.

‘That must be the welcoming committee.’

While the Argonaut started floating back to not scare the locals a group of cultivators approached him. There were five of them and they were all nascent soul cultivators of varying degrees of strength with the weakest being a middle stage one and the strongest at the late stage.

From the looks on their faces, they were a bit taken back by the large ship that emerged from the clouds. Zhang Dong made sure to use his technology to try to evade detection. This was not done out of malice, no.

He just wanted to see if the Azure Emperor troops would be able to detect his ship before it landed. Now he knew that their detection capabilities weren’t up to par with his sect’s technology which might boost his prestige during this coming debate.

There was no way of him knowing what they really wanted from him. Would they question him about Wang Long or would they just try to throw him into the dungeon if they deemed him too much of a threat?

“Honored Zhang Dong from the United Element’s Sect?”

“Yes, that's me.”

Zhang Dong nodded while clasping his hands. The five nascent soul elders looked at him with curiosity in their eyes. Even before they spoke out he noticed that they were trying to examine him with their spiritual sense.

Due to his strange cultivation realm now he would be hard to read. His aura was not of a nascent soul elder nor of a core formation master. It had changed since he entered this new transitional stage even if he allowed them to take a peek they would probably not be able to measure his true power.

They could only take his flying capabilities into consideration and think of him as a nascent soul master that was too strong for them to read.

“By the Emperor's decree we are to escort you to the Azure gates, there you will be escorted by the inner elders.”

‘Inner elders? I guess these guys are just some outer sect elders?’

This made him raise a brow as these people might have been weak for their cultivation realms but they were still very high for an outer sect elder.

“I will put myself in your hands then my fellow Daoists.”

He just nodded and followed without asking too many questions. This was also a good opportunity to see how the top clan in the empire operated, for now, they got some brownie points for being respectful.

‘I hope the inner clan elders will be just as cordial.’

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 398

‘So this is what the top of the Empire looks like?’

Zhang Dong looked up at the giant wall that even with his enhanced vision he couldn’t see the end off. It was truly immense, how long something like this took to build was probably astonishing.

The place that he would be entering supposedly survived the trials of time. The Long Clan that ruled this Azure Dragon Empire was apparently something that stuck with it through many millennia. They were the undisputed champions of the land now even more, after one of the large sects disappeared.

The Heavenly Crane Sect that was around the same prestige as the Soaring Dragon Sect was somewhat in a bind now. While previously the big three could not really act out against each other, now it was different.

Qing Long the Azure Emperor could now take over everything if he really wanted. With the Soaring Dragon Sect being gone the Long Clan could overpower the Heavenly Crane Sect. It would take some time but without a third party looming over their shoulders to strike when they were weakened, it was now possible to take the initiative.

But Zhang Dong’s elders informed him that this was not really how the Long clan operated. They gave their subjects a degree of freedom to fight it out with each other. They would probably sit back and watch from behind these walls till another Soaring Dragon Sect arose to fill in the gap.

There was far too much land to occupy by one faction. From Zhang Dong’s perspective, it was probably smarter to focus on a couple of high quality spots than to spread themselves out.

In this world, one nascent soul master could take out a full battalion of core formation cultivators. Only if they were in possession of some high quality battle formation that boosted their strength past this master would they stand a chance.

Even then, the master could easily flee and prolong the fight. Such battle formations took a lot of training and even one person falling behind could cease to be. Thus it was better to focus on quality over quantity.

The land he was on was still only the border town that divided the commoners and royal members of society. For the people living in this empire, it was an honor to go past those dragon gates. Some would even abandon their families if they could become a member of the Long clan, even being a retainer was enough for other kingdoms to fall.

“I’m not sure what you have heard about the Emperor but best you be on your best behavior, you will not speak unless spoken to, don’t meet the Emperor’s or his aid's eyes, I don’t think I need to explain to you what angering the Emperor could entail for your sect?”

While slowly floating towards the gate one of the elders from his escort started giving him ‘advice’ on how he should behave in front of his Emperor. It seemed like it was natural that Zhang Dong should be put in his place as he was just some random sect Patriarch from a rural area of the empire.

It didn’t seem like these people were seeing him as much of a threat for now. While the escort was composed of some strong nascent soul elders, they were clearly not the strongest fighters on their side. The most powerful man here was at the level of the nascent soul late stage elders that attacked his Sect.

The man called Tong would probably wipe the floor with all of them here and even Huo Qiang could take him with a slight boost from the faction system. This would be a good moment to let his aura spill to show them that they shouldn’t underestimate him but the smarter option was to do the opposite.

The more they underestimated him the more freedom he would be given, if they decided to spring a trap they would probably not prepare something lesser from which he could escape from.

“I will heed your advice fellow daoist but could you answer my question?”

The old man frowned a bit as he got interrupted by then nodded as they still had some time.

“Do you perchance know why the Azure Emperor has summoned me?”

The man just shook his head as he replied.

“No, The Azure Emperor has his reasons, those reasons are not for someone like me to know.”

Just as he expected the men here were just following orders and would be out of line if they actually asked for the reason. He could clearly tell that they were also perturbed by his appearance

Finally, they arrived at the giant gate that looked like it would require some titanic creatures to open it. But while he was stuck looking at the massive construction the people from the escort beckoned him to the side.

“Why did you stop, come this way.”

“Ah, we aren’t going through the gates?”

The group of elders looked at each other and then back at Zhang Dong before giving out a chuckle. They seemed to be some kind of inside joke but they still were cordial enough to not laugh out loud.

“The Heavenly Azure Dragon Gates are not for such trifle exchanges.”

The man answered while they descended down to the ground, there he found something that he was familiar with, a teleportation formation. Quickly it started making more sense to him, he was but a single man and opening this huge gate only happened when something like the Argonaut needed to pass through it, not a single Patriarch from a country Sect like him.

The group of elders looked quite smug after Zhang Dong’s comment. It was clear to him that after it they saw him as someone uneducated and that didn’t know his own worth.

“Please step into the teleportation array.”

They were even quite condescending while asking for him to stand in this teleportation formation. It was as if they thought that he was unaware of such formations. This might have been true to other Sects as even they mostly only had access to teleportation gates that were easier to manufacture.

Even he had to agree as the ones back home were all teleportation gates and he used his system’s features to go around the building process. This didn’t mean that he was not aware of the ways of constructing one of those. Now when he was able to see a working model he would be able to copy it over if the need ever arose.

To get things to move along they didn’t comment and remained docile. He was going into the belly of the beast so it was better to not antagonize the natives yet. Soon the formation lit up and his whole body was surrounded by a bright white glow. In a matter of seconds, his body vanished from the area with the elders that escorted him remaining.

“Was this person really the one that fought back that demon Wang Long?”

“If the rumors say… but he didn’t seem that powerful.”

They all looked at each other but soon flew away to monitor the large ship that was floating somewhere above in the clouds. Even though they were just making fun of the country bumpkin that arrived they were still baffled by the capabilities of that ship. This was the first time in a while that someone managed to sneak up on them.

As he vanished the elders that escorted him looked at each other with puzzled expressions and one started speaking out.

"Didn't that man look familiar?"

"Yes... could it be!"

*Bzzzzp*

After a bright flash of light, Zhang Dong found himself in another location. While a normal person would be disoriented he had his system map to help him out. With it, he could see that he was tossed into a quite far away location from the initial border town. The jump to his ship would still be possible as he was in the area on the map that belonged to the Azure Emperor.

The first thing that he noticed was the nice breeze at his new location. What he expected to see was some dark hidden chamber with nothing but stone. Instead, he was in something similar to a gazebo formed of blue azure dragons.

On the ground he was standing in he could see an intricate array formation that was even more complex than the one he came through. It was quite miniaturized and hard to understand, so without enough time to go through it he ordered Bob to take a snapshot for later use.

Later he could examine the lines in all intricacies but for now, he realized that he was being watched. He felt a presence of a person before him but his attention was still elsewhere as he noticed the splashing of waves behind him.

From what he could see he was in a summoning array that was placed on some tropical island. The weather was quite perfect and sunny. He could hear birds singing and the wind was gently moving the tree leaves around.

Soon he took a step forward and descended through a laid-out path. This path was composed of pure gold and it was clear that he was supposed to follow it to his destination.

While continuing forward he kept looking around. It was very hard to ascertain anything here, there were many strange contradicting energies everywhere. Powerful beasts loomed somewhere in the distance along with many strange trees filled with fruits that he had never seen before.

One of such trees drew his attention when he passed next to it. The fruits that it possessed looked like golden peaches and they radiated an odd holy aura. As a person poised in such energies he strayed from his path due to this opportunity. While he knew that it would be rude he just had to check this tree out.

It only took a couple of steps to arrive at this tree. Its trunk was radiating a strange presence while the unsuspecting golden fruits remained devoid of any Qi.

“Interesting…”

While he stopped staring at the tree he finally heard a voice call out to him. It was quite alluring and reminded him of his own wife.

“I would advise the dear guest from eating or touching the nirvana fruit, you will suffer a most gruesome of faiths if you do.”

Zhang Dong turned his head to see quite the voluptuous young beauty that looked more like an exotic dancer than a cultivator.

“I can’t?”

“This one will not stop the guest but please reconsider.”

Zhang Dong looked at the woman again and could see only a smile. In reality, he knew what eating this fruit would entail for any normal cultivator. Luckily for him, he was not an ordinary cultivator.

The only thing keeping him from eating this treasure was that it belonged to the Azure Emperor. The woman here didn’t say that he couldn’t eat it, so this was enough for him to quickly grab one and begin munching.

“Wait! You mustn't, the Emperor will be…!”

The woman’s eyes went wide as she noticed that her visitor didn’t understand her words fully.

“The Emperor? Hey, you did say that I could eat it, don’t bring him into this!”

Zhang Dong on the other side just gave out a burp as if nothing out of the ordinary happened.

“H-how...how can you still be alive after consuming the nirvana fruit!”

He just shrugged while looking at a second one that wasn’t far from it.

“Uh… is this a bad time to ask for a second one?”

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 399

The nirvana fruit was its name. Its taste was supposed to be one of the sweetest in the world but also one of the deadliest. If a person was to ingest this fruit without any preparation they would suffer a fast death. The moment the sweet nectar of the fruit reached their insides they would start to burn up.

To this day there were few people that could suffer through this fruit’s condensed Qi. It would instantly cause the person that consumed it to burst up in flames of bright light. There would be nothing left but white ashes that radiated an eerie divine glow.

For this reason, the woman that Zhang Dong met up with was close to collapsing. He had managed to devour the whole fruit without batting an eye.

“H-how could this be…”

“It’s a bit too sweet for my tastes but not that bad.”

Zhang Dong smacked his lips as he licked up the juices from his mouth. Even when he tried to consume it all, the fruit was a bit too juicy and some of it dribbled down to the grass below. The moment it did a massive white glow of light burst forth while leaving a zone of deathly white ash behind in its wake.

“Hey, are you alright? Would this be a bad time to ask for another one?”

Zhang Dong asked while looking up into the tree. There weren’t that many fruits left there as it was clearly something rather rare. While a normal person would probably die rather quickly from ingesting this pure holy energy, he was able to absorb all of it into this golden core.

This was truly a nascent soul treasure of the uppermost level, it was even closely approaching a level above it. It was hard for Zhang Dong to resist the temptation of ingesting a massive amount of holy energy like this. The woman clearly didn’t deny him the fruit so he decided to quickly gobble it up before she changed her mind.

“Huh, what? Another one? Stop this instance, put your hand down!”

Zhang Dong was about to reach out for another fruit while he had the chance. It would be somewhat impolite to eat another one when the woman said otherwise. There was also the thing with her tossing herself in front of the tree and pulling out her weapon to defend it.

“How could you desecrate the secret garden, spit out the fruit this instance!”

“Spit it out? But you said that I could have it?”

“I… I didn’t think you would eat it! Give it back!”

The woman had long black hair and looked like your everyday jade beauty, the only thing that was characteristic were her deep blue eyes and a strange golden gem in the middle of her forehead.

“I’m sorry but I don’t think you’d want the remains of the fruit after I’ve eaten it… how about you have this instead.”

The woman looked at a fruit that Zhang Dong pulled out from the spatial ring. While he had to clear out his spatial ring before arriving here he still came with some necessities that would be fine to smuggle into the inside of this clan.

“T-that’s just a regular peach! How can that replace the sacred Nirvana fruit?”

“Is it a regular peach? How about you look again…”

“What are you babbling about? It's clearly a normal … !”

Soon the peach that he pulled out started glowing with a golden sheen. Soon a similar aura to that of the fruit that Zhang Dong had eaten sipped into this regular peach. Something like this didn’t go unnoticed as more people started popping their heads from within this garden.

A group of ten beauties in similar dancer-like robes stood around him while he was holding a glowing peach. They were all pointing their spears at him and he was starting to think that he was transported into a certain Amazonian island.

“W-what did you do?”

“Nothing… I just gave the peach similar properties to that nirvana fruit. Regretfully it’s not as potent but should be fine for lesser cultivators to eat, the taste should be the same as well.”

After consuming the Nirvana peach he was able to analyze it. By infusing a somewhat ordinary spirit fruit that he got from his sect’s garden he was able to create a lesser version with his own power. It would not hold a candle to the original but could be mass-produced and would still give people quite the boost of holy energies.

“Catch.”

He threw the peach to the lady that was first to meet him. The woman dropped her own spear and almost fumbled in catching this new treasure. She quickly glanced at it and after analyzing it she was left speechless.

“T-this…”

Soon the other women gathered around that peach and started looking at it with much interest. After passing it around between themselves they came to some kind of consensus. They even started talking. One of them even proposed to take this fruit and him to the clan apothecary's for investigation.

“I wouldn’t want to interrupt your debate but wasn’t I supposed to meet the Azure Emperor?”

“He is right, we must fulfill our mission.”

From what he could tell all of these beauties were nascent soul cultivators of various levels. The one that he met first was the strongest while the others kept shadowing the two. It was clear that they were the backup if he decided to be rowdy.

While she looked to be in her early twenties Zhang Dong knew that he was looking at someone that was above the age of Feng Maling. It was unclear to him how the old woman was able to keep her youthful appearance but there were many ways that even he knew about.

One would be using a disguising technique like the one he taught Zhang Jin. Then the only way to measure a person’s true age would be their Qi that with age did change slightly. He on the other hand had his system that could pinpoint the ages of people he examined without much hassle.

“If you want more fruits, I could prepare more if you just supply me with peaches…”

The women looked at the strangely glowing fruit that they were handling and then went back to Zhang Dong who just smiled back at them. After absorbing the nirvana fruit his holy energies were already part of his cultivation.

When he used them up they would quickly regenerate after some rest, he could actually fashion far more of these treasures if they just let him eat more of those fruits.

It didn’t seem that he had the trust of these beauties as they pointed their spears at him. He just moved his hands up as if he was being aimed by guns and started walking.

Now with another escort, he was unable to wander anywhere to see the sights. Soon they left the forest and arrived at a beautiful gate. This one as all the rest was made from some kind of bluestone that radiated a strange aura.

Dragons and serpents were clearly the motives of this garden of Eden-like island. The place they arrived was a large villa and from within he could hear a gentle zither tune. Someone was playing a slow emotional melody. What was strange about this tune was how it had a limited range and with a little step back, he found himself unable to hear it.

‘Interesting, this must be some kind of sound-canceling formation, I wouldn’t be surprised if this island isn’t some kind of illusion.’

Zhang Dong looked up into the sky and found the sun’s glow a bit strange. If he compared it to where it was before he entered this place, there was a difference. From this, he could make the conclusion that this could be inside of some sort of treasure like the Dimensional Regalia through which he would have a harder time to escape.

‘The teleportation feature is still there…’

He glanced at his system window to see if he could still teleport out to the Argonaut. If nothing was grayed out it meant that he would be able to click it. The women that were guarding him could be considered the top experts of the empire but they were not his equal.

‘Let me see this Azure Emperor.’

Now after stepping through the threshold of this gate he felt an even more protective barrier. It was clear that they were taking their defenses quite seriously and that for the unsuspected cultivators acting out here would be quite deadly.

“Wait here.”

The group of amazonian jade beauties came to a full stop right after entering through the entrance to this beach resort villa. By how the gates looked a person would expect a giant castle behind it but instead it was a house made from bamboo. He could even hear some kind of stream flowing behind it and after spreading his senses there was also a hot spring.

‘Did I arrive at an old Japanese inn or something?’

They made him wait for a few minutes thanks to which he had some time to examine all of the formations in this place. His eyebrows started twitching as even his own place could not compare to this. Even for him, it would be quite hard to figure out a way to escape on foot.

The women were clearly only able to get in through some kind of trick. Either the formations were attuned to their Qi or they were in possession of something that acted like a key. Even if he managed to get it, he would probably not be able to use it.

“The Emperor will now see you.”

Zhang Dong nodded while he received the stink eye from all the women here. It was clear that they didn’t trust him but for some reason, this Azure Emperor didn’t seem that alarmed.

He expected to be padded down more thoroughly or be placed in some large room and be surrounded by a hundred guards before he got to talk with the big boss man. On the other hand, he found himself on some island resort that his grandparents would probably love to spend the rest of their life in.

“Please take off your shoes.”

After coming through the entrance he noticed another beauty sitting there. She had more of a mature look and made this look like an inn out of a Japanese anime. After going through it he wandered inside and the more he walked the more he realized that there was something not right here.

Finally, at the end, the doors were slid open by two beauties that were guarding the door. Inside he finally saw the Azure Emperor, his face was buried in a lap of another beauty that was tending to his years.

‘I sure hope this isn’t what I think it is…’

He gulped as he checked his system window, he was ready to lay an egg if he discovered that the person before him was another world traveler.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 400

Zhang Dong looked at his system window with narrowed eyes. The person that he was looking at had quite the blue hair that was similar to the color of the sky. He was enjoying a lap pillow from a stunning beauty that was somewhat unique when he compared her to the other women on this island.

She looked a bit more exotic, her skin tone was more natural than all the pale jade beauties that were on the island and her hair color was a ruby red. She even had a gem in the middle of her forehead that was of the same coloring.

Both she and the Azure Emperor luckily didn’t seem to have Japanese names. By what they were doing it made him think of the four heroes he met in the other world. They were clearly performing the fabled lap pillow ear cleaning combo that he had seen so many times in anime shows when he was still on earth.

Long Qing the Azure Emperor seemed to be quite relaxed as this woman that was called
Long Chunhua was tending to his ears. This was not something that he had tried with his own wife as he didn’t want to have Liena looking at the inside of his ears and digging for wax.

From the look at his place, he came to a conclusion, either this Azure Emperor really was another player or the whole Long Clan came to be thanks to a person like him. This option made more sense as he knew that people like him existed already.

With the appearance of Wang Long, it was also clear that the new players were quickly replaced. Probably when Wang Long died he would also cause someone else to come to replace him. How long the other person took to get here was unknown to him but he was more interested in the procedure that got them here.

He didn’t think that he replaced a person that was named Zhang Dong. This wouldn’t make sense as he went through a character builder and also decided on a name. His theory was that this system implanted some vague memories of him into some people.

His backstory was of a young man leaving the clan for over ten years to train up. Besides Zhang Jin and a few other family members, not many people had interacted with him. But with Zhang Jin’s word as the highest elder there, no one else could complain. He wouldn’t feel surprised that if he pressed the old man for specific things in his youth Zhang Jin would not be able to answer them.

“Dear, your guest has arrived.”

The woman was the one to look up to him. Her bewitching ruby eyes were hard to evade, if Zhang Dong was not a married man he would probably be instantly smitten by this woman’s gaze. It seemed that the Emperor had aimed high.

There was a certain lack of other female caretakers here. When he thought of someone like an Emperor an image of a large harem popped into his mind. It didn’t seem that there were any other women here besides this one and the ones outside seemed to only be part of the guards.

“Eh, already? Don’t they live at the end of the empire?”

“Yes dear but our new friend arrived a few days early~”

“Ah is that so…”

The Emperor that had his head turned towards the woman’s crotch finally flopped around to reveal his face. The moment Zhang Dong saw the Emperor he noticed the deep blue eyes that were a stark contrast to the wife's fiery set of pupils.

‘Is that him? He does somewhat look the part but…’

Zhang Dong looked at the man’s face and could see that he was very handsome. His eyebrows were quite sharp and the jawline was something that could be envied. But on the other hand, he looked kind of wishy-washy and sleepy, like he thought this was somewhat a bother.

While he was standing he also noticed some malice coming to him from behind. It had been a while since he had come face to face with something that outranked him. This was probably the only man in the empire that he should bow his head to but instead, he was standing upright and looking down at him.

The women guards that were standing behind him clearly didn’t like this fact and started moving towards him. They drew their spears and were about to point them at him but before they could utter the words ‘You dare’ the Empress looked at them. One look from here was enough to make these two guards back off, they lowered their heads and soon closed the room doors while removing themselves from it.

Now he was finally alone with these two people. It looked like the woman beside the Emperor had a lot of power. Her presence was undeniably fierce and her cultivation realm was just as high as the Emperor’s was.

While he had the time he continued to look around. From what he could tell there were no protective formations here to speak of. These two were probably perfectly confident in their own skills to defend themselves against any foul play.

The two were wearing somewhat more Japanese-style kimonos. The woman was somewhat more revealing than it was probably originally designed to be. Her legs were revealed and her ample cleavage was bouncing about even though she wasn’t moving too much.

If it wasn’t for Zhang Dong’s tranquil mind technique his eyes would probably be wondering about to inappropriate places. This could already cost him his head as he would be caught looking in a naughty fashion at the emperor’s wife.

Finally, the two parted and the young-looking Emperor stood up. While standing he was about the same height as Zhang Dong. It was a bit uncanny as the two men looked somewhat similar, while the man was down on the ground it went unnoticed but now when they were looking at each other, their similarities could be noticed.

The long hair, the sharp eyes, and the chiseled jaw, if he wanted he could probably pass for a cousin. It seemed that the Azure Emperor was also of the same mind as Zhang Dong. The moment their eyes met he started to examine his whole body.

His blue eyes glowed with powerful light as he tried to use his spiritual sense for a scan. He found this deed somewhat difficult as Zhang Dong was able to successfully deny the invasive treatment. While this could upset the Emperor he thought that he had enough freedom to assert himself here.

“Oh… very surprising indeed… you are also very young…”

The Emperor looked to his wife who was properly sitting to the side and looking at the whole scene. The woman had realized what her husband was doing and was also somewhat surprised.

“Oh my, this young man does look like the one we were looking for but dear, don’t you think you are being rude?”

“Ah yes, excuse me, what was it? Zheng Pong?”

“Zhang Dong dear.”

“Hah, I knew that, I was just testing you for my love!”

The man in question just stood there as the Emperor couldn’t recall his name. The two seemed like some kind of newly wedded couple as they continued to look at each other with loving gazes. This made him wonder if he and Liena ever acted like this in the presence of others.

While this would cause a regular cultivator to be alarmed to him it just made these two be more down to earth. He expected the strongest person in the Empire to be someone with a stick up his behind but instead, he felt more like a goofball.

“Come, my friend, this is not the place for this discussion!”

Zhang Dong wanted to clasp his hands to do a proper greeting but the man stopped him. With a snap of his finger, a different sliding door on the side opened up. Behind him was another sliding door which slid to the side right after and this phenomenon continued for a few seconds.

This was obviously not something simple, he that was versed in spatial formations could tell that this one was of a very high caliber. The Japanese-styled inn that this was supposed to be didn’t seem that large but this tunnel that formed went on for about a hundred meters.

The two didn’t elaborate too much as they got up and left towards the tunnel. Zhang Dong looked around him but didn’t find anyone urging him forward or to ask about what was happening.

The whole thing was already strange, they were treating him like some kind of friend that came over to play some checkers. The Azure Emperor was relaxed and the woman next to him just smiled without saying much either.

‘I sure hope this tunnel doesn’t bring me outside the teleportation range.’

The range was quite huge as he was able to get to his sect all the way from the other empire’s border. But if they traveled somewhere a bit further away than that, he would be stuck there with no way to escape.

Were the two leading him into some kind of dungeon for questioning? Was he in danger? The two didn’t feel that antagonistic and didn’t even care for proper decorum. It was strange that the guards were still outside and no offense was taken when he didn’t bow properly.

Still he took a step forward, his gut was telling him that he didn’t need to be afraid of this man here. The biggest question here was why they were leading him to.

The moment he stepped through the threshold of the first door he felt it. The dao of space was strong here and the area was clearly distorted. Even though this tunnel didn’t seem long, each step that he took could take him hundreds or thousands of kilometers in this direction.

For this reason, he brought up his system map to track his movement. Just as he had suspected as he continued to walk the map terrain started shifting dramatically. Even the system had trouble keeping track of him.

The people that walked in front of him seemed to disappear into the distance. Their bodies became distorted but this didn’t cause him to lose his cool. He knew well how these sorts of passages worked and just continued to walk at his own pace.

After what felt like an eternity he felt that he had gone past the space warping effect of this tunnel. He was really far from his initial starting point but still in the vicinity of the Azure Dragon Empire.

“Welcome my friend, you can’t believe how long we had waited for this very moment, with your arrival this Empire will be victorious in the coming war!”

“The what now?”

He heard the Azure Emperor’s words echo through this cavern and soon the lights went on. The chamber he was in was quite spacious and in the middle was a large holographic projection of the whole empire, it was suspiciously similar to the one that his clan members were using all those years before during the tower defense trials.

Soon it dawned on him what this could be and why the Azure Emperor had led him here. When thinking back to how these game-like worlds operated the answer was clear. It seemed that he had triggered a new event that would plunge him into another big mess.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 402

‘Very funny Bob, now change it back.’

‘Attempting request… request denied.’

‘The hell? Why can’t you change it back?’

‘User’s true identity is an integral part of the system, the user’s name can’t be changed after it has been updated to the true one.’

‘For the love of…’

Zhang Dong wanted to punch the person that designed this system even more now. It seemed that this was some kind of scripted event that was left for him. He had been the original system holder when he came here and probably due to this there had been no change in the grand scheme.

He was unsure about how Wang Long came into this. While spending many years in this realm he did read up on old cultivators that had ascended to other realms. They were all shrouded in mystery but were all probably players like him.

From what he could tell none of these players existed at the same time as the other. Only when one vanished for one reason or another would they be summoned. Here on the other hand there were two of them with two different backgrounds.

Wang Long was a member of the Soaring Dragon Sect so he was already born to power. Maybe due to this, he would not get a boost from the Azure Emperor. Zhang Dong on the other hand started off at a different level.

This could be something to level the playing fields implemented for when the war started. If he was really related to the Long Clan it could be on purpose. The system was giving him a chance to become the leader of the Empire.

Maybe in the original scenario, the Azure Emperor was supposed to die and he was to replace him. They also could have just become allies in the coming war and his true identity was there to help him get through it.

Being part of the Long Clan would allow him to partake in their resources and also gained him the protection of their strongest cultivators. It was probably a safety net that he could go back to if he ever needed to run.

He had thought about his past when he entered this world. He had rushed to the defense of the Zhang Clan which at that time was somewhat stupid. If he thought about everything in the grand scheme he would have been better off as a renegade cultivator.

With the help of this system, he could slay the clans that took his own apart and slowly grow stronger. Probably after he took care of them a sect would be waiting for him to conquer. There were other special locations with strong beasts and treasures that he could farm along the way as he got stronger.

The Zhang Clan that he had saved wasn’t anything special. It actually got him killed as he was forced by the Dark Palm sect to take part in that strange testing grounds. That place was created by someone that realized that the system was something else. Without that cube he found there he would have probably truly been dead.

This also caused Wang Long’s arrival. Probably because he hadn’t even been in this world for a year at that point in time, the administrators of these worlds didn’t see any reason to wait.

His mark on the world was small and he didn’t get any of the resources, it was as close to a new game as it could be. He wouldn’t find it strange that the email that Wang Long received only lacked the option that he had taken as the thirty-year-old cultivator.

His opponent clearly went with the easiest option that also made him younger. The last option was of an old powerful master of the nascent soul level. Probably all three of these options had unique circumstances that somehow led up to the war that was now in the making.

This cross empire war seemed like it would be the ending phase of this scenario. It was still happening a bit too soon in his opinion as not really that much time had passed since he entered this world.

If he counted the five years that he lost due to the time difference in the other world it would have been close to ten years. This didn’t seem like enough time to get ready for something like a whole enemy empire of cultivators.

But perhaps the initial rush wouldn’t really cause much harm to them and it would be a more contained battle. There could also be a reason for the scenario to be hastened and the words that the Azure Emperor mentioned alluded to it.

“Long Dong, I’m glad that you are with us, and judging by how you handled the nirvana fruit you will be an indispensable asset in this coming war! You could have not come any sooner, the bridges have become unstable without reason.”

“Unstable?”

“Yes, normally we should have had more time to prepare, we didn’t really have time to alert the citizens and other sects yet. I wanted to bring it up with the Heavenly Crane Sect and the Soaring Dragon Sect but then that Wang Long fellow went crazy!”

Long Qing gave out a sigh while Long Chunhua patted his back softly. It seemed that these two had a good relationship with each other. It also showed that the Azure Emperor was just a regular person that had trouble with handling the future of his nation.

As someone that had a large sect to maneuver he could relate. But this didn’t mean that he was fine with how this was turning out. While he could use this to his advantage he still wasn’t sure how much leverage this Azure Emperor would give him.

“I think our new friend is confused, we should give him some time, don’t you think so dear?”
“Is that so?”

Zhang Dong looked at the necklace that pointed him to be part of the Long clan. Before he could answer the question that the emperor posed, the light in this room went on.

“Young Lord, why didn’t you tell the council that you were bringing someone into this secret chamber?”

He looked to the side where he saw a trio of old cultivators. Two men and a woman of advanced age was standing there. Their robes were quite regal and at the same level as this Azure Emperor’s. It was clear that they were people in a high position just by the fact that they spoke up without the need of asking for permission.

“Ah, it’s just you Yingjie, don’t worry about the small things!”

The Emperor smiled widely and showed the old man a thumbs up. It was not something Zhang Dong expected to see from someone that was called the Azure Emperor. This man seemed too relaxed and laid back for someone in such a position.

‘Huo Qiang would probably like this guy… but those elders don’t look that happy about it.’

The old man that was at the front of this trio wasn’t amused. His beard was braided with a golden ring at the tip that looked like it cost a fortune to make. Even without his system, he could tell that it was worth a lot.

“Please my lord, listen to the Prime Chancellor Yingjie, this information isn’t to be taken lightly, we should place this man in solitary confinement and discuss this situation with the elder council!”

The old woman that was next to the Yingjie character spoke out while looking over to Zhang Dong. He didn’t like the sound of that, if they threw him into a prison cell he could be stuck for years without being able to leave. The cultivators were famously slow when it came to bureaucracy, it could take years before they come to some kind of conclusion.

“You wish to imprison my brother Dong? Can’t you see what he is holding in his hand?”

“His hand my lord?”

The three looked at the necklace and their eyes instantly went wide. It was already clear to him that no one that was of a different linage could hold this thing. After the blue flame surrounded his body and did nothing it was clear that he was part of the Long clan.

How this was possible was still a mystery to him. Could his grandfather be the responsible one, could he have managed to conquer a high noble lady from the Long Clan that then left a child there?

‘This is probably what happened… I wouldn't be surprised by that old fart's track record…’

“As you can see, he is one of us. I want Long Dong’s name to be written into our history books as he is my closest relative! He possesses royal blood just like me!”

The Azure Emperor raised his nose up into the air while pointing at Zhang Dong. The moment he heard the new name he wanted to slap his past self for being so immature.

“How could it be… he can hold the ancestral treasure? How could someone like him exist outside of the Clan?”

“What does it matter? With his help, we will be able to move the Azure Goliath! Now we do stand a chance against the other Empires!”

“The Azure Goliath?”

He perked up at the name, it was strange that this Azure Emperor was this happy to see him. With this name, he got the gist of why he was so ecstatic to meet him.

“T-the Ancestors Weapon?... Could we really activate it?”

All three of the old farts looked at Zhang Dong with question marks above their heads. It didn’t seem that they were buying whatever Long Qing was selling. He wasn’t sure about it either, how did they even know that he was part of their plan, to begin with.

Was there some kind of bloodline scan when he teleported in? It seemed that they were already aware of this before he arrived as he was invited to some strange pleasure resort with the Emperor already being here.

This was somewhat fishy and he could only attribute this to the scenario playing out from the background. There could have been some kind of event that triggered this that he was not aware of and it should not be Wang Long as he was the dark horse of this operation.

While the Long Clan would help protect him and his sect, that didn’t mean that Wang Long was an easy opponent. He had vanished for now and with the war being close, he would also be able to sneak into one of the other Empires to harvest spirit points. Before he became too powerful Zhang Dong needed to find him.

“We still need to discuss this with the other elders! The ancestral treasures aren’t toys to be played with, my Lord.”

“Bah, you’re no fun, let us throw a party for my blood brother, we will call it the Long Dong Festival and hold it every year!”

“Please don’t…”

Zhang Dong muttered while placing the necklace on the table. It seemed that he needed to gather some more information before going back home. The war and the role that he would play in it was something that he needed more intel on.

Chapter 403

‘Are you all right?’

‘Yes I’m fine but I think I will have to stay here a bit longer.’

‘Did something happen? Do you need help?’

‘No, I’ll inform everyone when I’m back, tell the elders that we will be holding a meeting, there will be a lot to explain. Please be careful, we never know when that Wang Long could show up.’

‘I will, please be careful and…’

‘Yes?’

‘The children miss you, try to be back as soon as you can…’

‘I will try, tell little Xiu that father will be back before she knows it.’

‘That child sure likes her father, she didn't throw tantrums like this before…’

While being stuck in the Long Clan Zhang Dong decided to call his lovely wife. Thanks to his system he was able to connect to people from his faction that he had a high devotion value with. His wife was one of the highest there and shared a maximum devotion rating along with his disciples.

After being brought over to that room with the empire’s map he was led outside. This place had no windows, the corridors were small and confusing, clearly made to confuse people that would try to enter it from the outside. If he didn’t have his system map he would have no idea where he was.

He was right in the center of this huge Azure Dragon Empire. If compared to the maps that he had access to he would be in the capital which was of course named the Azure Dragon City.

‘I think we are close to reaching our destination, I need to go now, take care of yourself and the kids.’

‘I will be sure to return my husband.’

‘I’ll try to make it before dinner.’

The two laughed for a moment but the stares from the three elders of the Long Clan brought him back to the current situation. The three started interjecting whenever the Azure Emperor tried to bring up some state secrets. It was clear that they didn’t trust him. If they attempted anything like a slave contract he would still need to get out of there in an instant.

Even though he was apparently a member of the royal family, this didn’t mean that he would be welcome with open arms. This could actually spark a war of succession if everyone wasn’t careful.

Zhang Dong knew that places like this had multiple factions. The war for the throne was an everlasting struggle with many people trying to get their foot in. Now he appeared out of the blue and apparently had a similarly strong bloodline as the Azure Emperor himself.

Some of the infighting factions could see this as a chance to dethrone the old leader while pushing him on the throne. He wouldn’t be surprised if some sleazy characters appeared and tried to get him on their side.

Then there was the more drastic option where the people close to the Azure Emperor could see him as some kind of upstart. This was the faction in power now, he didn’t really want to have any assassins being sent after him during the night.

To his surprise, he was led to another teleportation array. This one looked more traditional and was also in a closed chamber.

“Let us show my new brother our Long Clan, I’m sure this will be a sight that he will remember for all eternity.”

“A great plan my love.”

While they stood in the teleportation formation the Azure Emperor started talking. The three elders showed scowls the moment he mentioned showing the long clan. At first, he didn’t know what this was supposed to mean but after they teleported he realized.

They found themselves on a large elevator. It was surrounded by a blue glowing dome of energy that allowed him to see everything that was here.

‘Are we going up?’

He could see that they were moving up and as he started glancing around he noticed the lush lands everywhere. The spiritual energy was the highest he had ever been in, it was clear that this place was sitting on a large spirit vein.

With his enhanced vision he could see the large walls in the distance. Even though they were going up these walls were still blocking the view from every direction. On the ground, he could see various buildings and many people just going about their ways.

‘Huge… this city is much larger than anyone that I have visited.’

Zhang Dong had visited many wondrous cities in this world. They were all large with the population being much higher than any modern-day city that he had seen in his original world. This one was truly tremendous, he could barely see the end of it, and the life signatures of the people were felt by him from all directions.

‘Could this place have a hundred million people living in it… maybe more?’

“Bask in the glory of the Azure Dragon City, my brother! I can’t wait to show you to the rest of the Clan and to the citizens!”

“Show me to the clan… and also the city?”

“Yes, such a wondrous occasion as this doesn’t come around too often! Don’t you also think so my wife?”

“Indeed my love, brother Dong, needs to be inaugurated into the family properly otherwise the seniors might get rowdy.”

“Oh, you bring up a good point my wife, I thought that we should throw a big feast that will last for at least two weeks!”

Zhang Dong listened to the conversation that he was apparently not the part of. The three elders didn’t look very pleased about the Azure Emperor’s statements. He wasn’t surprised as he appeared from nowhere and now their leader was going to spend clan resources on some kind of feast.

“Ah no, I wouldn’t need to intrude on your Long Clan, I’m only an outsider I don’t think it is my place to…”

“An outsider? You are my brother, you are part of the Long Clan, Long Dong!”

While he wanted to distance himself from this strange Azure Emperor that was too friendly for his own good, it didn’t seem that he was willing to let him go without a fight. Then there was this strange treasure that they were talking about before, it apparently needed people with pure enough bloodlines to run.

This was probably the main reason why they were acting so cordially with him. This Goliath they mentioned probably needed co-operation between the two of them. Maybe slapping on a slave collar on him would cause the weapon to not work correctly.

Thankfully to this, he had gained some worth. Probably if he was able to move this thing his safety was guaranteed. On the other hand, now that he was forcefully taken to see some of the clan secrets, if he was unable to help them, he would become an eyesore. He wouldn’t find it strange if they tried to murder him on the spot if he failed to be useful.

‘Better if I don’t mention my family, they could try to take them as hostages…’

While the scenario was playing out in a good direction for him, he could not drop his guard. All of his closest family members were given special rings with teleportation features. He could not risk them being used against him but his enemies would not know that he was able to teleport to them with his system’s function. Even if they got captured he would be able to get to them, that is if he had enough spirit points to go around.

“Dear, I think brother Dong is still stunned by these events, I think we should give him some time to relax. I know, how about we invite his family members over?”

“My family members?”

“Brother Dong’s family?”

“Yes dear, I heard that he has a beautiful wife and two children.”

“She can not be more beautiful than you, my wife!”

“Oh, you~”

‘This vixen… is she planning something?’

Zhang Dong didn’t reply as the two continued their lovey-dovey routine. While the Azure Emperor seemed like a doofus she did her homework. She knew that he had a wife and children. Bringing them over here would be akin to holding them hostage and the best way to make him cooperate.

‘Is this her plan or is she just trying to be nice?’

There was also the option of him just overthinking things here. The woman could have just been someone friendly and just wanted to invite his wife for a talk. While Liena was strong, this woman was much stronger thus he wouldn’t feel comfortable leaving the two together. One bad move and everything could go south real quick.

When looking at the woman she just smiled like a little angel. If he didn’t know that outside appearance could be deceiving he would probably believe that this woman could do no wrong.

“My children don’t really like traveling that much. It will be better if they remain in my own sect, they are far too young for such events.”

He waves the proposition off and thankfully the Azure Emperor didn’t seem perturbed about his reply.

“Is that so? If brother Dong thinks so then it’s fine.”

The woman just nodded while glancing back at him with a smile. While the city landscape was breathtaking he was more concerned about where this lift was going. They were clearly traveling at a very high speed right into the clouds. They even passed a thick one that blocked out the city view.

Only after they passed through this fluffy white barrier could he see their true destination. Above in the sky there was a whole floating city that was slightly larger than Spirit Spring City.

“I see that you noticed it brother, this is the true Azure Dragon City and the district that our Long Clan lives in.”

This elevator was going straight up into the middle of this floating city. From this vantage point, he could just see a massive mountain underside. There were some smaller parts floating above and made it look like something ripped a part of the planet and it was now floating up in the sky.

‘So that’s the Long Clan base? Makes my little floating fortress look like a toy…’

The scale of this thing was something else. He could already see how the Azure Clan was able to survive this long. A flying fortress like this would be quite hard to conquer. If it could actually move while defending itself it would cause quite the headache for everyone.

Even a nascent soul cultivator would not be able to remain at an altitude like this for too long. This city was surrounded by some kind of energy bubble that probably also generated a comfortable living environment inside.

‘Wang Long still remains at large and a war is approaching… why can’t I ever get some rest for once?’

He gave out a sigh while they closed in on the city’s insides. It didn’t seem like the coming years would be easy...

Chapter 404

There it was before him, the elusive Long Clan. It was the center of the empire and even considered the empire itself. The moment the elevator reached the apex he arrived before a magnificent city.

The tremendous amount of spiritual energy that was just floating around was truly astonishing. Even back at his own sect he needed to harness the spirit vein directly and implement several spirit gathering formations to barely be close to this.

‘I bet that in the central part it will be even higher, no wonder they were able to stay in power for so long.’

A high ambient spiritual energy allowed people to naturally absorb it while they were young. This would widen the future bottlenecks for anyone living in such an environment. Thus it was quite an unfair advantage that couldn’t be easily passed.

‘So this is the Long Clan?’

Zhang Dong started looking around while the five people that were with them started advancing from this elevator platform. Around them was a wide-open area covered with grass and trees. It looked like a heavily tended garden with a nice path laid out with bricks leading to the outside.

The moment they arrived here he also noticed a large crowd around them. On the path laid out of bricks that seemed to be made from gold, there was a tunnel of core formation cultivators. They were all standing at attention while wearing some expensive-looking armor.

It was a sight to behold as the moment the Azure Emperor’s foot touched that brick road the soldiers raised their swords into the air. It looked like a picture from a game as a tunnel was formed from shiny weapons that probably cost as much as a whole small clan in the lower regions.

This kind of put everything in perspective. He had advanced quite a bit since the first time he entered this world as a core formation master. Probably if he had to face any one of these regular guards at this base level all those years ago he would be in for a hard battle.

“Come brother, I need to introduce you to the rest of our family!”

“Rest of the family?”

Long Qing nodded while urging Zhang Dong to move towards this path of soldiers. There were quite a few of them, it wasn’t odd for the lower clans and sects to not be taken seriously. There were enough guards in this park to eradicate anyone at the level of the old Zhang Clan.

While they were walking through this tunnel of swords Zhang Dong continued to spread his spiritual sense in all directions. He noticed that there were many people looking at them from the buildings around them. Some were waving and screaming the Azure Emperor’s name, others were already on the ground and bowing even without being anywhere near them.

The city in itself was somewhat more modern-looking than he expected. Large buildings made of stone and glass that were akin to skyscrapers from his world were spotted in the distance.

Around them were other various buildings that didn’t seem to belong to one theme. He spotted some that looked like grand churches while others were the regular large pagoda types that were seen everywhere. The city was somewhat random in its architecture without sticking to any single theme.

Then in the distance, he saw a large tower made of bright blue crystals. It stretched far into the sky and towered over all the other tall buildings. It looked like some kind of giant spear that was shoved into the ground by a titanic existence.

“That’s the Crystal tower of azure, the place where I live and your new home my brother!”

“My new home?”

Zhang Dong wanted to instantly refuse but for now, he was still just gathering information. At any moment in time, he could just teleport away to his ship that was waiting at the border. It didn’t seem that he was in any immediate danger, getting more intel was important.

Swaying Long Qing towards Wang Long was also on his agenda. He could not let that madman roam the land and absorb everyone's spirit points, the other player needed to be stopped.

This tower was closer to the edge of this floating city. He was unsure what it was made of but it had a similar color to spirit stones. At this point in time, he would not be surprised if it was actually a huge chunk of spirit energy as it was radiating a gigantic amount of energy.

From here he could tell that there were some formations in place that blocked most of that energy from seeping out. When removed it would probably cause widespread damage as there was a limit of how much spiritual energy each person could actually contain in their body.

The bodies of the cultivators in this empire caused them to absorb ambient energy from the surroundings. If the energy was too pure though it could cause a rather nasty affliction that would lead to death.

He could only speculate that the people here had grown accustomed to this high degree of spiritual energy. Their children would thus be fine living in this environment even though normal children's bodies would be unable to survive for too long.

“Yes, this is your new home and also your people, come my brother let us rejoice in our family reunion!”

While he was half a step behind the Azure Emperor the man moved over and hooked his arm around his shoulder. It was as if two drinking buddies were just walking together while others stared.

This was about at the same time as they stepped out from the tunnel of swords. He could instantly feel thousands of eyes on him. This was not surprising as he was walking hand in hand with the Azure Emperor, the leader of the whole empire. The people were clearly interested in who he was and why the emperor was acting so intimate with him.

There was of course an immediate roar from the citizens of this city. There were various cultivators floating around and keeping an eye out for anyone trying to get too close to the emperor. He could even see some people being shoved back as they were trying to rush to where the emperor and others were.

This painted a picture in his mind when he compared the city to other ones in the empire. The people looked happy and didn’t feel threatened even when rushing towards their leader. It was clear that they were led with compassion and not with an iron fist as most societies here operated.

At least that’s how it looked on the surface level. Zhang Dong was old enough to know that appearances could be deceiving and that on the inside there could be some murky business afoot.

‘He sure is a celebrity…’

The Azure Emperor smiled brightly and finally moved away from Zhang Dong. He floated up into the air with a big smile on his face. The people started cheering loudly the moment they saw him, in the distance, he spotted something that he thought only existed in his own city, a large holographic display.

On this display all of them were visible but the Azure Emperor was clearly the main character. From time to time they would zoom in on his wife and the elders but he was mostly ignored.

“Please Emperor, we must return to the azure tower with haste!”

The previously silent member of the three elders spoke out. It seemed that if they didn’t move this along the Azure Emperor would start a big speech to the people that were shouting. Zhang Dong could even hear some young maidens throwing marriage proposals at the city leader.

“The elders are right dear, our guest also looks overwhelmed with this display.”

“He is? Let us return home in haste then!”

While the Emperor seemed to ignore the elder that spoke up he instantly changed his mind when his wife spoke up. The Azure Emperor was quick to wave his hand to surround everyone with blue flames. From the outside, it looked like they were inside of a flaming ball but on the inside, it looked like a normal spirit barrier.

Zhang Dong took this chance to investigate this peculiar cultivation method. This was some variation of flames that was similar to his holy lightning. It had a somewhat divine aura to itself that was giving him good vibes.

‘This Long Qing is a bit odd but he doesn’t seem like a bad guy…’

In a few moments, all of them zoomed towards the azure tower. When they got closer he noticed that they were passing through several hidden barriers.

‘Scan those formations, Bob.’

He gave the order while looking around, the scan didn’t take that long and he was given a result that he expected. The formation worked similar to the treasure he was in contact with before, they investigated a person’s bloodline.

The closer they got to the tower the better looking the buildings became and the spirit energy increased. Even though the city looked like a happy unit, this barrier clearly segregated them into sections. He wouldn’t be surprised if the people with a purer bloodline looked down on the lesser ones.

Soon they finally arrived at the large tower that looked like a big chunk of blue spirit stone. At the base, there was a large yard made from shiny tiles and the welcoming committee was already waiting for them.

Most of the people there were wearing white robes but some had ones somewhat identical to what the Azure Emperor was wearing. There were three of them, two were young men and one beauty that could give her own Zhang Xue a run for her money in the jade beauty department.

At first, he wasn’t sure who they were, maybe his younger brothers and sister but after they opened up their mouths, it was clear.

“Welcome back father.”

One of the young men stepped forward to greet the Azure Emperor and his wife. The two looked somewhat similar but also the same age. Zheng Dong almost forgot how people aged in this world. It would be somewhat hard to tell which of them was the older one as both looked to be around twenty.

“You to mother, welcome back… and this is?”

While the family of four were having a nice moment they soon noticed him. It didn’t seem that they were that happy to see him as their faces were devoid of joy. From the looks of it, these young lords didn’t think much of him, this probably due to his strange cultivation level that was more similar to a core formation master than a nascent soul one.

“Don’t be rude, this is your long-lost uncle, Long Dong! Be sure to give him the respect that he deserves!”

The Azure Emperor’s words took the trio aback as they examined him some more. From what Zhang Dong could tell the elders of these ‘children’ was actually older than he was while the other two weren’t far behind.

‘They don’t look too happy about me being here, hope this goes well.’

While they did start, with their father around they somewhat lowered their heads with indignation in their eyes. Soon the tour of the Azure crystal tower commenced and he waited for the time to bring up the issue with Wang Long.

Chapter 405

“This is where the formation masters contemplate new improvements…and that’s the building where the Clan’s physicians take in the patients, I’m sure I don’t need to explain how much better our healing arts are compared to what you would find outside in the empire...”

“...is that so…”

Zhang Dong along with three people were walking through the main Long Clan compound. The three here were all the children of the Azure Emperor and were quite gifted for their age. Two young men and a beautiful lady that would make almost any man’s heart flutter.

After arriving at the Azure tower that looked like a giant phallic object going towards the heavens the Emperor had to leave. At first, it seemed that he would be getting a tour of the compound by the leader himself but the elders from the clan had other duties for him.

They started bickering between each other and only when the empress spoke up did the Emperor agree to tend to his duties first. Zhang Dong had already noticed that this dynamic between the Emperor and Empress was a bit one-sided. Whatever the lady said was taken to heart and he acted instantly.

It was probably her that he needed to look out for even though she was the weaker cultivator. Clearly, the pants in the relationship were worn by her and not the man that was enamored by her.

Thus while the Emperor was yanked away to tend to some things he was deposited into the arms of his children. The oldest prince was clearly not happy about him being there, his face could be easily read as he didn’t hide his disdain.

The second prince was a bit more mellow as he had a happier expression. He was also the one that was the most talkable out of the three. While going around he seemed quite proud in showing all the advances in this sect but Zhang Dong also noticed that his guide was talking down to him.

Clearly, he was not that welcome here and he didn’t fault the emperor’s kids for this. To them, he was only some random cultivator their father brought over. They had no reason to like him even if he was a part of the family. There were many other family members like him that were part of branch families.

He knew how these cultivators looked at status and he clearly didn’t have any in their eyes. As the leader of a small sect from the lower regions they probably were shocked by him being here and getting so much attention. Probably unless they saw some proof they wouldn’t believe that he had a pristine bloodline just like them.

“Our new friend doesn’t sound that interested in these structures, maybe we should show him something different brothers?”

This was true as he just continued to nod his head while giving out one-liners whenever they showed him the various clan structures. They were probably hoping for a big reaction from him after seeing the state-of-the-art facilities that they had here.

In reality, this wasn’t anything new to him as his own sect was on a similar level as this Long clan. In some cases, they were even ahead thanks to his knowledge and healing arts he considered the United Element’s Sects physicians and healing pills ahead of the curve.

The formations that he had the opportunity to glance over weren’t anything that he wasn’t familiar with. They did vary in some ways but not by that much to make his eyes pop out. Thus it made him look somewhat bored as there was nothing in particular that he was interested in.

But this also made the three children of the Azure Emperor somewhat upset. Thus the daughter spoke up while her face remained behind a semi-transparent veil.

“Maybe we could show him something more interesting, like the elite clan training ground?”

She chuckled while looking at her two brothers that quickly caught on to the meaning of those underlying words.

“Yes, our dear uncle Dong is probably tired of all these boring places!”

The younger of the two brothers nodded to the sister while the oldest brother agreed.

“You are both right, there is nothing better than some exercise to bring family members together!”

“Is that alright with you Uncle?”

The sister turned to him while smiling. For some reason, he was getting some bad vibes from this conversation as if he wasn’t in on the joke. He was in enemy territory and didn’t really want to offend anyone just yet. His system window was open at all times for a quick teleportation escape so for now he decided to wait and see.

“I don’t mind, lead the way if you wish.”

He was still someone that by proxy of the Azure Emperor would be considered a senior to these three. His decision of just nodding with a blank expression on his face could be taken in several ways but it seemed that these youngsters didn’t like him too much.

“Good, let us depart then dear uncle, father will probably be busy for a while before he joins us!”

They all soon departed towards a new destination. They were all being flown around on a large flying platform by another member from the clan that was not talking at all. After some time they arrived at the entrance of a giant building. From the outside, it looked similar to a closed-off stadium that was several times larger.

There were various people moving back and forth between the entrances. Some of them looked injured and somewhat worn down by this training. While heading in he started to somewhat realize why they wanted him to see this place. It seemed that they would be going through with a childish plan.

On the inside, there was a wide-open area that was sectioned into several smaller training grounds. It made the inside look like it was divided into many fields for various sports that people were engaged in.

‘There is a spatial formation in here.’

The whole building was bigger than your average football stadium from the outside but inside it was more than ten times as big. It was like a mini pocket dimension which allowed them to probably save a lot of space and also make the formation not as hard. It did certainly not compare in the slightest to his dimensional regalia.

Various shouts filled this large space and even without looking he could tell that people were doing combat training with each other. There were old and young cultivators exchanging pointers with each other in brutal combat.

It was just as violent as in any other clan. People would get their bones broken and teeth knocked out. With good healing pills, there was no problem in mending wounds that would normally take a body months to recover.

“Hey isn’t that young master Shen?”

“Yes, and he is together with fairy Yanyu and young master Fengge.”

Long Shen was the oldest of the bunch with Long Fengge being the youngest brother and Long Yanyu being the middle daughter. All of them were prominent names in this city and were shown proper respect the moment they entered this training ground. They were quite noticeable as behind them there was a group of guards, some at the nascent soul level.

At first, Zhang Dong thought that that would be it but after they bowed once it became quite noisy. Some of the women started shouting at the two young lords while the men pelted Long Yanyu with compliments.

“Please marry me fairy Yanyu!”

“Lord Shen, please look this way!”

“Young master Fengge, you look as stunning as ever!”

Were one of the lines that he heard as it became quite nosy. It was somewhat strange to be on the other end for once. Normally he was the person that was in the center of it, here though he was ignored and pushed out as a circle formed around the young lord trio.

If he could, he would take this opportunity to walk away. Due to how some of the guards were looking at him it was impossible. Even though the Emperor seemed to trust him, it was clear that his children and followers were more grounded.

He couldn’t fault them for thinking that this whole situation was bizarre because it was. If he wasn’t in possession of the system and knowledge of the other worlds he too would be confused about the whole thing.

“Please my friends calm down, today we have brought a friend from the far reaches of the empire.”

Long Fengge spoke up while looking to where Zhang Dong was standing. This caused the crowd to part way and bring the attention to him.

“A friend?”

The people started to look at him, Zhang Dong’s facial features were somehow similar to the Azure Emperor’s with the main difference being the hair color.

“Lord Fengge, this gentleman is?”

“Oh, how rude of me, let me introduce you to… um, what was it again?”

Fengge asked as if he didn’t find Zhang Dong’s name all that important. Who replied was his older sister that just giggled a bit.

“It was Long Dong, brother.”

When he heard his ‘true’ name being mentioned he wanted to cry. He could probably force his own sect members to stick to the old one but he probably wouldn’t be able to do the same here.

“Yes, uncle Long Dong has been invited by our father, we were trying to show him around. He hails from the lower regions so we hoped we could show him the might of our brothers and sisters, would someone be willing to demonstrate?”

The people started to look with interest at Zhang Dong but the moment the lower regions were mentioned they all somehow seemed dejected. He knew what was going on here as the other kids were trying to make him look bad.

It didn’t take much to bring the other cultivators that were here to demonstrate some techniques during a fight. All of them went over to one of the larger training spots that looked like a small arena. On it he was somewhat forced to sit through a few boring matches between core formation cultivators.

While the three youths sitting next to him probably thought that he would be surprised that their young warriors could fight like this. To him, this was child play as the people from his own sect were about at the same level as these youths here.

“Uncle, you don’t seem that interested in the fight, is something wrong”

While observing his mind did wonder about the troubles that he was facing. This didn’t go unnoticed as the three young masters were just waiting for something like this to happen.

“If uncle is bored, why doesn’t he demonstrate his techniques to the juniors?”

“That’s a great idea sister Yanyu!”

There it was, the bait that he was supposed to take. He now had two options of either going along with it, or just ignoring the cocky young masters but seem less in their eyes...

Chapter 406

“Please give me some pointers senior Dong.”

While the option to just deny the three young masters their fun was on the table, he decided to use this chance to test out this Long clan. Before he was blasted off to a different world he had sparred with the people of his own sect. He was somewhat curious if the people of his sect were on the level of the elites of this empire.

There was no better place to test this out than in the Long Clan. It was supposedly the strongest power in this empire. Depending on the results he would have a clear understanding of the power limit of regular cultivators.

The other empires would also be arriving, if he judged this by game standards he believed that the other empires would be a bit stronger than this one. Maybe not all but they needed enough strength to not make this fight too easy.

Of course, it couldn’t be too hard either, as the person that created this world probably wouldn’t want their player to just die at an advanced stage of the scenario. At least that was what he hoped, when he was dying the system apparently didn’t offer him any life-saving measures. Instead, he was somehow able to live through it after it was hacked.

“I can give you some pointers, but are you sure about this? What if you get injured in the process?”

Zhang Dong replied to the man that was standing on the other side of this smaller battle arena. It was similar to the one back home and the ground was made of sturdy slabs made from high quality stone. It was a type of stone that could somewhat absorb Qi attacks which allowed it to last through a lot of damage.

The three young masters that were the Azure Emperor’s children were trying to teach him a lesson. It was clear that they didn’t think much of him. This could probably be attributed to his lower perceived cultivation level as he was still just at the core formation realm.

The opponent that was chosen to go against him was a somewhat young-looking man at the age of forty. Zhang Dong did have to give it to him though as he was already at the great circle level of core formation. It would be hard to find someone equal to this man in the lower or middle regions that was in the same age bracket.

The trio was high up in a VIP booth as their types liked to frequent. He knew that there was probably a better way to go around this issue. If he brought it up with the Azure Emperor he might even give his kids a good trashing in his name. That wouldn’t fix the underlying problem of them thinking less of him, it would only fuel their pride and disdain.

“Don’t worry ‘senior’, we from the Long clan are known for our vigor!”

Zhang Dong clearly caught the mocking tone of the voice when the man called him a senior. This was truly the main dysfunction of these young master types. They couldn’t even fathom that he could be someone dangerous as they only looked at the surface level of who he was.

The only information given to them was that he was probably a core formation great circle cultivator from a small sect. They had the permission of the Emperor’s children so they also felt confident of them not getting reprimanded even if they hurt him. They probably also wanted to get in the good graces of these three young lords.

“If that is your wish, please don’t regret it later, you can come to me whenever you are ready.”

Zhang Dong just gave out a sigh while beckoning the man over. He didn’t hide his boredom and lack of interest which clearly made the man that he was up against somewhat mad. Before he charged out though he looked for confirmation to the three youngsters that were overlooking them. They just nodded without replying while probably hoping for a good show to unfold before them.

The man took a fighting stance with both fists closed. His body soon started glowing with blue flames that slowly encompassed his whole frame. It didn’t seem that he was taking any damage from these flames but the stone slabs they were standing on were sizzling under his feet.

‘Interesting, it's some kind of self-immolation skill, somewhat similar to what Huo Qiang uses but not as potent.’

The flames that were covering his opponent's body were giving out a certain unique radiance. It was clear to him that this was some kind of combined elemental dao. It combined divine energy with fire to produce this heavenly blue flame.

While it was interesting it was far below his own holy lightning energies that he could clad himself in. These flames would probably fare well against demonic cultivators. The evil energies would probably burn up before they reached the practitioner's body.

The man that he was going up against looked kind of smug the moment he activated this ability. This was followed by cheers from all the people around them.

“Senior brother is so good at controlling the Heavenly Azure flames, his bloodline must be very pure!”

Without asking for it he now realized that these blue flames were something akin to a linage ability. Things like this existed in this world as well, strange powers that could only be activated through the clan’s origins.

If there was any particularly strong ancestor with some heaven-defying skill he could pass it over to his family members. This skill would always be a bit weaker than what the original ancestor’s but it was something that was easily reproduced.

It was somewhat a free skill that each member of the family could easily use just by being related to the ancestor. The lineage varied by descendants and could be awakened by people that had little to no blood that was of the ancestor. It was somewhat random and also caused some stress in the clans as people that didn’t possess a strong bloodline ability were looked down on.

This point made him a bit curious, if he really was a member of this Long clan, shouldn’t he be able to utilize all of these linage techniques that the Azure Emperor had to offer. They would probably be all high tier manuals with the knowledge that could give him a chance to learn some new skills.

His opponent performed a somewhat flashy movement technique that made it look like his body turned to flames. It then reformed behind him while some of the flames kept rushing at him. The flames took the shape of a raging bull which reminded him of his hot-headed friend.

“I have you!”

The victory was assured as his opponent’s punch descended to the back of his head. The three young masters leaned in close as they wanted to enjoy watching Zhang Dong’s head get clobbered. But to their dismay, instead of connecting with the head of their uncle it passed right through it.

“What?”

The people that were watching from the outside were mostly unable to witness Zhang Dong’s fast movement. He just simply countered one movement technique with another that left an afterimage of himself behind. The moment the fist clad with blue flames connected with this afterimage it discharged a burst of electrical energy that went right through the defenses of this cultivator.

“GUAHAAHHA”

The man stopped in his tracks while lighting up like a Christmas tree. A jolt of bright golden light shot out of his eye sockets before a small explosion rocked the small arena. Almost instantly the man dropped down to the ground while his long locks turned to quite the large afro.

“Oh, was that a bit too much? You must excuse me, I did lower my cultivation level to fit yours but maybe I miscalculated on juniors actual strength, it seemed to be below my expectations.”

Zhang Dong chuckled while looking at his opponent that was turned to a smoking mess. The white robe that he was wearing turned black as the attack clearly penetrated through all of the defenses that he could muster.

“The Senior lost this easily…”

The people from the audience were shocked while the three young masters that were looking for afar were angry.

“This Zhang Dong isn’t that simple…”

Long Shen muttered to his brother and sister that nodded. All of them were prominent cultivators of great strength and already at the nascent soul level. It was only the early stage but at the age they were it made him into the strongest at their age bracket if they ignored Zhang Dong that was actually younger.

“That rascal, he was hiding his cultivation level.”

Said Long Yanyu while the other two nodded. They were not sure how strong Zhang Dong was now, but what he did was something above what a core formation cultivator should be able to do. It was at about the level of a half step nascent soul master.

“Is he hiding more? Maybe that’s why father…”

Long Fengge started talking while contemplating another plan. If the man turned out to be a formidable master then he would make them look like fools.

“No, he is just a country bumpkin from the lower regions, his sect isn’t even that known, we need to continue!”

The oldest interrupted as the discussion continued. Zhang Dong at this point in time was looking at the charred man before him. He could have just ignored him and let the Long Clan members tend to him but instead, he went with another approach. The stick was already given so why not give them the carrot now?

He leaned down to the passed-out person and gently poked his forehead with his index finger. The man's body gave out a radiant light which drew in the eyes of the people around here. All of them were somewhat inclined towards divine energies due to their bloodline skills thus they knew that this golden light was something similar.

"What is this divine radiance?"

They asked as the darkened body of the core formation junior was restored. The man instantly woke up and jumped up to his feet. He started to examine his body that was still filled up with this wonderful energy.

"M-my bottleneck... I can't feel it anymore... I... I must go cultivate!"

The young man quickly bowed his head before Zhang Dong and jumped to the side. There he went into the lotus position to quickly cultivate. This caused widespread curiosity from everyone around, they could feel that their brother had gained something as the radiance continued to enter his body and his cultivation level seemed to be expanding rapidly.

"..."

"I will be senior Long Dong's next opponent!"

"Wait... I should be the next one, please give me some pointers senior!"

"Get away, I'm going to be the first one!"

"Screw off, it's going to be me!"

Soon the people started to fight between themselves, Zhang Dong just smirked slightly as his plan had borne fruit even better than he had expected.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 407

‘They sure are quick to change their mind whenever there is something to gain for them…’

Zhang Dong wanted to shake his head at the group of cultivators before him. After they saw that he was somewhat able to aid in their cultivation growth they suddenly got more interested in what he had to offer.

The point of no return wasn’t quite there as before a full-blown fight could break out and an oppressive spiritual sense filled the area.

“Stop this shameful act this instant!”

A womanly voice echoed through the area as the young lady called out from the top. She and her brothers were still not convinced about what he was capable of. It was enough for her to raise her voice to make all of the people here back away. While they clearly were interested in Zhang Dong’s holy element capabilities they were unwilling to go against someone from the royal family, at least not just yet.

“It’s okay little Yanyu, your uncle doesn’t care, let them come, I’ll give them some pointers.”

Zhang Dong chuckled out loud while looking up at the young beauty. The moment he called her ‘little’ he could see a small twitch by her left eye. It was clear that she wasn’t fond of him too much but he still was the senior here.

“I could give you some pointers if you wish for it, you don’t have to be reserved, we are one big happy family are we not?”

After being led around the compound and looked down on he was also slowly starting to be fed up with how they were treating him. The danger of going up against these three was more towards their guards but those would probably not act against him that was getting the Emperor’s favor.

“You wish to give us pointers? Fine, this Long Fengge will be your opponent!”

While the young lady was somewhat taken back by the proposition, the youngest brother was quick to jump in. It was clear that he was maddened by the words, in his eyes Zhang Dong was some kind of swindler unworthy of the ground that they walked on.

The young man descended from the booth that the three were previously sitting on. All the other clan members quickly moved out of the way while bowing their heads. It was clear that these three young lords had the utmost respect from the people here.

“Why isn’t it Little Fengge? I'm sure this will be a good learning experience for the both of us, you can come at me when you are ready.”

Zhang Dong just smiled at the young man before him, he was playing the benevolent uncle that just meant well. He noticed a similar twitch in the young man’s eye, it was clear that Long Fengge wanted to do nothing else than wipe the smirk from Zhang Dong’s face while using his fists.

He took a good look at the young man. His hair was very long and his height was slightly above average. His face was quite handsome and he did look somewhat similar to the Azure Emperor. His father’s features were a bit more chiseled while this young man’s were a bit softer.

‘I wonder how Jun will look when he is his age…’

His son was quite young but was quite a cute-looking child. He hoped that he would develop into a handsome young man. The biggest problem here was if he would be able to reach that point as this whole war dilemma was giving Zhang Dong a headache. Then there was Wang Long that could be anywhere.

“Then ‘uncle’ I will begin!”

Long Fengge shouted out while surrounding his body with the same blue aura as his previous opponent. This was enough to pull Zhang Dong back to reality as he still had to show to these youths that they needed to give him some respect.

The technique was the same but it was of a different caliber than the previous one. He wasn’t sure of Long Fengge's motives but it seemed that the young man wanted to use a technique that he had already seen against him. It was an improved version of it, he probably intended to embarrass him if he wasn’t able to take this move that he had already witnessed.

This azure flame technique was somewhat denser this time around. It was clear to Zhang Dong that the nascent soul was adding to its strength and making it burn in a fierce deep blue. When he recalled the other man’s azure flames they were of a more pale coloring.

‘I guess depending on the color you can measure the proficiency in the flames. By the way, Bob, are you done with analyzing the flames?’

‘67% done with the analysis, more data needed for faster calculations.’

Zhang Dong looked at the angry young man that was shoving his palm into his face. Before it collided with his face he managed to dodge it to the side. The palm strike caused a massive shockwave that was also consumed by blue flames. If he didn’t have a tough shield made out of golden light around his body he would probably receive some damage.

“Hoh, those are some powerful strikes nephew!”

Thus to gather more information he decided to play around with this young man that was only an early stage nascent soul cultivator. His fighting prowess would be actually closer to a middle stage master but not like Zhang Dong wasn’t much stronger than that.

“Are the Azure flames ineffective?”

The people watched from the sides while trying not to be blown away by the shockwaves of spiritual energy. Now with the addition of nascent soul energy, the whole arena started to rumble slightly. This caused a defensive formation to be automatically triggered that surrounded the part where Zhang Dong and the young master was sparring.

Even though the Long Clan was a powerful entity, there weren’t that many nascent soul masters that exchanged blows in this place. This was a chance for the juniors to see real masters of the craft at work. Thus quite a crowd formed around the arena as everyone else that was sparring went right over.

There were even some people using recording devices. Such treasures were quite rare outside but at the Azure castle, there were some people that had them in their possession.

‘98%...99%...100%...’

‘Analysis of the azure flames done, presenting the interpretation to the user.’

Through his new Ai helper, Bob Zhang Dong was now able to inspect energy signatures in a more scientific way. Even though he didn’t possess the cultivation manual for this skill, he had enough of them to reference this data. With the help of his system, he would be able to create this technique through previous knowledge, at least to a certain point.

‘Not enough data to create a full complete Azure Flame manual.’

‘Not enough knowledge hm? Could you replace some of the divine energy parts with my holy energies?’

Zhang Dong’s Dao of the Holy was above the one that this azure flame was using. His knowledge of the flame dao was also up there but not as quiet as his heavenly lightning. But, he did have a crafting abode where he could mix other techniques with each other.

‘Do you wish to combine the Incomplete Azure Flame technique with previously established techniques? If so please choose the manuals you wish to mix.’

While before leaving his world he needed to physically enter his crafting abode, this wasn’t the case since Bob appeared in his life. This Ai companion was not an integral part of his system and worked like an app. His functions mixed with some of the ones in the crafting abode and now Zhang Dong could mix his techniques through him.

‘How about we mix in some of these…’

There were a couple of high level techniques that he could mix these flames with. The base would be this new Azure Flames technique while things like his immortal grade cultivation method would be mixed to heighten the grade of this new manual he was making.

‘Creating new technique, please wait a moment…’

“Why aren’t you fighting back?”

Long Fengge was at a loss for words as he continued to battle Zhang Dong that just dodged all of his attacks. He hoped to show off his improvements but instead, he was hitting nothing but air.

“Enough of this!”

Finally, he jumped back and the aura around him changed dramatically. The people that were watching gasped out loudly as they noticed that the young lord would be performing an attack that was only taught to the innermost clan members.

“Could that be the Heavenly Azure Palm of Eradication? Will the formation be able to last?”

The people that were here started to slowly inch away from the arena that the two masters were fighting with. Long Fengge was on one side and was already condensing his blue flames into his fist and it didn’t seem like he would be stopping. His older brother and sister didn’t seem to be doing anything to stop their younger brother.

“Heavenly Azure Palm of Eradication? How about I return the favor to you, my nephew?”

“What are you babbling about? Did you go crazy from fright?”

Fengge called out while also seeing Zhang Dong take out the same fighting stance as he did. The others were also confused as it seemed that the man was trying to produce the same technique but to their surprise, there were no blue flames that they were used to.

“Golden flames? What is that?”

They were all confused as instead of the divine azure flames Zhang Dong was manifesting something different. The flames turned into a bright golden hue and continued to move towards his fist.

“Get ready! Celestial Holy Palm of Obliteration!”

Zhang Dong shouted out the name of the attack that he totally didn’t just come up with to mock his opponent. The whole area went bright and a massive boom reverberated through the whole large training ground. The blast caused many backup formations to be brought up to shield the core formation juniors in the area.

People shouted in fright and the nascent soul bodyguards that were standing next to the young masters had to get involved. The exchange only took a moment but after the light subsided the winner of the exchange appeared before them.

Zhang Dong stood in the middle of the stage with his fist raised. Flames of a golden coloring were surrounding it while his opponent was nowhere to be seen.

“Ah, you must apologize to this uncle of yours… I might have used too much spiritual energy…”

Then everyone noticed poor Long Fengge or at least his bottom half. The young man’s clothes had been shredded during the exchange and his upper body was buried underground in a crater. Everyone had a clear view of his pale posterior that was now reflecting the golden light that Zhang Dong was giving out.

“Haha, well then, who will face this uncle next?”

Zhang Chuckled while looking up to the two remaining youths.

Chapter 408

“Let uncle help you to your feet.”

Zhang Dong reached towards Long Fengge’s ankle and yanked him out from the ground that he was stuck in. After their exchange, the young man was submerged under the now destroyed stone slabs that were supposed to last through almost any attack.

“Up you go!”

The moment the young man was pulled out there was a clear focus at a certain part. The young man’s robe had been blasted to nothingness by Zhang Dong’s golden flames. This then caused Long Fengge’s family jewels to be seen by everyone that was there.

“Ack… It’s Lord Fengge’s…”

“Why does it lack any hair… did those golden flames burn them off?”

The women cultivators that were now regaining themselves started screaming out. Their young masters' lower regions were fully exposed to them now.

“Y-you l-let him go this instant!”

Long Yanyu called out from the upper booth that had survived the blast. She was covering part of the face with her hand while looking down. Zhang Dong on the other hand just looked up at her with a big smile on his face. The person that he was holding flopped around like a ragdoll as he was tossed about by his ankle.

“There is nothing to be shy about, we are all family here, aren’t we?”

Zhang Dong could see that the situation was slowly spiraling in a certain direction. The two young masters jumped down and their bodyguards moved with them. From all sides, he could feel that people that were late stage and above were gathering. Even though he was having his fun, he still made this young master look bad.

Most of the time this would be a death sentence to an outsider but for now, he had a large shield protecting him, that shield was the Azure Emperor. He looked like him and the golden flames that were surrounding him were very similar to the Azure flames that these clan members used.

From what he discovered through his own prodding and with some help from Bob, these flames did require a bloodline. There was a certain pivotal component to using them, sort of a key code that was somehow integrated into his own body.

He could only attribute it to being some kind of DNA requirement that this body he was given possessed. When he clashed with the core formation clan member he had Bob analyze some of his blood during the healing process.

Then after comparing his body composition there were a few spots that were identical. He was truly related to these Long clan members. It wasn’t a soul bond as his inner shell belonged to him.

The only conclusion he could come to was that this world's scenario had been programmed in and the person that was Zhang Dong had been a secret Long Clan member from the start. With this information now cemented, he didn’t think that he should fear these people anymore.

Instead, he could use this world’s logic to further his goal of defeating Wang Long and getting to the root of it. Who was making these planets with these game-like systems? Why did they allow people to run loose with no supervision and what really happened when they transcended the scenario.

“You approach me with malice and disrespect in your hearts?”

Fengge was surrounded by a golden light as he was healed by Zhang Dong’s energies. The young man had a couple of fractures after the exchange but he was not in any danger of dying. The infusion of his healing arts that had been improved caused the knocked-out Fengge to awaken.

“What is…”

Before he realized what was going on he was tossed by Zhang Dong towards his brother and sister that were coming this way. It was clear that the two wanted to intervene in this situation but their behavior was less than stellar considering that they were supposedly in the presence of someone above them.

While in some cultures the offspring of the emperor or a king would be above anyone else of the royal family, this wasn’t true here. Him being part of the Long Clan was only one reason to respect him while his personal strength would be the main one.

Thus he decided to act as a properly angry senior that had been disrespected for once. The golden flames that were around his body surged in all directions. A bright golden inferno filled the entire stage as his oppressive aura ballooned to staggering proportions.

“Juniors, you dare dissect your uncle? Even after I graciously agreed to give you pointers?”

Most of the people that were still on their feet were forced down to the ground while the whole training ground rumbled. Even the guards that were at the late stage of the nascent soul were shoved down to their knees as Zhang Dong’s aura exploded.

The only person that was managing to keep a somewhat straight position was an expert that was at the great circle level. To Zhang Dong this was probably the main guard that was responsible for the trio’s wellbeing.

The three were forced down to their knees and had to avert their gaze from the radiant glow that Zhang Dong was giving out. Even though this should be the point where they apologized, instead they continued with being little brats.

“H-how dare someone like you…”

“G-guards what are you d-doing, apprehend that man!”

The oldest son and the sister shouted out in indignation. This was probably the first time where someone was exerting their authority over them. They were powerless to do anything by themselves which caused them to call out to their retainers. These people would probably listen to them over him as he was still an unfamiliar element in this whole Long Clan.

This clan had existed for many millennia, its power structure was unknown to him. He did not know how these people chose their next Azure Emperor. Probably one of the two youths here were brought up to take the position. To some, this would be enough to see them on the same level as the Emperor. They would push their way into their good graces at all costs.

From the oldest son of the emperor, a blue glint escaped. Some kind of strange seal appeared on his forehead and produced a blue shield that produced an image of a dragon’s head. It looked like the dragon swallowed up the three young masters but in reality, it was protecting them from his oppressive aura.

“But young master, the Azure Emperor stated that the guest should not be harmed…”

The man moved forward but still asked the question.

“That was before he blatantly attacked us, now carry out your orders!”

Long Shen shouted out while helping his confused brother up from the ground. The other nascent soul masters that were at the late stage also started to slowly get up from the ground. Even though Zhang Dong’s aura was immense, it could be canceled out if some effort was applied.

“Oh? You would attack this… Long Dong? Is this the renowned Long Clan hospitality?”

“That is…”

It was clear that these old martial artists didn’t want to have anything to do with this. They knew that their young masters could end this predicament with one head bow. Instead, they were being forced into a potentially deadly confrontation with a man that could be favored by the Azure Emperor.

“Are you really going to let this continue for longer?”

Zhang Dong found himself surrounded by a bunch of scary-looking cultivation uncles. While he was somewhat confident in his own strength, he wasn’t sure if he would be able to battle his way out if more people came.

The various formations that were in place here also gave his opponents an advantage that he wasn’t quite sure of yet. Thus he decided to play another card, calling out to the person that was watching this scene play itself out.

While others might have not realized it yet, he was well aware that somewhere the Azure Emperor was looking at them. He was also a father and he knew that no one would just leave their kids up to their own devices with an unknown element near them.

“Oh, I see that you have good senses, my brother!”

After a moment of silence, the voice of the Azure Emperor sounded through the whole training ground. Zhang Dong didn’t know where exactly he was hiding but he could feel some faint aura fluctuations around the area.

At first, he just thought it was the formations but after analyzing the Azure flames of his opponents, he realized that this was a cultivator hiding. The first possibility would be that it was another powerful bodyguard.

But he gave the fatherly Emperor the benefit of the doubt as he didn’t think he would let his kids just fight a yet unknown member of the family. During the exchange with the youngest son, he did finally spot the hidden Azure Emperor that leaked some of his power while probably ready to defend his son in a split second exchange.

“It’s fine, stand down.”

The Emperor appeared this time without his wife, the moment he was there the guards gave out sighs of relief while bowing.

“But father, that ruffian…”

“That ruffian is your uncle Yanyu, did you see it? Those radiant azure flames… no they were more similar to the celestial flames of legend!”

Zhang Dong’s aura subsided but there was apparently something that the emperor noticed about them. He did add ‘celestial’ to his punching technique but that was just a hastily put-together name with no deep meaning.

“Celestial flames? But father only the hidden ancestor… could it really be?”

“Um… hello?”

Everyone promptly ignored his call-outs as they began debating what had occurred at this very moment. He knew that his golden flames weren’t all that special but to these people, it seemed that there was more to it.

By the reaction of the young master trio, they were somewhat aware of these celestial flames. There could be secrets that only became clear to the innermost circle of this clan. It appeared that his little trick to garner attention had, in turn, worked to his favor. If he was taken as some reincarnation of the old ancestor, his status would probably rise even further, maybe even above the Azure Emperor himself.

“How could this person be related to the great ancestor?”

“You’re still talking like that? Go pay respect to your uncle or I will cut your allowance!”

“But father!”

The three kids started arguing with their father in front of everyone here. It was truly a strange sight to behold as they were not worried about hiding their emotions. The father was quick to smack the two sons around a bit for talking back to him. The daughter was the only sensible one as she didn’t raise her voice in the presence of her father.

“W-we apologize to senior uncle…”

Soon he had the three bowing before him while the Azure Emperor stood behind them with a raised fist. This apparently wasn’t the end of the journey as some more information was about to be revealed to him.

He had planned to use this dramatic fight to teleport away back home after having his pride trampled on. Now he decided to stick for a bit longer, maybe something that could get him through the hurdle that was this coming war and Wang Long waited for him inside this Long Clan.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 409

His first plan of acting like a benevolent senior had gone down the drain when the three young masters decided to send one to fight him. He then moved onto plan B where he would try acting offended.

When everything was said and done he wanted to teleport out as it would give him an excuse. Now he was going with plan C as apparently, he was now closely related to the ancestor that created this empire.

He did not think that this ancestor would wield golden flames like the ones that he had created to show off. From how things looked the ancestor should just have a deeper bluish color, how could he know that the ancestors ‘Azure Flames’ had a tint of gold. Soon he would discover how the golden flames played into all of this.

“There were two ancestors?”

“Yes, most of our clan members are unaware of this fact but the first emperor had a brother.”

“A brother?”

“That’s right, both of them were instrumental in establishing this empire, he went by the name of Aurulent Dragon.”

“Aurulent?”

Zhang Dong just kept repeating some of those talking points while he and Long Qing sat around in a new room. After the debacle with his three children, he produced the golden flames. These flames apparently were proof that he possessed some kind of offshoot bloodline that didn’t belong to their prime ancestor but his blood-related brother.

They have shifted into some kind of cript looking place with some murals on the walls. Even though he could tell that these walls were thousands of years old, the rocks were imbued with spiritual energy. The writings could be read and they depicted the last war in which the Azure Dragon empire was created.

Long Qing was more than happy to clue him in after the golden flames were manifested. This area also had some kind of defensive mechanism that would only allow the current Azure Emperor to wander unchecked. The only reason that he was apparently able to come in was because he was of the bloodline of the other ancestor.

Zhang Dong could not believe that such a coincidence could be even possible. Did that Aurulent Dragon person manage to sire some offspring before he died? Did they mix with the other Long Clan members or something? Then he was supposed to be someone with an extremely pure bloodline to manifest these golden flames?

This all sounded like a bad plotline in a novel. He had been turned into a chosen one that had no reason to exist. This was truly something that someone else could have come up with. The scenario was forcing this world to even react to the cultivation method that he chose all those years ago. Perhaps if he went with the purple flame variant the ancestor would have been the Dragon Pimp?

“Wait, so this ancestor sacrificed himself in the battle of the empires?”

“Regretfully so, the great Azure Dragon ancestor created this clan so that we would be prepared for the next war between the empires. The old text states that he was immensely worried that we would not be able to turn the tide without anyone to take his brother's mantle, but now you are here, victory is now assured!”

His new ‘brother’ was very enthusiastic about him being here. It was clear that he wholeheartedly believed in the old prophecies that the ancestors have left behind. Zhang Dong knew that those were probably all something the administrators of this world had put in place.

He wasn’t even sure if something like a great war between the empires even took place. This depended if the people that made these worlds could alter the memories of people living in them.

The only thing he could base a theory on was the Demon Lord from the other world that he faced. That one wanted to eradicate the whole population of the planet to start anew. IF that was the case then they probably couldn’t alter people’s minds that easily.

This was a big relief as he was worried that there could be a time where his own family could turn against him. It seemed that it was better to kill everyone to start anew, these administrators could have a lesser grasp on these worlds than he might have thought.

“Is there more detail on the war? Any battle records of the forces our ancestors faced?”

While walking and looking at the murals Zhang Dong decided to play along. He couldn’t totally trust the Azure Emperor just yet but he needed some help for the coming war.

“Most of them have been lost, I don’t know what or who will come through those bridges but I don’t think it will be a simple enemy…”

The Azure Emperor moved his head down while talking, it was clear that he had been worried about this coming war. Zhang Dong could relate as he knew how stressful the position of a leader was. So many lives depended on him, one wrong order could cause thousands of people to perish.

It was no wonder that he was so energetic when talking to his newfound brother. He was probably a person that from the Azure Emperor’s perspective could share the load with him. The second dragon had appeared to help him in the coming battle. By the logic of this world, this was a sign that the heavens were on this empire’s side.

Zhang Dong had the urge to give the Azure Emperor a pat on the back but he didn’t really know him that well yet. For the time being, he needed to use this chance to gain more strength, and what better way, than to ask for some treasures?

“Is this the crypt where the ancestors are resting?”

“Ah yes.”

Long Qing snapped out of it and pointed to two statues that were standing at the end of this huge area. The two were about ten meters tall and reached all the way up to the ceiling. They depicted two cultivators that had similar facial features and both of them had dragon engravings on their robes.

Below these statues were two large coffins that could probably fit at least three people into them. When he looked at them Zhang Dong noticed that one was a lot dustier. It was clear that the clean one had been used, probably opened up.

“Those are…”

“As you have noticed already, there are no bodies in these coffins, instead the legacies for both the Azure Emperor and his brother were hidden inside.”

“So, that one was the Azure ancestor… so this one it…”

“Yes, that one belongs to the Aurulent Dragon, just like the one I opened it will only react to a person that is a direct descendant.”

The legacy of the Azure Emperor was already pillaged from that coffin. Perhaps it was some kind of secret cultivation manual, or maybe some weapon that was placed there.

“After the current Azure Emperor’s death, the contents of the coffin will return to their resting place and wait for the new Azure Emperor to appear.”

Long Qing continued with a story that made this quite the peculiar treasure. He had never heard of ones that teleported back to the place they were found when their user perished. If he had time he would have liked to take this coffin home to examine its secrets. With his knack for crafting he might be able to create something similar for his own clan members.

“Now brother please, place your hand on the dragon symbol.”

Zhang Dong’s attention was brought over to a handprint. Around this handprint was a coiling dragon eating its own tail. The dragon was made from pure gold while the rest of the coffin consisted of some rare spirit minerals.

“Place my hand there…”

Long Qing nodded, his eyes were glistening with anticipation. It was funny as the Azure Emperor was a lot more interested in this coffin than Zhang Dong was. This probably was just a locking mechanism that would scan him.

“Bob, see if you can open this coffin up if there are some problems…”

He was convinced that this coffin was reserved for him when he was the original system owner. This system had gone through a few changes so it might reject him now. This would probably cause a lot of confusion and more problems if he would not be able to access the last part of the golden dragon legacy. It would also throw a wrench into his future plans.

‘I hope this isn’t some elaborate trap…’

Zhang Dong narrowed his eyes while looking at the coffin. He knew that there were some strange formations on it but they were above his expertise. This was truly something above the nascent soul level.

It was a bit late to run now. If he didn’t get the help of the Long Clan the coming war would be hard on his sect and children. This would have been too much of an elaborate setup to just trap him so he didn’t think the Azure Emperor was trying to pull a fast one on him. Thus he did place his hand on the marking and got ready for it.

“Hm…?”

Nothing happened so he looked back at Long Qing that was standing right next to him with a smile on his face.

“Oh, you need to activate your bloodline technique brother Dong.”

“Ah yes… I knew that, was only testing you, brother Qing...”

He turned towards his palm and slowly produced the golden flames that he created previously. His palm started glowing and soon the whole coffin produced a magnificent light.

“... connected to old system lock... “

“... error … unable to produce key…”

“... please wait, attempting to recreate the key from old code…”

Bob started talking to him while he was trying to act naturally. The glowing symbols on the coffin started shining brightly but the moment he wasn’t able to produce the ‘key’ the glow started to die down.

The moment it did he could hear the Azure Emperor behind him gasping out in shock. This was probably an indication that he had failed in opening the lock. Luckily for him, his Ai program didn’t let him down this time around and the bright glow returned.

“...a copy of the key has been recovered, uploading data…”

The whole room started to shine brightly and the statue that was above the coffin began to move. It started to open up its eyes while its head moved down to look at him. A bright ray of light descended on him soon after as he felt strong spiritual energy seeping into him.

The golden core that he had created while reaching his new realm started reacting. This light was a surge of very pure holy energy which also carried some kind of hidden technique. Through Bob, he was able to receive it while also managing to increase his cultivation by a small step forward.

Soon the radiant glow subsided while he leaned back from the coffin. When he did a few clicking sounds caught his ear, the closed treasure chest was opening up to reveal its contents to him...

Chapter 410

“A book and a rusty sword?”

Zhang Dong looked inside of the old coffin that was mostly empty. In it, he could see a somewhat rusted sword that might have been some kind of powerful weapon but had degraded over time. Next to it was a really old book that looked like it could crumble at any moment.

“These items… I’m not sure they are usable anymore…”

He looked back to the man that was with him, Long Qing his supposed brother was looking over his shoulder.

“The second ancestor tomb has never been touched before… I thought it would preserve the treasures inside…”

The answer seemed to be obvious, the heritage for the Azure Dragon part had been taken out many thousands of years before, thus it had survived and conserved all these years. The ones for the golden dragon on the other hand were not.

Even then he decided to give the book and sword a scan with the help of his system, maybe there was still something that he could gain from this.

Celestial Sword of the Ancient Dragon [ Degraded] | Heaven middle grade

Probably before it was placed into this coffin the sword was somewhat usable but it couldn’t fight against the passage of time. Even heaven grade weapons didn’t last forever and need to be reforged or repaired from time to time.

“Maybe I can reforge it to something good…”

Even though it was rusty, it was still a heaven grade weapon. The materials that it was made from were still rare, with his crafting expertise he might be able to fashion a new sword. He just needed to use it as the core for the new weapon.

“Oh, are you perhaps a talented blacksmith my brother?”

“Ah, I guess I know a thing or two about these, I might be able to strip this sword for parts and reshape it to its former glory, but I won’t know until I take it to my forge.”

If this weapon could be built up again depended on what it was made of on the inside. Powerful weapons in this world tended to have their own cores while the metals around it were more of a shell.

The core mineral inside would produce a powerful Qi radiance that would keep the metals intact during combat. Only when these invisible barriers were shattered would the weapon break. Thus even when a blade from a sword like this broke, if the core inside remained undamaged it could be remade.

“Your forge? Why don’t you use our Long Clan forge instead? I bet you’ll find everything you need there!”

“You have a forge?”

“Of course we do! Blacksmithing, pill making, formation creation, there is nothing that our Long Clan doesn’t excel at, we have vast quantities of knowledge in our grand library, as the ancestors' descendant you will naturally have access to it all!”

This actually sounded quite interesting as he could always use more knowledge. He was still mostly depending on the things he had gained from that expedition all those years ago. With the help of this Long Clan, he would probably be able to fill some of the holes in his knowledge, maybe even gain some resources for his current cultivation.

What he needed to do was to gain more strength and knowledge for the coming days. His biggest enemy Wang Long at this very moment could be killing some unsuspecting villagers or beasts for more spirit points.

With the help of the system shop that he had, he had access to many immortal grade techniques. The only edge that Zhang Dong had over his opponent was that he mostly specialized in certain things.

When he fought against Wang Long the man seemed to use various random techniques that he probably didn’t put much thought into buying. Probably the only thing that person was interested in was if the skill or technique was high level enough.

He didn’t worry if it meshed well with his current cultivation nor did he train himself in these techniques. This was something even his old system failed at, teaching him how to properly use the techniques he bought.

For that he needed to slowly train them and only with time would they reach the next level. A lower ranked technique could overtake a higher ranked one if it was trained to perfection with ease. He did not think Wang Long would bother with something like that and he wouldn’t have enough time at this point.

Even though both of them had been here for a while, Zhang Dong used some time to train himself. He and Huo Qiang sparred quite a lot. The other elders that were at the nascent soul level were also forced to participate so that he could progress further.

“How about the cultivation manuals, can I see those?”

“Why wouldn’t you? Your authority is not less than my own, you have been accepted as the honorable ancestor's descendant, I am the Azure Dragon and you are the Aurulent Dragon!”

“Aurulent?... how about we just go with Golden instead?”

“If you so wish but first we need to get the elders approval, those old farts can be fussy about things like that.”

While the emperor was making it out to be somewhat simple, he wasn’t so sure about it. Zhang Dong didn’t believe that there wouldn’t be some pushback against him becoming some kind of Golden Dragon descendant. This put the whole Azure Emperor in a tough spot as there was someone at the same level as him, at least in theory.

Normally there would be some kind of war for succession as there was no way for two kings to coexist with each other. Long Qing seemed a bit too nonchalant about it, it was as if he didn’t really care but this could also just have been an act.

With the looming war over their heads, he could have just been acting friendly as he still needed the Golden Dragon’s power. This something had probably something to do with that Goliath thing they previously mentioned. It might have been some superweapon that required both of them to use it.

Zhang Dong wouldn’t be surprised that at the end of this war, this Long Qing could turn out to have been the real villain from the start. Maybe that was how the previous Golden Dragon died, killed by his own brother after the war was won.

“Yes, that makes sense.”

He nodded while placing the sword that was in his hand into his spatial ring. What now remained was the old-looking book that was still in the coffin. While it was still holding out, he wasn’t sure if the pages wouldn’t crumble to dust if he tried opening it up.

Luckily Zhang Dong was still in possession of his system and scanning books was something that he was good at. Thus he gently placed his index finger on the book with applying a minimal amount of pressure to initiate the scanning function.

Divine Celestial Dragon Manual | Immortal Grade Middle

His system was quick to examine the book and just as he had thought the pages started to turn to dust almost at the exact moment when he interacted with this book. This manual was probably not really meant for anyone to read, only someone with a system’s scanning feature would be able to gain its knowledge.

‘Interesting… it describes the golden flames in more detail… it also has various other techniques that implement those golden flames…’

The old book was quite thick and there was a lot of knowledge in it. The bloodline technique that he created previously was of a lesser grade than this one. This manual would be a great addition to his current holy cultivation method, maybe with its help, he could even go further than before.

‘Celestial huh? Got me hoping that it was above the immortal grade…’

“No… the sacred text from the ancestor… now we will never know…”

Long Qing shouted out in horror as he saw the manual crumbling into dust after Zhang Dong poked it with his finger. It was clear that even though this man acted a bit goofy, he was still a cultivator at heart. Seeing a precious cultivation resource just vanish into thin air was not something that he could even bear.

“Oh, it’s fine… I uh… I heard the voice of the ancestor, I think he had blessed me with a vision of this manual…”

While he didn’t really need to mention the fact that he had received the ancestor's treasure, the fact that it was in his brain could keep him safe. Even if the others betrayed him, they would probably try to get the information out of him first which could later give him an opportunity to escape.

“You did? But how… I don’t ever remember my ancestors ever reaching out to me like that…”

“Uh… maybe it was some kind of safety for when the manual was too damaged to be of use?”

Long Qing pondered this question while Zhang Dong tried to go over the manual in his head. Thanks to it being scanned with his system he was able to go through it much faster than by just reading it manually.

“Oh… are those… they seem more radiant than before…”

He decided to show off by manifesting a tiny golden flame orb in front of his index finger. These flames were a lot purer than the ones he previously produced and they had a kind of buffing function.

“This feels rather refreshing!”

Long Qing felt energy rushing into his body when standing in front of this golden light. Zhang Dong could also feel it, this technique seemed similar to the divine spells in the other world he was in. This was quite well suited for large-scale battles if he could buff his side by just giving off some of his aura.

‘Hm, maybe the Golden Dragon was the healer while the Azure Dragon was the attacker?’

As he looked through this Celestial Dragon manual he noticed that most of these techniques that were described in it were used to aid others. Other ones were meant for dispelling demonic corruption and battling evil energies.

‘This will be useful against Wang Long for sure…’

With a new manual in his brain and a potential new strong weapon in his spatial ring, Zhang Dong felt like this was a useful journey. Now, what remained was to gain even more by using the resources that this clan could offer him. If what the Azure Emperor was telling him, the other elders would not have the right to stop him, even if he went slightly overboard…

“Well then my brother… you said that you have a big library… could you show it to me?”

Chapter 411

“What is he doing?”

“Shhh be quiet, what if they hear you? You want to be sent to the lower regions or something?”

“I know… but what is he doing now?”

“I don’t know…”

The two people from the apothecary faction of the clan were looking at what was a new face in the Long Clan. He went by the name Zhang Dong or Long Dong and at this very moment, he was sticking his finger into a life-giving elixir.

They had never seen a method of examination like this. What healing experts would normally do was to scan the contents of the elixir bottle with their spiritual sense. This madman on the other hand went around sticking his digits into the high quality elixirs for some reason.

This wasn’t the first section of the clan that he had visited. There were many other clan members standing outside of the apothecary building talking with each other.

“He went through the entire library just poking the books with his finger and running around like a madman!”

“At least he wasn’t interested in the beast tamer faction… but he did pat down all the formation scrolls…”

“Oh, be quiet, he is walking out…”

Zhang Dong left the apothecary guild that was responsible for keeping all the medicine and pill formulae. Some of the elixirs were made by specific masters that had their own secrets but with a little poke, he was able to scan for the ingredients that they were made. When comparing it to his vast library of knowledge he was able to deduct the manufacturing method almost perfectly.

‘Formations, pills, blacksmithing… I think I got all the major ones, what is left is…’

With his current level, he was able to scan everything really fast, he had gone through the library to gather all the hiqh quality martial arts manuals. What was left now were a few monuments that implemented knowledge in a slightly different way.

After going through these pockets of great knowledge he was able to gather many heaven grade manuals. A handful of half-step immortal manuals were also kept hidden away at some places that he now had access to. This trip had really been very fruitful and he continued towards the next destination while munching on something.

“Wait… what is that man-eating… could that be?”

He ignored the chatting people while devouring a piece of fruit packed with divine energy. This was the same fruit that he had eaten previously, now on the other hand he was handed them all by the clan. Thanks to being the Golden Dragon’s ancestor's true descendant he would be naturally given everything that concerned holy power.

Regretfully almost every technique, formation, or secret art related to that ancestor had been lost to time. Mostly what he could find were some lesser copies that some other branch families tried to hold on to. But with the help of the manual from the crypt, he could somewhat upgrade these lesser techniques if he wished to.

“Bring me to the ancestral pillar!”

“Yes, my lord!”

Zhang Dong gave out an order to a person he was lent by the Azure Emperor. The man was the guide that explained every important part of this clan to him. Where he was going now was a secret place that only the members of the Azure Dragon line had access to.

He was already in the giant blue crystal tower that overlooked this floating city. Probably if the Golden Dragon ancestor survived past the wall, there would have been a golden tower next to it. Luckily the place they were heading to had some old knowledge that survived from the past war.

“So this is it, an interesting way to preserve their techniques…”

The area where he was was large and the ceiling was quite high. The most characteristic thing about this place were the many various pillars. Some were square, some were oval while others were just large boulders that didn’t even reach up into the ceiling.

At first, he wasn’t sure what to make of this place. After further examining, he noticed that there were various clan members meditating in front of these large pillars. Each and every one of these rocky structures was scratched up by something. When he got closer he realized that these were no simple scratches, no they were sword strikes.

Each pillar told a different story as it was carved up by various sword techniques and dances. This was a very archaic way of preserving swordsmanship through the ages. Instead of books, they would use hard stone slabs into which they would etch the knowledge with their weapons.

This was a somewhat difficult way of learning the proper sword stances but there was a certain perk of doing it like this. Each sword strike that caused a gash on the rock would carry some of the sword master’s sword intent.

Through looking at those sliced-up pillars the student needed to piece the art together and interpret it for themselves. This gave various effects and produced many versions of the skills.

“While it looks somewhat inconsistent it does preserve it better than old texts.”

He had the pleasure of watching an immortal manual crumble into dust before him. Thanks to this way of preserving knowledge the sword strikes managed to survive tens of thousands of years.

‘But this is a problem… I can’t absorb this into my library….’

Even though Zhang Dong gave one of the pillars a poke he wasn’t able to just analyze it. There weren’t any words here that he could copy and the sword intent was only part of the puzzle. He would somehow need to recreate the movement of the person that performed the sword technique to piece everything together.

While thinking about what to do he noticed a certain young man. He had seen him before as he was Long Shen the oldest brother and son of the Azure Emperor.

“I see that you are keeping up with your studies little Shen.”

“...Little?”

The young man was performing some kind of sword dance before the center pillar of this chamber. Around him were various other students and children of other various powerful elders that hailed from the Long Clan.

Zhang Dong appeared right next to him which caused the young man to fumble during the dance. The technique that he was performing utilized quite a bit of spiritual energy so ending it prematurely caused his sword to fly into the distance.

“You should be careful with that nephew, I’m not sure you should be damaging ancient clan pillars like that…”

The sword flew off and embedded itself in one of the other pillars and caused everyone to look this way.

“That was because you…”

Before continuing Long Shen realized who it was. Even though Zhang Dong wasn’t liked he could see that the young man had learned his lesson. At least that's what it looked like on the surface but he could tell that he was not someone that was liked.

“Please, I’m in the middle of my training, why are you here uncle?”

“Oh, I’m just looking around, what are you trying to perform, a dance?”

“The Heavenly Azure Swordsmanship is not a dance!”

He sounded offended when Zhang Dong called his technique a mere dance. Shen was quick to turn around and resume his training, it seemed that he would rather ignore him now than continue the interaction. Thanks to this Zhang Dong got a good idea of how to try his system's new AI feature.

‘Bob, can you compare this Shen fellows sword dance to the cuts on this large pillar… could you also perhaps produce a holographic image?’

‘Initiating holographic projection…’

While he was in the other world and cultivating his soul he had some time to play around with his new AI partner. His function to automatically use the crafting abode to upgrade skills was only one of them.

While Long Shen continued his dance Bob started scanning his movements along with the sword gashes in the large pillar. With the combined input the helper app was able to piece together the technique that he was performing.

‘Sword technique detected, incomplete…’

While the young man seemed competent and was already a nascent soul master, it seemed that he wasn’t able to fully paste together the sword dance that was in this pillar. This was only natural as most people wouldn’t even be able to properly make one good move out of these pillar scratches.

‘Can you put together the full technique for me?’

Bob went to work as he scanned the pillar for the right technique. As this continued Zhang Dong discovered that there were various other sword strikes and skills embedded in this one pillar, some of them were quite hard to see as they overlapped with other sword strikes.

“Why is he just standing there like that…”

“I don’t know…”

The other students that were there were curious about this new person that even Long Shen needed to abide by. For some time he remained stationary while just looking up at the pillar filled with knowledge.

They didn’t know that the person was pasting together a long-lost art and was doing it at an alarming pace.

‘That took a while… that’s a bit of movement but it's also a half-step immortal level technique… should I try it out?’

This was no book so reading this type of monolith wasn’t easy. After about an hour he was finally done and would probably be able to do the same with the other pillars at a faster pace.

“What is he doing now? He took out a sword? Is he going to perform a sword dance?”

One of the clan members asked while finding Zhang Dong’s stance very similar to the one that Long Shen had. When the Azure Emperor’s son saw what his uncle was doing he instantly stopped with his training. From his standpoint, there was no way of Zhang Dong being able to perform the correct set of movements only after glancing at the stone pillar for an hour. He was ready to mock his uncle after he failed but then he noticed something that he didn’t expect.

“T-those movements… is that really the same sword dance the young lord was studying?”

“It looks somewhat different and the movements are sharper…”

An aura of golden flames washed over Zhang Dong’s body as he performed a few movements of this new sword art. This was nothing simple as it was the first technique that he was trying to perform that actually went over the nascent soul limit.

Sweat formed on his brow and his hands felt heavy. The amount of spiritual energy that this trance like swordsmanship swallowed up was staggering but it could certainly not be denied. Even though he wasn’t performing any attacking strikes his movements caused the whole place to rumble.

“Oh god, did he achieve the sword heart?... is he moving past it… how is that possible?”

“A genius of the sword!”

Everyone cleared out of the way as the sword energies that continued to gather around Zhang Dong’s body would be able to slice any opponent that came near them apart in a matter of moments. This was truly the pinnacle of swordsmanship that could not be reached by buying skills alone.

Chapter 412

“You see, I told you that he is the true second descendant.”

A rather happy-looking Azure Dragon was standing together with three elders and looking at his new brother performing a mystical sword dance. His movements weren’t anything that these old men and women had seen before, it was truly a long-forgotten sword art that they were witnessing being born anew.

“Did he really reach enlightenment by just spending only an hour in the secret chamber of sword intent?”

“What the Emperor says must be true then, no one other than a true descendant would be able to grasp the ancestral sword techniques… doing it this fast only shows us how much of a genius he is…”

“I still can’t grasp his true strength… his cultivation method is bizarre, he seems like a core formation junior but is much stronger, could it just be the aurulent flame’s unique Qi?”

“The evidence is hard to deny but we should still be careful, this man has not been brought up within the clan, we do not know where his duty lies…”

The three here were the grand elders of the clan. After the Azure Emperor, they possessed the most political might in the whole clan. If the Emperor ever perished or died of old age they would take up his duties until a new one surfaced. To them, Zhang Dong was a big wild card which they didn’t know if they could trust.

“Are you worried that he might side with the other factions?”

“The possibility isn’t zero, they will surely try…”

Even though these three had a lot of pull, the Long Clan had many powerful nascent soul masters. Some were influential and powerful enough to be on the same footing as these three grand elders.

Now if for instance, they gained the favor of someone that was on the same footing as the Azure Emperor it could mean civil war. While Long Qing didn’t seem to be worried about his new brother’s loyalty, the old elders were.

“You three worry too much, even the old texts mentioned the appearance of the true disciple and that he would usher in a new age of cultivation!”

“Yes we do, but what if in this new age of cultivation the Long Clan doesn’t exist?”

Long Yingjie, the oldest of the three grand elders, asked while feeling the ground rumble. Zhang Dong was finished with his sword dance which left some of the pillars in bad shape.

“He managed to damage the ancestral pillars… he truly is strong…”

“Stop worrying, we need my brother for this coming war! During the battles we will deepen our bond as we are warriors at heart!”

The three were still skeptical but it seemed that their leader had made up his mind about this new element. What would need to follow was a proper inauguration to the sect and presenting him as the second true descendant. This would probably get some pushback from the Azure Dragon faction.

“Well, I’ll leave the paperwork to you elders, you know I’m not that good with these things.”

Long Qing laughed out while strolling towards Zhang Dong who was somewhat sweating after performing the new sword technique. The three elders just nodded as they knew that their strength was mostly in politics while Long Qing was still the most powerful warrior here.

“While my husband tends to our newest family member, let us discuss the coming crisis, shall we?”

The Empress spoke up as she made herself known. Long Yingjie bowed to this woman. While she was all smiles he knew that she had a lot more power here than one might expect. The emperor would constantly ask her for approval on difficult decisions and she was always able to sway them.

While this was going on Zhang Dong looked at his shaky sword hand. The weapon that he pulled out of his spatial ring was a lower heaven grade sword. But after performing some of the movements this item was filled with cracks.

‘I just performed a couple of sword movements… what if I actually tried to use a more powerful offensive move?’

This swordsmanship wasn’t something easily mastered. It required a lot of spiritual energy that even a nascent soul master at the great circle stage would not have. He didn’t despair as with his new cultivation method he was a master at such a level.

His cores were still unfilled as they constantly wanted more energy. The seed that he was nurturing had grown slightly and he felt his power increasing as the seed grew. If this continued he might even be able to push slightly past the limits of what a nascent soul master would be able to contain.

‘I need to gather more spirit points and upgrade this sword style… Only powerful techniques that I can somewhat master can get me past that deficiency…’

While his strength was comparable to the pinnacle of the nascent soul, he lacked one component. This was a soul beast, this was something unique to that level and he was unable to summon his soul dragon that once aided him in battle.

This put him at a disadvantage against other nascent soul masters. It would be as if he was constantly going against two opponents at once. The only way to get past this deficiency was to be stronger than his opponent or somehow seal the opposing soul beasts.

While the beast were mighty and could act on their own, they were still condensed soul energies. Zhang Dong’s soul core had already proven how well it could absorb those kinds of energies. Maybe with more training, he could point it towards the soul beast and absorb them even when they belonged to cultivators at his level of power.

‘This clan has provided me with a lot of holy energy, I need to gather more lightning and souls now to put everything into equilibrium.’

After eating almost every nirvana fruit his golden core had expanded to a larger size than his other cores. It would be impossible for him to absorb more holy energy before nourishing the other two cores. If he tried he risked cultivation deviation which could cripple him outright.

“See Shen, I told you that you should respect your uncle! Maybe if you pay your respects he will even teach you some sword techniques.”

“Father…”

Long Qing appeared once again with a big smile on his face. When he heard that he was supposed to teach the brat sword techniques Zhang Dong frowned slightly. There would be some ass crawling required from this Long Shen for him to get anything out of him now. His opinion of these three young masters was somewhat low but it didn’t mean that he would be opposed to it if they apologized.

“Hm, maybe if he kowtows a thousand times and calls me great senior uncle, I might think about it.”

Long Shen recoiled in disgust at what Zhang Dong offered. It was clear that he was a prideful one who would probably not be easily swayed by techniques.

“I don’t need any help father, I can achieve mastery of the ancestral sword arts by myself!”

“I don’t think your son has much of a sense of humor, my brother.”

Zhang Dong just shrugged while looking at Long Qing. The Emperor just laughed while also being somewhat surprised. There weren’t many people that talked to him in such a casual way.

Everyone that was here noticed how nonchalant Zhang Dong was being with the Emperor. It was clear that this was a new powerful player that had arrived at their faction. That Zhang Dong was a true descendant was still not known to everyone as a proper announcement still had to be made.

The man in question had gone through every important point in this large crystal tower. If he was frank he would probably want to leave at this point. His wife was also constantly calling him every thirty minutes over his system as she was deathly worried that he was being tortured or something.

It didn’t look like he would be able to just ditch everything now. He probably needed to go meet with all the important elders of the clan. Then his true identity needed to be announced to the entire clan and then through the entire empire.

This would offer him the freedom to roam the realm in search of Wang Long. With the Azure Emperor backing him directly no sect could close their gates to him. Due to this, he decided to go along with this process as he did need the help.

When everything was done he would gain access to every single teleportation gate in the empire. He could produce an empire-wide witch hunt for Wang Long, any information that could bring him closer to where the man was would be rewarded. This loose end needed to be tied up before the other nations attacked.

….

In another location…

A large man with his chest bear was sitting in a large throne room. Behind him, lava was pouring down from the ceiling and lighting up the entire chamber. The heat was truly immense but the man sitting there didn’t seem perturbed by it.

In his hand, there was some kind of leg of an unknown creature. While looking at a bowing man in front of him the large man opened up his mouth to present quite elongated sharp teeth that ripped into the piece of meat he was holding.

“Speak.”

“Oh great Demon Emperor, I bring news from the world boundary, the time is upon us.”

“Hoh, is it time for the legendary hunt? You better not be lying to me, shaman!”

“I would never, oh great Demon!”

The man prostrated himself before this man that seemed to be at least three meters tall. He wasn’t the only person here either, many others were down on their knees, faces lowered into the hard volcanic rock that this place was made of.

“Finally, sound the horns, we prepare for the great hunt! We will gorge ourselves on the flesh of our enemies and reach the apex of creation!”

The man stood up from the large throne that was made from various bones of unknown creatures. His footsteps caused the whole place to shake as he descended with a massive flaming cleaver over his shoulder.

There were various other scenes like this playing out at almost the same time at other locations. Various leaders were being informed about the coming time. It was as if each and every one of them had a different prophecy guiding them towards the coming conflict.

The millennia they spent preparing for this day were finally going to be of use. The battlefield was beyond the borders of their lands. For some, it was called the great hunting grounds, for others the celestial lands of legends. Time was running out for everyone, the war that was to rock this whole planet was close...

Chapter 413

“My brothers and sisters, we have gathered today to greet a new member of our family…”

Zhang Dong was sitting to the side while one of the elders was giving a speech. Long Qing, his supposed brother, was down on his throne together with his wife. The kids were all properly dressed and to the side while the older generation was presented to the masses.

The Long Clan was quite advanced for the setting. It had similar holographic technology to the United Element Sect. Thanks to it they were transmitting a proper image to some of the larger cities around the empire.

While he didn’t really want to do this, it was important to get his face out there. The Long Clan was giving him and his sect free advertisement. By confirming that he was now part of the royal family there would not be any closed doors to him.

“Thus I would like to introduce everyone to our Azure Emperor’s brother, Long Dong the Golden Dragon!”

With some persuasion, he was able to go with the golden dragon title instead of the one the old ancestor had. This didn’t matter as much as no one besides the core family members even knew that he had existed. The information had been long forgotten and only existed in the locked library.

With his name now spreading through the lands he would probably have the trouble of ever being called Zhang Dong ever again. He would have to cope with being Long Dong from now on.

“Thank you elder Yingjie for those eloquent words of introduction but this is not the time for pleasantries, I must implore everyone to be vigilant in these coming days as there is a villain that plagues this land and he goes by the name Wang Long…”

While the people that were listening to this introduction were a bit confused, the members of the Long Clan had been informed beforehand. They also agreed that someone like Wang Long needed to be stopped and they couldn’t really stop Zhang Dong from speaking out.

To him this was the most important problem they needed to tend to, more important than the secret war effort that was starting in the background. Almost no one besides the Long Clan and the Heavenly Crane Sect knew about this problem. The smaller sects had been kept in the dark as they weren’t seen as very useful.

From Zhang Dong’s perspective, this was a faulty mindset. He knew well that a united sect or land was far more deadly than one that was not. His sect was proof as with the help of formations even the lower leveled cultivators could combat the ones in a higher realm.

If it was up to him, he would have spread the knowledge through the lands to at least prepare the border regions for the onslaught. He was informed that the areas where the bridges to the other empires were supposed to appear the Long Clan had set up fortresses.

Even with those in place, he wasn’t sure if the Long Clan was expecting to go through a proper fight. With the eradication of the Soaring Dragon Sect, victory was more unlikely. The Azure Emperor was in high spirits though, it seemed that this hidden treasure that they had in store was supposed to be the ace to bring them victory.

The only problem with that was they weren’t willing to show it to him just yet. The elders were quite against Long Qing showing him this Goliath. It looked like they wanted to wait first, which made some sense.

Secret weapons were meant to be revealed at the later stage in war efforts. If they played their trump card too soon they would probably regret it. The threat that the attackers would pose was also unknown, it could have been highly exaggerated as some Long Clan members thought.

There was a part of them that was convinced that their cultivation had improved with their advancement. They believed that those other empires were probably at most at the level of the two grand sects. In their opinion, they would probably be able to achieve victory with conventional tactics and their own strength.

“This demonic cultivator is extremely dangerous, that is why I The Golden Dragon from the Long Clan implore you to not face him alone, you will be rewarded for any information that might bring us closer to his apprehension…”

Zhang Dong continued with his speech. He knew that the regular cultivators in the empire had no chance against Wang Long. They would just feed him more spirit points if they confronted him. Thus he only required them to point him in his general direction. He was also someone with a system and probably the only person that could handle him in a one-on-one scenario.

“I will personally dispose of this demonic cur, thus I implore you to report any strange occurrences…”

As he continued he listed a few particular things about Wang Long’s characteristics. One of them was how he liked to force himself upon young and beautiful women. The other was his soul beast, while he could disguise his face it wouldn’t be that easy to change his draconic soul beast.

While the information traveled through the whole empire, he expected Wang Long to also see it. This couldn’t be helped but might also lower the body count of the victims. After knowing that there was an empire-wide manhunt for him, he would probably try to hide somewhere safe.

There was a certain shadowy place for people like Wang Long. It would probably be the first one that he would attempt to make his own. But if the man was smart he would avoid any obvious places where demonic cultivators met.

“Live long, prosper, and may the Qi be strong with you…”

As with his own sect, he ended the speech with a few chosen words that stuck with him from his previous world. The response to his speech was met with lukewarm stares from the Long Clan populace.

He didn’t really mind this as this was quite the big exposition pill to swallow. They were getting a new high elder that was on par with the current Azure Emperor. At least on paper, the two should have the same amount of power and prestige.

Reality was often disappointing though, Zhang Dong didn’t fool himself into believing that the people would just accept him. It would probably take many years or something like the expedition he went through with his Zhang Clan to prove himself to them.

After the speech took place and he was inaugurated as the Golden Dragon, he noticed a change in his system. The part that had changed was his faction display. While he was still listed as the leader of the United Element Sect faction, he was now also a member of the Long Clan faction that had a separate tab.

There was not much on that one as besides the Azure Emperor that was next to him on the faction tree, there was no one else. This was probably all due to him not having a favorable relationship with anyone besides his new brother.

His approval rating was also not fully maxed out and only 70%. Before he showed that he was the actual true descendant the approval rating was probably lower. The elders that were here didn’t seem to trust him enough to show up on the faction tab, the queen nor her children appeared on it either.

‘I guess everyone is just putting up with me due to Long Qing… I wonder if they would accept me as their new Emperor if anything happened to him…’

This was something that he expected people to think. He was a powerful cultivator on the level of the Azure Emperor. From their standpoint, it wouldn’t be surprising if he pointed his sword at Long Qing. It was actually a very natural event as all of the cultivators here had progressed in mind.

The spot on top of the empire would be a natural place for them to go for if they were in Zhang Dong’s position. Thus everyone that was on the Azure Emperor side were on guard as they didn’t know when the Golden Dragon would make his move.

‘I bet after they gather more information people from the opposing factions will try to contact me…’

Zhang Dong on the other hand didn’t want to have anything to do with the inner struggles of the Long Clan. He just wanted to use their help to get past the coming hurdle. They were something that he needed, if the war was really coming he might even have to move his own sect here.

He didn’t want to admit it but this flying fortress was probably better suited for a prolonged defensive. After reading through some craftsmen books that were here it would take some time to get his own sect up into the air along with the whole city. The problem as always was a proper power source which this flying city apparently had. It was something hidden away quite well as even with his senses he could not tell where it was.

“That was an interesting speech my brother, I see that you really wish to get to this Wang Long.”

“Yes, I would sleep much better if he vanished from these lands.”

“Come, this is not the time for such matters, we need to feast!”

“Well… about that…”

Zhang Dong stopped before his new brother. Long Qing was clearly not taking things as seriously as he was. Now that he had done what he came here for there was nothing keeping him here. His family was waiting for him at home as well, his disciple was still in the ship that they left behind.

“Is there something bothering you brother?”

“I have to return to my own family, I have already overstayed my welcome but don’t worry we shall meet again, for now though… I’ll have to bid you all farewell.”

With a quick clasp to his fist and a bow he just vanished. Golden dribblers of lights were left behind as he left the people here quite shocked.

“Instant teleportation?”

“H-how? It shouldn’t be possible without the proper knowledge of the formation…”

They were all shocked as the grand formation that was in the city didn’t allow anyone to teleport in or out. If they attempted they would be struck down by the defensive features but this Golden Dragon apparently was able to get out as they could not feel his presence anywhere else.

“Ha Ha! My brother is full of mysteries of his own, don’t worry elders, we should trust him!”

The Azure Emperor just started laughing while everyone else was left with question marks above their heads.

Chapter 414

“What did I just watch… Did that guy really include quotes from old movies in that speech?”

A man covered head to toe by a stylish dark robe was looking up into the heavens. There in the clouds was a grand projection of a face that he knew. While listening to the long-winded tale he placed his hand to his cheek where he still remembered getting hit by the person that just finished talking.

Wang Long was his name which he chose as a joke. Now after being the reason for his own sect’s downfall he was taking it easy in one of the largest cities that the empire had to offer. The projection came as a surprise as he had never seen anyone else use these sorts of treasures in this world. At most, they had theater plays or musicals that were not recorded for later use.

“Are we going to have two emperors now?”

“How can that happen?”

“So is this Golden Dragon just a part of the Long Clan or something?”

“It doesn’t matter who he is you fool, he is clearly someone important so keep your mouth quiet if you see someone from the capital!”

Wang Long was sitting at an empty table at a certain costly inn. After his plan of eradication was fruitful he was at a loss. To him, this was a game but one that was not that easy to play. There were no map markers pointing him to his next destination. In his mind, he needed to find the right NPC to show him to the next stage of this ‘game’.

While he was deliberating on his next move the speech happened. For the time being, he was hiding his face behind a certain skill that he bought from the system store. It was a demonic technique that made people perceive it to be different even when directly looking at it.

This technique performed the same act as the one Zhang Dong was using but it was fundamentally different. The other one actually altered the person’s body structure at the molecular level. Which had its advantages and disadvantages.

The only reason Wang Long went with this type of technique over the other was that he was quite vane. He did not want to change the perfectly crafted face that he possessed. If he did he felt like his new persona could crumble and that would remember his previous appearance before coming to this world.

‘Look at those idiots talking... ‘

While sipping some expensive wine he continued to listen as after the speech was over, he was part of the news.

“But that Wang Long is clearly a no good maniac.”

“You’re right, how could someone kill everyone from their own sect? Does he have no remorse for his own family?”

“It was also the Soaring Dragon sect… how do they expect us to deal with someone that could do that?”

As he continued to listen he became more annoyed than ever. Before Zhang Dong came along no one dared utter his name in bad faith. Now on the other hand they were calling him a murderous bastard that ate newborns for breakfast.

‘I did switch my alignment though… where do demonic cultivators even go?’

Wang Long was not someone that planned out things too well. This was the first time that he was truly alone even the place that he was in now wasn’t that far away from the Soaring Dragon Sect grounds.

With the money that he took from there, he could actually live a life of leisure which made him regress to his old ways. In the city that he was in he could live in a good hotel while they delivered women to him. There wasn’t that much of a difference, with some spirit stones he could make almost everyone do his bidding.

His main goal was to shut down his true opponent that was Zhang Dong. For now, he feared attacking his faction base even with his current improvement. He had no allies and no particular place that he could call his home.

Zhang Dong had clearly gone for the faction building option that he had previously ignored. Now after his first loss he took some time to examine this part of his system tab. But without actually having a faction of his own, he could not test anything out.

‘Do I need to create my own faction now? As a demonic cultivator it would probably be best to take over an evil sect… but is there one that can go against that bastard?’

While he mostly ignored the political and geographical lessons that his old sect tried to force upon him, he did know who the Azure Emperor was. If Zhang Dong had managed to trigger the emperor’s favor he would need to somehow counter it.

At first, he thought that his only option would be to just drain people for spirit points and increase his battling capabilities. But luck was on his side as one of the NPC's that he was eavesdropping on gave him some critical information.

“Where do you think that murderous Wang Long vanished to? You don’t think he could be staying in our Fragrant Jade City?”

“How would that make any sense? Who would be stupid enough to flee to the closest large city they can find?”

The man telling this burst out in laughter while Wang Long’s face contorted into anger. It seemed that even this nobody knew that it would be unreasonable for a demonic cultivator to flee to the closest big city next to the crime scene.

“We would have known if he passed through here, those demonic cultivators are cruel bastards!”

“That’s true, we would have probably all been dead if he passed through here, or taken prisoner for some grotesque experiments!”

The two old men shivered a bit as they knew that the evil cultivators liked making pills out of humans. The larger the cultivation of those humans the better the pill came out.

“If I was him… I’d probably head to the Eternal Dark?”

“Oh, right there is still that place…It would make sense if he went there...”

‘Eternal Dark?’

Wang Long perked up at the mention of something he wasn’t quite aware of. He strained his brain which had been enhanced by the system. Even though he did not like learning new things, his memorization capabilities were superhuman.

‘Oh yeah, now I remember… it’s some kind of area at the fringes of the empire…’

The memory of a certain forced lesson flooded into his head. This Eternal Dark was a region populated by demonic monsters and cultivators alike. It was supposedly a safe haven for these people as no one really cared for it.

It was surrounded by dark clouds and acid rain. The Qi was corrupt and would suck away the energy of any cultivator that didn’t study demonic energies. It was filled with dangers and monsters at every corner.

‘This could be it…’

A lightbulb went off in his head, it all started making sense to him. If he thought in gaming ways, this was the perfect place for him to conquer. The righteous cultivators could not venture into these lands that were filled with many dangers. He on the other hand bought an immortal level demonic cultivation manual that was perfectly suited for it.

‘I just need to go there and create my own demonic sect! No, wait. Why do I need to create it? I’ll just take over one of them!’

Wang Long had seen how Zhang Dong managed to make his own faction stronger. He attributed everything that his enemy achieved to his system. Thus he believed that if he took over a sect there he could dump spirit points into this new faction.

Through this, it would become stronger and act as his new army of demons. With his cultivation being over Zhang Dong’s and a large army of demonic cultivators and beasts, he would be victorious.

‘That idiot isn’t even using his system right, the evil factions are always stronger and easier to farm.’

Zhang Dong was clearly going with the good factions. The holy energies that he was using were proof of this. Wang Long knew that due to this his enemy couldn’t just go around killing people. Thus he would only be able to farm spirit points by converting spirit stones.

On the other hand he went with the more morally gray faction at first but now he was switching to a morally corrupt one. He could even kill people from his own side and no one would probably bat an eye.

While going through the faction section of the system he also discovered something. There were two ways of gaining more followers, one was through something called an approval rating that increased dedication. But there was also something else there, the fear rating.

‘I don’t need them to like me, if they fear me they will be forced to respect me and dedicate their life!’

“This is it, this is what I will do!”

The people that were having a conversation about the Dark Lands looked over to where Wang Long was seated. His outburst was loud and somewhat obnoxious which caused everyone to scowl at him.

“What are you looking at?”

Instead of apologizing though he started them down with anger in his eyes. The men instantly turned their heads to the side as Wang Long had a somewhat imposing air around him.

“That’s what I thought!”

Like a strutting peacock, he moved his chin up while standing up. Everyone went quiet for the time being after they noticed that the man that stood up was not hiding his Qi. It was truly immense and overbearing but thanks to Wang Long’s special disguising technique the people here didn’t perceive it as demonic Qi.

“Hey there old man, I have a question for you…”

Wang Long after the prolonged walk ended up directly in front of the two men that were discussing.

“P-please s-senior I didn’t mean to offend.”

“No need to be scared, I just wanted to ask you about what you were discussing, Eternal Dark was it? Where can I find this Eternal Dark?”

The two men were now lowering their heads while panicking. But this was not the first time that they interacted with a scary cultivator, if he asked them a question they just needed to be respectful and give him the information.

“Ah yes the Eternal Dark, you just need to go towards the…”

Wang Long just smirked while looking at his system map feature that as more information was given to him continued to fill up. Soon he had the correct path towards his destination.

“Good, this will do.”

The old man was given a pat on the shoulder before Wang Long left the premises. The moment he was down on the ground and outside the large expensive inn, he heard a dinging sound.

Hong Fung has been slain, you have earned 1 spirit point.

When looking up to the tower he could see a dark green cloud bursting out through the windows and eating its way down through the whole structure.

‘Damn low leveled shits, I need to get to a higher leveled place than this!’

As he departed the screams of his victims filled his ears but to someone like him that didn’t see them as anything other than spirit points their pleads went unanswered. What was on his mind now was the next stage of this game which would consist of gaining even more power and his own personal army.

Chapter 415

“I thought I got over my stage fright already.”

Zhang Dong was sitting in his own quarters back at the Argonaut flagship. He had specifically used his teleportation feature to show to his new allies that he was no simple cultivator. Even now they were probably wondering how he was able to escape from their teleportation blocking formations.

In reality, he wasn’t that sure either as this was a feature of the system that was above his current knowledge level. It was clear to him that the teleportation feature had to be at least immortal grade or even further beyond that. What was above the immortal level even he didn’t know as his old system store never showed him any techniques above it.

When remembering his old store he also remembered Wang Long. With the speech given he would be probably receiving a lot of false information about other demonic cultivators. Luckily there probably weren’t that many demonic cultivators at the nascent soul level which would narrow the search.

While he hoped that he would be able to flush Wang Long out he didn’t like his chances. Thus he consulted the only person that he could.

‘Bob, is there no way of tracing Wang Long?’

‘Not enough data.’

‘Isn’t there some way to track other system users? Don’t they possess some kind of unique spiritual energy signature or trail? There must be something, when the items they buy from the store, there always was a strange distortion in space, can’t we track that?’

‘Calculating… proposition is feasible but requires Qi fingerprint of the target user.’

Zhang Dong nodded as this was along the lines that he thought it would go. Bob would be used as a bloodhound to sniff out Wang Long, for this, he needed to find a place where his opponent had been. One place was his own sect where they battled with each other but he wasn’t sure if Wang Long accessed his store there or not.

“If I can’t find a traceback at home, I’ll have to go to the Soaring Dragon Sect…”

That was probably the area with the largest concentration of Wang Long’s energies. Apparently, the demonic energies that he transferred into it were still swirling around. No one below the nascent soul level could safely enter it.

Even the masters at those levels couldn’t hold out long without some kind of demonic Qi protection. Luckily Zhang Dong came equipped with a massive amount of holy energy that would just filter the environment out for him.

As he was thinking about his next few moves he heard a knock on the door.

“Come in.”

“Master.”

Zhang Liu entered through the automatic door to give a small report.

“We should be at the Sect in a couple of days, Master but...”

“But?”

Zhang Dong asked as he saw Zhang Liu fidgeting around.

“Don’t worry if you have a question you can go ahead and ask your master, I won’t bite.”

He chuckled slightly as after spending some time with his male disciple the young man seemed quite distant. This was probably due to how much time had passed since the last time the two saw each other.

“Ah… then… I think you should go ahead and up…”

“Go ahead?”

“Yes, we will be fine Master! So you can return!”

Zhang Liu started to awkwardly shout the sentences out at the end as if he wanted to get his point out at the fastest possible rate.

“Oh…”

Zhang Dong could have directly teleported back to the sect but decided to stay in the flying ship for one main reason. He was there to protect the people inside as he did not know if they would be attacked by some unruly anti-Golden Dragon faction.

While he had been introduced as a true descendant and blood brother to the Azure Emperor, this didn’t mean that everyone accepted him. He could see some loyal subjects trying to remove him out of fear of him causing a revolt. He had teleported away to safety and probably no one knew that he was inside this ship but he was still worried.

“The other sect members also agree, I’m sure Master has more important tasks to carry out, you don’t need to worry about us, we will arrive safely!”

“Heh…”

He could only smile while standing up from his seat. There he went over to Zhang Liu and gave his awkward pupil a pat on the shoulder. He wasn’t sure what had happened for these past five years but he hoped that there would be enough time for more pleasantries later.

“You’re probably right if they wanted to attack as they missed the best chance they had…”

They were already out of the Long Clan territory that wasn’t all that large, to begin with. They clearly didn’t care about any other spot than what was around their floating city.

“Well then Liu, I’ll leave the ship to you... oh, right I almost forgot…”

He placed his finger on Liu’s forehead and injected some of his knowledge that he had gathered through the years. When parting his techniques to his students he didn’t take into account that he would be gone for that long. He didn’t like to push too many advanced arts onto them before they were ready. While he did leave many books and notes this impartation technique was far superior as always.

“Master!”

“Yes I know, you should study hard. If you continue like this you might be able to reach the nascent soul level soon.”

It was kind of funny how little time it took for a person to reach this fabled realm. With the help of high-quality techniques, it was not hard to do it before reaching the age of forty. This only showed him that there was something wrong here.

If a person could progress this fast, why weren’t there any immortal level masters around? It seemed that going past the nascent soul level was impossible for the regular people of this world. It didn’t seem that anyone would get anywhere if they didn’t have the system's help.

Even with it around it would require an astonishing amount of spirit points to achieve the breakthrough.

‘This war scenario is looking more and more like just a scripted spirit point farm…’

To him that had a whole sect and family to worry about this wasn’t such a good thing. On the other hand to someone like Wang Long that didn’t care about anything else by himself, it would be free points left and right. He could attack each of the fighting empires until he got powerful enough to face Zhang Dong.

‘I really need to find this maniac before this can happen… the other option is to get my faction stronger…’

How far Wang Long could go by farming spirit points from this war was unknown to him. From what he remembered the cost of immortal grade techniques and cultivation boosts was quite staggering. It was to the point of killing hundreds of nascent soul masters for one of those store-bought items.

“I will make you proud Master!”

“Oh right and one more thing…”

Before leaving Zhang Dong looked at his disciple with a somewhat scolding look.

“You should really stop letting Nuana walk all over you…”
After returning to this world he noticed that his disciple was still somewhat at the mercy of his wife’s younger sister. She acted all cutesy with him but he had Liena to keep her in check. In Liu’s situation, there was no one, he needed to man up and not let her walk all over him.

“Nuana? W-we are doing fine…”

“Didn’t look that way to me… she didn’t have trouble knocking you out before…”

Liu slumped his shoulders while flopping his head down. Because of his mishap, Nuana was put in danger.

“Here, you can use this mirror to train.”

Zhang Dong pointed to the mirror that was in these private quarters.

“The mirror, Master?”

“Yes, I want you to look at it and imagine that you are talking with Nuana.”

Zhang Liu wasn’t sure what this was about but not like he could refuse a direct command from his master. Even less after he had imparted some new knowledge to him. Thus he moved in front of the mirror and tried imagining that he was looking at Nuana.

“Okay, now Imagine that she is trying to get you to do something that you dislike.”

“Something I dislike?”

“Yes anything, does she give you some unreasonable requests?”

“Well… she does like to travel a lot… to the point of me not being able to cultivate…”

Zhang Liu gave out a sigh as he remembered a couple of the conversations. All of them he capitulated which pushed his progress back. The only way he dealt with Nuana’s approaches was by hiding himself in hard-to-access locations with the hopes that she wouldn’t be able to find him before he was done with his training.

“That will do… Now repeat after me… I will not go with you, I must train, now leave!”

Zhang Liu rubbed his head while staring at the mirror as he felt somewhat silly saying these words. But as this was just him looking at the mirror, it didn't pose much of a problem even for him.

“Louder! Put some heart into it!”

“I will not go with you! Now leave me be!”

Zhang Dong was a bit surprised as his disciple started out right shouting at the mirror as if it was a true enemy. He could see some pent up frustration in Liu’s motions as he had his fist clenched tightly.

“Oh hey Nuana, when did you arrive?”

“Liu, how could you say something like that!”

Zhang Liu looked to the side and saw Feng Nuana just standing there with tears in her eyes. The moment he saw her his anger subsided and he quickly started apologizing. This caused him to get smacked in the back of the head by Zhang Dong as he had failed the test.

“Huh? Master.”

The moment he got clobbered the Nuana he was apologizing to dissolved into the scenery.

“Can’t tell the difference between an illusion and the real Nuana? You still have much to learn…”

Zhang Dong chuckled as he saw his disciple drop his head in defeat yet again. But now after his little prank had gone through he seemed to have reached an epiphany.

“Well, I’ll leave you to it. You need to clear out demons like this or the demonic cultivators could use illusions like this to get to you.”

“Yes, Master!”

“Good, then I’ll see you back at the sect, there is much I must discuss with the elders.”

Thus he clicked the system's teleportation option to get back home. There he just wanted to flop into his wife’s ample bosom and sleep. REgretfully being the Patriarch he had his obligations that needed to be fulfilled first.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 416

‘Well, that went better than I expected… now what?’

After going through the Long Clan, raising his holy energies to a new level, and giving his disciple some pointers, Zhang Dong was back in his secret lair. It was the same room he teleported to when the Soaring Dragon Sect was attacking through which he could look at his territory without being bothered.

While he wanted to do nothing more than to return to his family, he needed to think. What would be the best plan for the coming future that was more uncertain than ever. Zhang Dong wasn’t sure but he needed to make a decision. The other elders could make propositions but in the end, it was him that needed to make the decision. A decision that would dictate if more people would die or not.

‘What options do I have…’

He started to pace back and forth while looking at the monitor screens. On them, there were many sect members running around. The city had been freshly destroyed and the rubble was still being cleared out. The city populace was also still scattered in all directions while some sect members were with them for protection.

‘If those bridges between empires open up, then the common people are at risk…’

The first problem was with the normal people that just wanted to live their lives. Not everyone cared for this war between empires as not everyone was a cultivator. In reality, the majority of people in the world were in the ‘mortal’ category while the ‘immortals’ were a vast minority.

But in a world where one cultivator could without effort eradicate thousands of lives with a wave of their hand, it was obvious who was in charge. What the mortals could do was flee to the outer reaches where the spiritual energy was low and cultivators were sparse.

His sect was in such an area that posed a problem of its own. It was a very well-established sect with many resources and good technology. It would probably be a prime target for any attackers from the other empires.

Luckily the escape mechanism of the sect had not been used yet. They would be able to flee to the designated locations if their formations fell to the attack. Thus some would probably want to remain here and wait it out. The grand formation was powered by the spirit vein under their lands, it was much more powerful than regular formations at a close level to the one that the Long Clan had.

When he looked from the point of the game, the Long Clan flying city was probably the last bastion of defense. From what he knew, the Azure Emperor was sure that even if they lost all of their lands, the flying fortress could not be breached.

They could remain there indefinitely and just wait for the bridges between empires to close. The was war supposed to take about a hundred years but it was not really clear. For him and the other nascent soul masters that could live a thousand years, this was nothing.

Some would probably prefer this turtle tactic. Most of the cultivators just cared about their own lands and sects. If the rest of the empire was eradicated in this war, it didn’t matter at all. After a hundred years they would just repopulate them again with their own branch families like the last time this happened.

It seemed to Zhang Dong that the Long Clan flying city was something to act as a safe point for the system holder. From there they could leave and farm for spirit points in a world filled with battle. Then maybe within those hundred years they would achieve victory and amass enough points to get to the next level.

‘Maybe the longer this war lasts the stronger the enemies will become… something like a horde mode in games, they will just keep coming in waves, some of them bringing bosses that you’re supposed to defeat?’

He could only speculate on the true way that this new phase would play out. If the enemies just came in waves then having a good well-protected fortress would be the best option. But the big question was if this sect that he had created was enough to push back the impending doom or not.

If the spiritual formations fell in the coming onslaught, then he would be responsible for many deaths of his own people. It might have been better to just move their base of operations into the Azure Emperor’s castle.

‘There is one problem, I don’t think they will just let me move the entire city into their territory…;

While the Azure Emperor treated him like a blood brother, he wasn’t the only one there. Zhang Dong could see them only accepting the innermost sect members without letting him bring over the common people that would be left out in the dust.

The lands that he controlled were also vast, much more than Spirit Spring City. There were various other similar metropolitans with millions of people living there. They were run by small clans that had trouble even producing one core formation master.

He was unaware of the scope of the attackers but how things were now, he believed them to have many cultivators at similar power levels as nascent soul masters. Saint Emperor and Saint Emperors from the Emerald Phoenix empire would probably swarm them. Without nascent soul cultivators to patrol the lands the cities would be in shambles.

‘The sect had improved a lot though… they should have a good chance of defending the lands…’

One good thing that came out of Wang Long’s attack was that he had forced his sect members to progress further. Now his sect probably possessed one of the largest forces in the empire. The number of early-stage nascent soul cultivators they now had was staggering, probably enough to give the big three a run for their money.

‘If I ask the others for their input…’
While looking at the motivated masters already training and improving their newly gained cultivation, he knew what they would want. The people from his sect were born in difficult times, it was an eat or be eaten kind of world. They would probably want to rise up to the challenge and prove themselves, gain experience through battle as well as new resources to go further beyond.

“But there are more important things in this world than blind pride.”

While he knew that his people would dive into the midst of battle the moment he ordered them, he was conflicted in asking. His gaze turned to a certain screen on which he saw two children. They were in the process of a fight which was somewhat surprising.

On one side was Zhang Xiu, her eyebrows were at an angle as she was yanking what looked to be some kind of child-sized doll. On the other side was Zhang Jun whose face was filled with tears. There were no adults in the room; the two were as their mother was away ordering some sect to reposition some furniture.

As their house had crumbled to dust after he revealed the flying fortress built under it, they needed to relocate into a new mansion. One of the elders agreed to relocate elsewhere as they took over one of the larger mansions at the main sect.

This was the first time that Zhang Dong saw his kids interacting without adults being there. It seems that Xiu was in charge as she had no trouble shouting at her brother who was desperately trying to hold onto the doll.

‘Wait that toy… is it?’

A memory from about a year ago rushed into his head. It was a few weeks before he had to go away to fight his favorite tentacle monster. Before he went away, both his kids were already in this world and he had created a certain set of toys.

Being a big nerd back in his old world, he always enjoyed large robots. Thus not knowing what his kids would like he created two small robots, one pink and one blue. One of these robots was now being pulled from both sides by his children, it was the pink one that he had given to his daughter before leaving.

‘Wait… wasn’t the other one here…’

He had almost forgotten all about it as he had lost his entire spatial ring and all the items there. Luckily some of his creations were here, right in this room that he used to get away from it all. In one of the spatial rings here he found it, a half-meter tall toy robot. It had a little blue shield in one hand and a little gun in the other.

While this looked like a toy, it was actually a functional puppet with some armor over it. It could carry out basic commands and even fly around. The little blaster it had in its hand could shoot out a blast of spiritual energy. These blasts would produce a nice light show but would not cause any harm even to a child.

The other one that he gave to his daughter had a more feminine shape and was red. It had a similar armament and function as this one as he hoped that they would order them around to perform battle moves. He hoped to improve on these toys later but as he was in a rush this was all for now.

It brought a smile to his face that the last toy that he made for his daughter was still being used. But as he was reminiscing about the past, he saw on the screen that an accident happened. The toy was made from softer elements and was not really built to resist that much pulling. Soon one of the arms that was being pulled snapped away causing both of the kids to fly in opposite directions.

‘Oh… she looks really mad…’

Xiu was left with a one-armed battle bot toy, while Liu was left with an arm. The older sister’s previously mad face started watering up as well and it seemed that her brother was in for a beating.

While he thought this was a normal reaction from his daughter's side, he wasn’t sure why his son was so clingy too. The toy that he made was not something that was made for him, he still had some attachment to it. At first, he thought that his son didn’t care that much about his father but maybe he was wrong about that.

‘I guess it’s time to act like a father for once…’

He gave out a sigh while his heart rate increased. A whole year had passed since he had to act as a father. Before it was quite easy, his daughter was just a bundle of energy that was quite attached to him.

Now it wouldn’t be so easy, she was much older and he also had a five-year-old son that didn’t know him at all. This might have been the hardest enemy that he would face to this day, being a parent.

Chapter 417

“What did you do!”

“I… I didn’t mean it…”

An angered girl was looking at her younger brother who was holding a part of a precious gift. It was the girl’s only reminder of her father that had vanished five years ago. Even though the father had returned to them, the toy robot still had a huge sentimental meaning.

“I’m sure that it can be fixed…”

Zhang Jun, who had been left with the arm on the ground, started to slowly move towards his older sister. Before he could try to attach the dislocated arm Zhang Xiu pulled away.

“No, you’ll just make it worse, don’t touch it!”

Xiu quickly smacked Jun’s arm away with all her might. But this also caused him to drop the robot arm that he was holding. The two looked in shock as the toy part flew into the distance. Though these two were still children, their strength was already immense. Their bodies came from a nascent soul master which somewhat enhanced their inner Qi and body as well.

They were still children though, they didn’t really go through proper training yet. Jun was quick to turn around to try and catch the arm but so did his sister. Both of them tossed each other at it which caused them both to collide with each other.

“Ow…”

“Oof…”

Soon they realized that they were both down on the ground. Jun also felt that he landed on something harder and as he tried to get up, he heard a crunching sound. With shock plastered all over his face, he quickly tried to remove himself from the floor.

“N...no… I didn’t mean to, it’s because sister wouldn’t listen…”

What the two kids discovered was a broken toy robot arm. While previously it might have only required a quick glue job, now on the other hand, the elbow joint was also broken. The fingers that were actually operational were also a bit cracked as this toy was made from rather soft materials that imitated plastic more than metal.

Zhang Xiu looked at the broken part that didn’t look salvageable. Then she turned her head to the person that was responsible for it. Her brother was standing there and prattling on that it wasn’t his fault. She didn’t want to hear it, thus she raised her fist up towards him with the intent to strike him.

While Jun was only five, his sister was still older. While no proper training was given, she performed some breathing exercises to enhance her Qi already. If the smack that was flying towards him connected the young man would probably feel it the next day.

But as the small fist was about to land on little Jun’s cheek it connected with a strange bubble-like substance. Instead of hitting his face, Xiu’s fist bounced back. This rebound caused her to float into the air while also being surrounded by a shiny transparent bubble.

“Now, now, you two shouldn’t be fighting over trivial things like this.”

The two children heard a man’s voice call out from afar. Soon they saw the bright white hair and chiseled jaw of their father as he floated their way. The moment Jun saw Zhang Dong approach he went silent, his head dropped as he evaded his gaze. Xiu on the other hand burst out in tears while squirming around.

“But daddy, he… he destroyed the toy that you left me!”

“Oh? He did?”

Zhang Dong glanced towards Jun who was trying not to look at him. He then slowly approached the young boy that was floating in a bubble of his creation.

“I-I didn’t mean to… I just w-wanted to help…”

For once he tried to explain himself to the father that he never knew. Finally, he gathered up some courage to look at the man that was approaching him. The young boy expected to see a stern look of disapproval but instead, he saw a big smile. The confusion continued as he felt a large hand being placed on his head, then his hair being messed up by some rough petting.

“Is that so? Good going then.”

“Good going?”

Both Jun and Xiu were confused as they floated down to the floor. The bubbles that were holding them in the air soon burst and they both landed on their posteriors. While Jun was just confused, Xiu was still mad. She looked at the destroyed robot arm that she cherished and was close to bursting out in tears.

“But daddy…”

“Now, there is no need to cry, it’s just a toy and toys can be fixed, just wait a moment and daddy will fix it.”

“Daddy can fix it?”

“Yes, I’m the one that made it for you, I wouldn’t be much of a craftsman if I couldn’t fix the items I make.”

Zhang Dong laughed out in a gentle fashion while pointing his finger towards the cracked robot arm. With a little wave, it was brought over towards a nearby table. The rest of the pink robot was brought over here as well and the kids were a bit astonished to see the parts floating around while being covered by a golden glow.

“I guess this will be the first time for both of you, let me show you have daddy crafts treasures. First, we bring out the materials, in this case, I don’t need much, just enough to cover the damages.”

Zhang Dong placed the cracked robot arm next to the toy along with a grayish clump that looked similar to clay. When he turned to look at his children they seemed to be really interested in this procedure which made him smile even more.

“But daddy… how will that gray thing fix it?”

“Hah, just watch, this quite a handy item, it's called cheytine, while it might look like everyday clay, it can do much more…”

“Chyt…”

“C..ine?”

While the two tried to repeat the name of the mineral that he was using, he continued with his crafting presentation.

“When a craftsman reaches a high stage in his craft, they are able to create treasures without the need of any proper tools like hammers. First, we produce flames and toss the cheytine in…”

He continued by producing a bright golden flam with his hand. The gray clump of cheytine was then tossed into it along with the destroyed toy’s arm. This caused Xiu to flinch as it looked like her father was further destroying the toy that was made for her.

“No need to be scared, these are special flames used for crafting, they do not destroy, instead they create.”

It didn’t take long for the items to melt and bind with each other. With another wave of his finger, the liquid that was created started changing shape. Soon it took the appearance of the robot arm, now without any blemishes or cracks.

The two kids had their eyes glued to this phenomenon. While they had witnessed other people perform blacksmithing, they had never seen someone craft items in this way. This technique was something only a nascent soul master would be truly capable of.

It also required pristine concentration and the exact knowledge of what the craftsman was making. If for a fraction of a second Zhang Dong’s attention was brought elsewhere, the process would be ruined and even an explosion could occur. For someone with his experience, this was as easy as breathing.

The rest of the pink robot floated next to the now repaired arm. Soon the shoulder joint was connected back into place and the toy was back to its previous form.

“There we go, good as new. X-Warrior 1, perform the salute!”

Zhang Dong placed the toy robot down on the ground. The moment he gave the command the toy robot performed a previously implemented motion. It made a fist with its right hand and brought it over towards where the heart would be.

“It works!”

Zhang Xiu moved towards the toy and picked it up from the ground. She started to twirl around while holding it above her head while laughing. Then at the end of the spin, she placed the toy on the ground and grasped her father’s thigh.

“I love you, daddy!”

“See, there was no reason to cry or be angry at your brother.”

Zhang Dong placed his hand on both Xiu and Jun’s heads and ruffled them both up. While Xiu was giggling around, the younger boy remained silent. The boy was still somewhat reserved but there was a change. During the moment that he was repairing the toy, he noticed that Jun’s eyes were quite sparkling. It was clear that he was interested in the process but probably didn’t know how to express his interest.

“Now, don’t you two have something to say to each other?”

He stopped petting them, the two children looked at each other, Jun moved his head down while Xiu pouted while turning her head to the side.

“Now don’t be like that, accidents will happen, the toy can be easily replaced but you can’t replace your family.”

After a moment of pouting the two finally managed to reconcile.

“I’m sowwy…”

“Me too, I’m sorry…”

Zhang Dong just nodded while smiling, this was not over yet as he was still holding out on one last thing. While Xiu was happily looking at her toy, Jun continued to steal glances towards it.

“Hey Jun.”

The moment Zhang Dong called out to him, the small boy flinched and almost fell on his behind.

“No need to be afraid of your father, I brought something for you.”

“Something for me?”

“Yes, here.”
With a small wave of his hand, Zhang Dong brought out the other toy robot that he was holding in his spatial ring. The gift was placed on the ground close to the pink toy robot that belonged to Zhang Xiu.

“This is X-Warrior 2 and it's yours.”

“Mine?”

Zhang Jun looked at the blue robot that was standing on the ground. It was a bit bulkier than the pink one and clearly crafted with a more masculine look in mind.

“Yes it’s yours, daddy made it a long time ago but never had a chance to give it to you before he had to leave…”

While Zhang Dong tried to explain himself, his young child didn’t seem to care that much. He was more focused on the toy that was standing in front of him than on the explanation.

“Why don’t you give him a command, it reacts to the same ones like the one that your sister has.”

His plan was to create more of these toys later as he did love when these types of robots combined with each other. For that he would need to make at least two more, maybe one for himself and one for his wife. Then they could have them combine with each other to form the ultimate toy robot.

“C-can I?”

“Sure you can, it’s yours now, how about you play with your sister?”

Xiu looked at the blue robot that was there and then back to her own. Luckily for Zhang Dong she seemed to prefer the more girly looking model while her brother was taken in by the blue one.

The kids finally started giving out some voice commands while their father looked over them. This small moment of peace would be burned into his mind, helping him through the dire times they were heading in…

Chapter 418

“Is everything alright?”

“Ah yes, sorry I spaced out a bit there…”

“You have a lot of nerve to space out when such a beauty is right next to you!”

Zhang Dong chuckled while hugging his wife closer. It was the dawn of the next day, after catching up with his children it was then time for his wife. One night of passion later he woke up with many thoughts crowding his head. Which continued all the way until the next day.

“The meeting is going to start soon, we need to get up…”

After a night of pleasure, it was time to get back to work. While he had gone through his decision in his head, he still intended to listen to the people he was responsible for.

“Do we really have to?”

To his surprise, Liena that most of the time was the proper cultivator in the relationship, wanted to skip the boring talk with the elders.

“It hasn’t been long since you have returned, the children need their father.”

From a family standpoint, it would probably be better if he remained at the sect ground to build up the relationship with his son and daughter. Regretfully the people from the other empires would not wait for that, neither would Wang Long. His biggest enemy remained at large and he had no idea where to search for him.

“I know but if we don’t act now, their future will be at stake.”

“I know…”

Liena nodded as he had clued her in about the coming war as he was returning from the empire. The other elders had also been informed via Zhang Liu that was close to returning home.

After a few moments, both of them put their robes back on. Zhang Dong's gaze focused on his wife as she was just as he remembered her. Five years did nothing to diminish her beauty probably before she reached the age of five hundred it would be hard to spot a wrinkle.

As he was the Patriarch everyone was already waiting for his arrival. The meeting chamber was still the same as the sect wasn’t damaged in the Soaring Dragon Sect assault.

Things had changed a bit though, with his absence the power balance had been shifted towards people like Huo Qiang and his Huo Clan. While he had feared that something like this would have happened, he was thankful to his old friend that he didn’t succumb to the allure of power.

With Zhang Dong gone it wouldn’t be hard for the Huo clan faction to take over. They did have the most nascent soul level masters and also the strongest one of them all. They would be crippling the sect though as they knew that Liena would not give up her position without a fight.

In a sense, the fear of other sects attacking during an infighting process had worked in favor. Without enough power to force the other side to capitulate without a fight, it was quite hard to change the status quo.

‘I guess having factions at a similar level is good for keeping order but this only works if they are close to equal…’

In his sect there were mostly only two factions, the one that he was the leader of which was the Zhang Clan and Feng Clan factions. The other faction was on the Huo side and their allies that prefer doing things the old-fashioned way, by the sword or fist.

“Senior brother Dong, when will we spar again? I need to show you all the new tricks that I have learned in these past five years!”

“Qiang, this is not the place for this!”

Before Zhang Dong could greet his old fight buddy, his wife placed herself between the two and started glaring.

“It’s fine, Liena.”

Before they could continue their comedic routine of shouting profanities at each other, he decided to grab his wife by her waist, pick her up and place her on the nearby chair to the side. The other Elders weren’t quite used to something like this, seeing their powerful Matriarch being handled like a child was not something they were expecting.

“Haha, that’s my senior brother!”

Huo Qiang was ecstatic after seeing his shouting partner being put in her place. It totally evaded him that Zhang Dong was only doing it to keep both of them quiet but it was just easier to do it this way. If he wanted to shut Qiang up, he would probably have to give him a good thrashing in a spar. Then he would gain a few months of silence before the next challenge.

“Why you…”

“Okay everyone, quiet down, we have a lot of things to discuss!”

Before his wife could retaliate he forced his aura through the whole chamber. This caused his voice to travel everywhere as well as showing that his cultivation realm was the largest in this room. The moment he did it, he could see some of the elder’s faces dropping down but mostly from the Huo Clan side.

“As you might have heard… there has been a recent revelation concerning my true roots…”

“Yes, I would have never thought that you would turn up to be related to the Long clan, should we start calling you Long Dong now, Dong’er?”

Zhang Jin with his somewhat younger-looking face and more vital energy commented as most people here were already aware of the Golden Dragon title.

“That won’t be necessary, I will always be part of the Zhang Clan.”

The elders started murmuring with each other at his declaration. Normally a cultivator would quickly abandon their family name to join such a prestigious clan. They didn’t actually know that the only reason that their Patriarch didn’t was because of the naming.

“I would wish to discuss the plans for the future, as some of you might know, a war is awaiting us…”

While some of the inner circle elders knew about everything, there were still a lot of them that didn’t know what was happening. Zhang Dong quickly explained about the coming century-long war that would turn the empire upside down.

At first he thought that they would be scared and try to run, but he had underestimated these cultivation nuts. Instead of fleeing, they seemed interested in the lands beyond the borders. The more he explained the more they were convinced to join the war effort and get stronger.

“I say that we just wait here, there is no reason for us to fear these ‘empires’, our sect is strong and now we even have the protection of the Azure Emperor himself, there is nothing we have to fear!”

Surprisingly Huo Qiang’s father spoke up in favor of the war. Most of the elders nodded at this point as everyone felt confident in their power. It did help that quite a bit of them went through a drastic change.

After Wang Long’s attack, he did boost them to new heights at the cost of most of his spirit stones and remaining spirit stones that the sect had. They would probably need to restock on those before attempting something similar but with him there, they were even more confident.

“I guess you all have made up your mind?”

The discussion didn’t even take more than an hour as everyone was in favor of fighting. They also wanted to expand their lands after the fact that they were so strong. They wanted to take back the lands that previously belonged to the Dark Palm Sect. With no fear of retaliation from the two sects that were occupying this land, they were resolute in taking it back.

“I to wish to reclaim that land, Qiang, could you take a couple of our ascended brothers there and ask them to return the lands that we should have received?”
Even he believed that they should have been given those lands. The ones that killed the Patriarch were them and not the other sects. They weren’t even given a speck from their treasure room, they were only left scraps that the other three sects didn’t want.

“Now you are speaking my language brother!”

“Wait, Zhang Zhi keep Huo Qiang company, make sure that he doesn’t go overboard, I don’t want a bloodbath to happen.”

Before Huo Qiang could leave Zhi was given an order to be a chaperone. They would also first send quick letters to notify that the other sects needed to leave the lands. But to be sure that they left most of their treasuries behind, he needed to send a proper battle-ready force of nascent soul masters along with the declaration.

“As you command Patriarch!”

Their United Element Sect was now a force to be reckoned with. The number of nascent soul masters that they had was staggering and if they managed to get their hands on a few spirit stone mines, it would only increase further.

“Before the Heavenly Crane Sect can move in, we need to claim some of the lands that used to belong to the Soaring Dragon Sect.”

This was another big issue, what would become of all those resources. Their sect was also run by the Soaring Dragon Sect that was not there anymore. What would normally happen in this situation would be that the next strongest sect would get it all. This would be the Heavenly Crane Sect along with the Long Clan, but now they were in the conversation too.

While their real strength was yet unknown, they had some accolades that would make people think twice before they attacked them. The first one was them defending themselves against Wang Long that later managed to eradicate his own sect. The next was that their Patriarch was Long Dong, the sworn blood-brother of the Azure Emperor.

Just by being associated with the Emperor, their Sect would gain prestige at the same level as the big three powerhouses. While Zhang Dong didn’t intend to manage all of that land, he would still like to receive the taxes in the form of spirit stones from these lands.

‘I won’t even need to rob those spirit stone mines, they will send everything to me but I have to be fast about it…’

Thus it was time to formulate a plan of action. They had many nascent soul masters to carry out this task. He just needed to send them in small groups of at least three to show off their might.

“Everyone listen up, we can’t waste any more time, we must get control of the most important lands, I need you to list the places with the largest spirit stone mines to me, we will start with those!”

It was time to act, there was no way of knowing when this war would start. Wang Long was also waiting for him in the shadows, while his sect worked on taking over the other sects he would visit the Soaring Dragon Sect or at least what remained of it...

Chapter 419

“You can’t do this, we need to discuss it with the elders...”

“Oh? Who is going to stop us? We can discuss everything with these!”

A rather imposing-looking muscle-brained cultivator with red hair was hovering in the air along with three other ten nascent soul masters. All of them were hovering over what used to be the Dark Palm Sect main sect. Around them were many peeks which were producing a certain light.

“If you think that your protective formation will last for long, you are mistaken.”

Besides The ten nascent soul masters, there were also some large ships hovering in the air. These ships were smaller versions of the Argonaut but were not much behind it. The whole area was surrounded and the protective formation that was pulsating with energy would not last for more than a day.

“Elder Qiang, please calm down, the Patriarch has ordered us to offer them a branch before we act.”

“So that’s why he told you to come here…”

Huo Qiang looked to the side where Zhang Zhi was floating about. The man was respected by him as he was probably the fourth-strongest person in the entire sect. His choice of weapon was a strange single-edged blade that Qiang would find hard to evade.

“If elder Qiang would allow me to speak.”

Qiang just shrugged and flew back while Zhang Zhi took center stage. He soon opened his mouth and with the help of spiritual energy made his voice echo through the whole area.

“Fellow Daoists from the Yinglong Pavilion, we have come to claim what was rightfully ours. Years have passed since our Patriarch had defeated the Dark Palm Sect’s leader, we are grateful that you have temporarily kept watch over the lands that rightfully belong to our United Element Sect. Now as our Patriarch has ascended to his rightful place at the side of the Azure Emperor you can relinquish this burden back to us…”

Zhang Zhi continued to talk and painted a nice picture for this Yinglong Pavilion that had remained here in the main city. This was one of the three sects that had cannibalized these lands.

After the debacle with the Limitless Sword Society that lost their leader after Zhang Dong slew him, they together with the Dragon Gate Sect moved in to distribute most of the lands between themselves. This was the center of their power base here though and rich with treasures.

Zhang Dong ordered a swift occupation by force but not like he wanted to become some kind of bloody despot. He would let everyone keep their lives and some of the treasures if they just packed up their bags and left. Zhang Zhi’s words just let the other sect keep some face as it made it look as they were just safekeeping the place for Zhang Dong from the beginning.

Now that it was known that he was the golden dragon and at a similar standing as the Azure Emperor, there was no shame in bowing their heads before him. It would actually make it look like this Yinglong Pavilion was in cahoots with the United Element Sect which would make the other sects fearful of them.

“Ah yes… that’s right, we were only safekeeping the treasures for the honorable Golden Dragon, the brother of our honored Azure Emperor!”

After some back and forth the elders finally capitulated. There was just no way that they could go against a force this big without any backup. The cultivators from the United Element Sect could also teleport people onto their ships, even Zhang Dong could appear to eradicate them.

There was enough information to back up the rise in power of this sect. Everyone also watched the royal broadcast which could not be faked. What remained was to hope that they would at least keep their lives.

….

“I see, good going Zhi, prioritize spirit stones and other treasures that store spiritual energy over weapons.”

“As you wish, Patriarch!”

Zhang Dong ended the call with his most trusted warrior. He wanted to make sure that his sect got all the spirit stones they could get their hands on. Anything that could store other types of elemental Qi was also important. He still had to boost his three formation cores to nourish this white seed of his. As it continued to grow, so did he, and his maximum power expanded further.

“Everything is going as planned, Liena is clearing things out at the borders, if everything goes well we can siphon the spirit stone tax towards our sect instead of the Heavenly Crane.”

After nodding he took off towards his next destination to which he was going solo. The war was approaching but Wang Long was the more important target. His enemy was a murder-happy individual that saw these people as nothing more than points to further his cause.

Luckily Zhang Dong was knowledgeable about the system Wang Long was using. There was a large change in spirit point gaining after getting closer to the nascent soul level. Wang Long would find it really hard to gain anything from low level cultivators, even core formation masters would probably be giving him meager gains now.

This was probably in place to encourage the system holder to go after stronger opponents closer to their own level. Farming points by killing mortals and low level cultivators would probably give fewer points than killing one nascent soul master.

‘I hope that’s the case… but not like I ever tried killing any of the non-combatants.’

He could mostly just speculate as he never went through a massive killing spree. The system could have some kind of feature that could still absorb the energy from a massive massacre. Before any of that happened he needed to get to Wang Long, while his sect brothers were getting more resources he was flying towards ground zero.

‘It sure is fun to be free like this…’

With his current cultivation, he could fly at the speed of a great circle nascent soul master and the best thing was, that no one would stop him. As he rocketed through the various border regions of the other sects everyone just bowed their heads. The word had already spread and his golden dragon status had given him enough prestige to almost go anywhere.

Yes, almost as when he arrived closer to what used to be the main area that was occupied by the Soaring Dragon Sect he found his first barrier.

‘Someone placed a barrier here?’

It was a literal barrier made from energy behind him; he could see some dark clouds gathering everywhere. The zone of demonic energy was further inside and this formation was certainly keeping it from spreading outside.

“Halt, Identify yourself!”

A small group of cultivators approached him, one of them was a nascent soul master at the middle stage and he had about ten core formation cultivators with him to boot. The robes that they were wearing was something he had seen before.

They belonged to the Heavenly Crane Sect that now after the Soaring Dragon Sect’s demise was crowned the number two power in this empire. While the smaller and middle sized sects would push open their door for his new status, this sect was a bit different. They saw themselves at the same level as the Long Clan.

“Oh? Do I really need to introduce myself, I did proclaim that I would search out the one named Wang Long, did you perhaps miss my inauguration speech, junior?”

The man he was talking with was actually many times older but his cultivation would be considered lower. Zhang Dong was now the Golden Dragon so he needed to act like one. While this elder was probably held in high regard in his own sect, Zhang Dong did not really need to answer to anyone besides their high elders or Patriarch.

“Y-you dare? J-junior…”

The old man was taken aback by how he was speaking but before he could react one of the core formation cultivators next to him quickly whispered something into his ear.

“This is… I must apologize but I didn’t expect someone of your status to arrive at this forsaken land.”

He quickly changed his tune and clasped his hand while performing a small bow. All the other people that were here did the same.

“But why would the esteemed Long Dong the Golden Dragon grace us with his presence?”

“Ah yes, I need to get there, so could you lower this formation for a moment, I wouldn’t want to destroy it.”

Zhang Dong smiled a bit while pointing towards the lands that previously were populated by many other cultivators. The dark smoke that covered the area was making it hard to see anything so he would need to get closer to examine it further.

“You wish to go past the formation… but the Supreme Elders…”

The man moved his head to the side as it seemed that he was in some trouble. The Supreme Elders that he mentioned probably ordered him to keep everyone out. They probably didn’t foresee that Zhang Dong would arrive here so fast after he made that speech. They might have counted on him to just be all hot air and not follow through his claims but now he was here.

“Don’t worry about your Supreme Elders, If I see them I’ll put in a good word for you.”

“But that wouldn’t really…”

“No need to thank me, now please, I don’t have all day, the more we wait here the more potential victims could appear, I must examine this demonic presence that lurks inside.”

He knew well that there was a lot of peacocking involved in situations like this. The two parties were not against each other as they were in a truce. They still had their boundaries and them letting him just pass here would be a slight hit to their face.

“Could you please wait honored Golden Dragon, I will inform a Supreme Elder and ask for permission this instant…”

“Ah, that’s troubling indeed… you see, the more we wait, the longer the madman remains in the empire. If you aren’t willing to let me pass, I will have to be somewhat reasonable…”

As he spoke the other cultivators could feel a progressive increase in his power levels. While at first he seemed to be someone at the core formation level, his power exploded well past the nascent soul master that was here.

“Senior please…”

“I’m sorry but you have prattled on long enough.”

Without giving these people any more time he bolted towards the protective formation. Due to his formation master knowledge, it was not hard to find an adequate spot to just slip through. A small Zhang Dong sized hole was left behind but with a wave of his hand, he mended it in an instant.

“Well then, I’ll be seeing you my fellow Daoists.”

The group of cultivators just looked on as Zhang Dong blasted into the distance and quickly vanished into the dark miasma. On their minds was only the scolding that they would receive for not being able to stop this madman from going into a deadly zone filled with malicious beings.

Chapter 420

“He really did a number on these people, there is nothing left…”

Like a light bug going through a dense dark bog, Zhang Dong continued to fly towards the center of this disaster. Dark Miasma was everywhere, it blocked out the sun and made the air toxic. If he didn’t have his holy aura around his body, his clothes would start to dissolve.

The lack of fresh breathable air was also a problem, luckily he knew a technique to purify it as he went through the area. It was an old one that almost any demon hunter knew, the days as his persona flowed back into his head as he tried to compare this area to some of the demonic outbreaks he had inspected in the past.

‘I have never went through demonic Qi this thick before, it must be feeding on the spirits of the dead… their souls are crying out in rage…’

Souls were very much a reality in this world and depending on how a person died they could turn into decrepit souls of the dead. These souls were skewed reflections of their former selves. They had jumbled memories of their lives but mostly what they focused was on the moment of death.

The demonic techniques would only enhance the rage in these souls and would help them be created. These phantoms would be formed in places of massacres and could cause harm to regular people that did not know how to protect their own souls.

These decrepit souls were broken, thus they longed to be whole again. There was only one thing that they desired and that was to eat the soul energy of others. If they gained enough they could even gain sentience yet again. They would turn into powerful demonic creatures with a proper form, even humanoid ones that just lusted for more soul energy.

“Here they come…”

For someone of his level of cultivation, it was not hard to pick up these demonic souls. Some of them looked like purple wills of wisps with human faces on them, while others had already consumed each other to form some larger horrors.

Luckily Zhang Dong had a lot of practice against foes like this. They were just the type of being that he could easily dispatch just by absorbing their energies with the help of his soul core.

As he stopped a glowing orb in the middle of his chest appeared. It started spinning around to create a vortex of energy that started pulling the souls into it. Unless these decrepit souls managed to turn into proper demonic beings, he could just siphon them dry.

At the Long Clan, he was able to gain a lot of holy energy and a new technique. Here on the other hand he could increase the size of his soul core. Even though he was making good progress it didn’t bring him much joy.

Many people died here, millions of lives had been lost just because Wang Long wanted more power. In a sense, it was his fault as if he never pushed his enemy's buttons he would probably not find himself backed into a corner.

At the time he didn’t know though nor did he predict that the maniac would go through something like this. His main goal was to protect his own sect and family. It was regrettable but he already made peace with himself that he wouldn’t be able to save everyone.

Thus any of the decrepit souls were absorbed into his body. This was only residual soul energy, the person it belonged to was already dead and had probably entered the reincarnation path.

At least that was what the people of this world believed in, what actually happened to the dead he was unsure. With beings able to pull his soul into a world like this, he wouldn’t be surprised if there were more than one answer.

‘There are a lot of them… I must be getting close to ground zero.’

The further he flew the more of these souls came out of the woodworks. They were all promptly absorbed by his soul core which slowly gained more power.

Finally, he arrived at a large gate, or at least what was left of it. The symbols for the Soaring Dragon Sect were there, cracked and hard to read. When he arrived there he also started hearing strange wails which didn’t sound like the souls.

“Zombies?”

The living dead were quickly drawn to the light that he was producing. In the miasma, he could see ugly creatures that inhabited dead human corpses. The decrepit souls invaded these shells to create monsters that now wandered these lands.

‘How many of them are there…’

Zhang Dong didn’t expect to see this many monsters here. He expected to see some kind of ruin covered by miasma, instead, he saw jumbled-up messes of flesh wandering the streets. They were quite strange, not that familiar to regular zombies, they were much thinner. It was as if they were sucked dry by something before turning to nothing but skin and bones.

‘It could have been some kind of absorption technique…’

This was his best guess, Zhang Dong could absorb various energies like lightning. This could be the same for Wang Long that had switched to a demonic cultivator. These techniques focused on robbing people of their life force and transferring it to the demonic cultivator.

It wasn’t surprising that his opponent went with a technique like that, it would give him a lot of power fast. This world was filled with life, this Empire was many times larger than the planet that he had come from. He would be surprised if there were a trillion people living here as there were many cities that housed a hundred million residents.

While the miasma was thick, Zhang Dong could peer through it if he concentrated. Thus he used his spiritual sense to scour the land in all directions and only discovered more destruction and death.

It had not been long since this place was destroyed; it didn't seem that even the Heavenly Crane Sect had checked things out here. The people that were patrolling were probably temporary guards. He wouldn’t be surprised if they rushed a team of higher cultivators after he appeared there.

They were probably looking into the demonic energies and hoping to get to the potential Soaring Dragon Sect stash later. But he knew that his opponent Wang Long would probably have lifted anything worthwhile like spirit stones.

‘He was only the grandson of the Patriarch, this doesn’t mean that he knew every hidden treasure that some of the other elders could have kept hidden away, there could be places hidden away that he didn’t get to...also…’

Zhang Dong thought that there could be potential survivors. Judging how untrusting most of the high leveled cultivators were, it wouldn’t be strange for them to create something akin to a secret lair. In those hidden away places, there still could be people, some family members of those elders that could have run there.

‘I need to do something about this miasma… it's screwing up my sensors… but first, Bob scan the area, this demonic energy should have Wang Long’s handprints all over them, create an energy profile for him!’

“Affirmative.’

After getting Bob it felt like he had a chip inside of his brain. With his help, he could do some things that went over the old system. What he now needed to do was to fly around and gather more data, this took him to a large hole that was too uniform to not have been created by some kind of explosion.

The demonic energies were the strongest here, dark lightning and poisonous rain filled the hole that was at least five kilometers in diameter. He could feel an opposing energy to the demonic one that has not yet vanished.

‘Was this the last confrontation… this energy probably belonged to a great circle nascent soul master… maybe the sect Patriarch?’

He tried looking around to find a body but there was nothing but empty space here. Some terrible technique went off here that disintegrated everything in a wide radius. It was as if someone scooped the earth out of here.

‘Energy signature of target stored in the database.’

As he was looking around he heard Bob finish up on the scan. A new tracking option in his system appeared with Wang Long’s icon.
Out of curiosity, he activated the new feature but he quickly turned it off. This was due to the whole area turning red the moment he gave it a test run. The whole space was filled with Wang Long’s evil energies, it was normal for the system to pick color everything red.

‘I got what I came for, but I can’t just leave this place like this…’

It was time to clean things up. With Wang Long's energy fingerprint in his database, he could start the hunt. Before that could happen he needed to clear out this demonic energy that was messing with his detective work.

Zhang Dong placed his palms together and he started to concentrate. A burst of holy energy erupted from his body, it spread in every direction while he remained in the epicenter of this wide-open chasm.

‘First, let me get all of these decrepit souls before I continue.’

Without opening his eyes he created a large vortex that radiated pure life energy. The beckoning effect on these life force-hungry souls would be immense. In no time, a swarm of them appeared from all sides.

It was like a tsunami of soul energy coming his way but instead of washing him away, they were sucked into the vortex where his soul core was waiting for them. They were all sucked in while the other creatures like the zombies and lesser flesh demons could not reach him so far up in the air.

The souls that grabbed ahold of the human bodies could not be absorbed. If the decrepit soul bonded with the flesh too much then purifying it would be the only way. Only creatures that kept most of their soul form would be ripe for absorption.

….

“What is the meaning of this, couldn’t you have held him up for a few hours?”

“My apologies but he just jumped in through the formation, it was like paper to him…”

The elder that Zhang Dong met before he entered the tainted land was now being chewed up by another old man. There was a whole large force of nascent soul masters here now, it was clear that they came to investigate the inside of the formation but were a bit too late.

“E-elder…”

As the leader was shouting he heard someone call to him. When he was about to reprimand this junior he noticed it as well. Inside of the formation, there was some kind of strange light shining through the miasma.

“W-what is that?”

All of them had to cover their eyes as the glow only intensified and spread all the way towards the edges of the formation. Soon they witnessed a power they would never forget…

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 421

“How could this be?”

“The demonic mist, it has all vanished… look elders… the demonic creatures, they are dying…”

Cultivators from the Heavenly Crane Sect looked on from behind the protective formation as the golden light subsided. When it did, they could see the old landscape and the creatures that roamed it. Now without the demonic Qi swiveling around, they were succumbing to the holy Qi instead.

“This strange spiritual energy… it really was the Golden Dragon…”

The elder that arrived after Zhang Dong’s appearance was now scratching his long beard. At first, he didn’t believe his junior and thought that the man that went inside must have been an impostor. Now, on the other hand, he wasn’t that sure.

“This complicates things, the blasted Azure Emperor probably sent him here to clear out the sect and take all the knowledge and treasures for himself, this won’t do, we must investigate!”

“But Senior…”

One of the other nascent soul elders called out but the main elder just raised his hand.

“I know, we will not engage in anything stupid as a battle with the Emperor’s sworn brother, this doesn’t mean that we will relinquish all of the knowledge and treasures that was left over by the Soaring Dragon sect, he is but one man, even if its the Golden Dragon he can not possibly go through something as large as the Soaring Dragon Sect.”

“Ah, Senior is wise!”

Everyone started nodding at each other. It seemed that the Golden Dragon did most of the work for them. The miasma was gone and the monsters inside were dying. They were human cultivators so the holy energy inside would not hurt them, it would be the opposite it would actually invigorate them instead.

“My brothers, it has not been long since the one called the Golden Dragon came here. This grand purifying magics that he has used has probably drained him of most of his Qi. While he rests we will come and take the treasures for ourselves yet, if you meet this Emperor’s Brother do not engage him in battle, even if he is weakened we don’t know the true extent of his might!”

After the announcement, the group of nascent soul masters pushed beyond the protective formation. There were five of them and along with about two hundred core formation experts they made up quite the large battle force.

With so many people on their side, they hoped to quickly go through the rubble and take some of the Soaring Dragon Sect’s secrets with them. Manufacturing techniques of fabled artifacts, pill formulae, and maybe even some hidden techniques that they could make their own.

…

“Whew… that took more out of me than I thought, good that I absorbed all of those dead souls beforehand…”

Zhang Dong was floating up in the air while looking at a giant hole in the ground. Now that the miasma was gone he could see the entire sect or at least what was left of it.

The hole in the ground was truly deep and even with the thick mist gone, it was hard to see the bottom. It made it seem that the explosion was in the shape of a column instead of one that went equally in all directions.

‘It’s as if it was stuck in a different dimension or something…’

While gathering his strength he started looking around. His system map was brought up as he was interested if he would be able to see a blacked-out spot. Regretfully he didn't, which told him that there was no dimensional cube here.

It seemed that Wang Long was not directly transported here. From what little he knew, Wang Long had started out as a young master but not one that was favored over the other ones quite yet. Only after he took the spot of his character and used the system did he start rising in the ranks. Thus it was possible that his arrival spot was at some branch city.

He achieved what he came for, Wang Long’s energy signature was implanted in his system. Before leaving though he took up the lotus position and started spreading his spiritual sense in all directions. This would help him check if there was something that he had missed and also allow him to rest momentarily.

‘I seem to have some visitors in the distance… still have some time until they arrive.’

The first thing he noticed was the large energy signatures that were coming from the direction that he arrived. It was clear to him that the cultivators from the other sect were here to check things out. The Heavenly Crane sect was somewhat on the same standing as the Long Clan, so he would not be able to talk them down with his newfound status.

‘...This is…’

While searching for possible pockets of spirit stones he discovered something else. A faint life signal that was quite hard to make out. When he prodded more and double-checked with his system map it was clear that there were survivors there.

Without thinking much about it, Zhang Dong popped a few recovery pills that he took from his sect and descended towards that area. Where there were people there could be some treasures but also maybe other answers to where Wang Long had gone.

A golden light surrounded his whole form and quickly changed to a drill. This allowed him to burrow underground to reach an open cavern.

“These walls are thick, did Wang Long failed to discover the people hiding inside, or did he just not care anymore?”

Zhang Dong mumbled while walking towards the area where he felt the faint life signal. This whole place was surrounded by several formations that made discovering anything with spiritual sense difficult. If he didn’t reach a new level with his cultivation he might have not been able to discover anything.

“This looks like… a vault?”

When he arrived the first thing before his eyes was a large circular slab of metal. It looked like a huge door to a vault. The walls had many characters and runes on them, the whole place was quite intricate and created from resistant metals.

“It looks quite sturdy but there is some damage here…”

After his little holy nova that covered the entire city, almost all of the creatures were eradicated. Even the ones that were previously in this corridor but before he came here they were still probably banging on this large door.

“It seems that the creatures that were outside were able to destroy parts of the mechanism, even if the people that were inside wanted to, they would not be able to come outside a strange design indeed”

At first, he thought that this might have been some kind of panic room, but one that locked people inside lacked reason. It was as if this was designed to lock itself if anyone used force from the outside. This gave him an idea that instead of a panic room, this was some kind of treasury.

“Let’s see… this should do it…”

Zhang Dong looked around and with a wave of his finger produced some spiritual energy. This energy combined with the damaged materials on the ground which started to float into the air. Soon the broken parts that were dislodged from the walls were being pieced together.

The scratches and bite marks were obviously created by the monsters that previously filled this tunnel. After his arrival, they all had turned to ash and even when they were this deep underground they succumbed to the massive holy energy output that he was able to produce now.

Even with his expertise, it wasn’t that easy to piece this thing together, he even had to use some of his own crafting materials as the spirit runes were too damaged. But he was still able to repair this mechanism and with one last wave of his hand, the large vault-like door was now opening.

‘This is…’

“W-who goes there!”

Not much time had passed since this whole disaster struck this sect, so he did not expect to see any malnourished survivors. When he opened up the thick door he discovered various people inside but most of them were women and children. A group of them were now holding various bladed weapons and pointing them at him.

“Lower your weapons, I am not here to hurt you.”

Even when he called out to them in a gentle voice it didn’t calm their nerves. It seemed that they were stuck in this reinforced prison without any way of knowing what was happening outside. Probably as Wang Long was destroying the sect, the women and children were rushed here.

“Please calm down.”

He could only repeat himself while floating forward, this indicated his level of power somewhat as no core formation cultivator was able to fly. When he glanced again he counted about fifty people, the strongest of them was an older woman at the nascent soul level; she looked quite tired and also injured. Even then she remained at the front with a large glaive in her hands.

It was clear that they didn’t trust him at all, who would? He was some kind of unknown person walking in after they spent weeks being locked away. While this tightly locked vault could keep the monsters and decrepit souls away, it probably didn’t dampen the sounds that much. Having to listen to the wails of undead creatures outside was probably not something he would want to sleep to.

While he was trying to calm the women down he took some time to look around. The inside of this vault was well lit and some of it was clearly shifted around. But the main reason behind this vault was obvious, books filled with knowledge and various weapons were everywhere.

‘It really was some kind of treasure vault, probably belonging to another elder… maybe this granny?’

It didn’t seem that the people here were very trusting of him, which wasn’t much of a problem. If he was in their shoes, a strange good looking cultivator that appeared out of thin air would look like a trick an enemy would play.

Luckily for Zhang Dong he didn’t need to be very political here. If he showed his overwhelming might and that they had no chance against him anyway, they would have to calm down. Thus he lit up the place with his overwhelming holy aura to show that he was not someone that needed them to stand down. No, even if they resisted they would have no chance against him.

“Now let’s all calm down and put away those weapons.”

The nascent soul granny found herself unable to move and the large two-handed glaive fell out of her hand. Everyone quickly realized that they were at the mercy of the person that just appeared but for some reason, they felt that he was not someone that they should fear.

“Good that’s better, now… I want to ask you a couple of questions if that’s fine with you?”

Chapter 422

Zhang Dong nodded to the old lady that had calmed down a bit after he entered the chamber they had locked themselves in. These people were still from the Soaring Dragon Sect, the information that he gave them was hard to swallow. It was understandable as finding out that their sect that was at the top of the whole world, had ceased to exist.

“Elder, this man has to be lying, how could our sect fall? This doesn’t make sense, we need to leave and get more information.”

One of the younger ladies here looked at him with anger in her eyes. It was clear that the juniors didn’t believe him but the nascent soul granny that was here did. When he opened up this vault he felt her spiritual sense bursting through it. She probably scanned the entire area outside and already knew that the whole place had been destroyed.

“Be quiet, what this man says is probably the truth…”

“But grandmother…”

The lady that was questioning his words referred to the granny quite closely. They were clearly related but not like he had time for pleasantries.

‘Bob, scan all the books in the area.’

With his increase in cultivation, some of Bob’s features were enhanced. Now he did not need to do it by hand or focus either, his Ai could just absorb all of the techniques that were in this room by himself. While there were various heaven grade texts here, they didn’t really add that much to his knowledge.

A few new pills here and there along with variations of preexisting battle arts. After already going through so many libraries with knowledge Zhang Dong noticed certain patterns in the skills. As long as a person was versed in the various elemental Dao’s they could add that knowledge to other techniques to get the same effects.

A palm that produced a smoldering inferno could now be easily altered to cause a frost nova instead. While it was easy to him, to a regular cultivator from this world it would be unfathomable. But as his knowledge grew so did his Dao’s of the elements in which he was now over 50% in all of them.

Even the Dao of dark energy was something that he could make his own, he just chose not to go into it too much as it clashed with his holy attribute. While he could freely study opposing elements like fire and water, this wasn’t quite the same for holy and dark. These elements were highly repulsed by each other.

If he had a small amount of dark energy in his body and activated his holy techniques. The light would feed away on the darkness until there was no Qi left. It was really hard to isolate these two energies and even keeping them close to each other could cause a massive backlash of untold proportions.

“I won’t stand in your way, you may leave and search for the remnants of your sect if you wish for but I’ll be taking these if you don’t mind…”

While he had already absorbed the knowledge from this place, there were still items that he could use to further his own cultivation level. There were some stones and weapons with lightning elemental energy imbued into them which he could still absorb along with some other goodies.

He waved his hand and the items in question started shining before rising up into the air and slowly floating towards him. The young lady that was previously looking at him with slanted eyebrows looked quite enraged by this fact. Luckily before she could say anything her grandmother waved her hand to force her mouth down.

It seemed that the younger generation was quite sheltered here. They didn’t know that they were in no place to make any demands with him. If any other powerful cultivator than him was here, they could easily kill them or do other dastardly things. From their standpoint, they should be happy that he was just taking some of the treasures and not even examining their spatial rings.

“I’ll take my leave then, the area should be safe now.”

He did not have time to take care of these survivors. They were together with a nascent soul elder which should be enough to guarantee their safety. Even though the main Soaring Dragon compound was no more, this didn’t mean that the entire sect was now gone. There were some remnants here and there, also some branch sects that could take them in.

‘This granny would be able to form a sect of her own in the lower regions so they should be fine.’

Before leaving he decided to fly around the destroyed city once more. He managed to find one vault which meant that there could be more buried treasures here. While searching for more loot he felt the old woman leaving the shelter with her juniors. They did remain in one spot though as they were probably quite shocked to see that not much had been left.

The previous monsters that roamed the area were mostly burned up but some of their bodies were still evaporating as he was scanning the area. His search revealed a couple of pockets of hidden away troves which he promptly flew towards.

Spirit stones, magical talismans, and more books with techniques were discovered by him. This time around though, there were no other survivors so he decided to just pocket everything he could get his hands on. While most of this would be useless to him, the juniors from his own sect could use the materials for themselves.

For Zhang Dong at his current level going through a huge sect like this didn’t prove much of a problem. After about twenty minutes he had scavenged everything that possessed a spiritual signature. Anything that could be absorbed was instantly devoured while everything else would be given to his sect members. It was finally time to leave but before he could there was a small commotion.

“Elder Zixin, it has been a while. It is truly unfortunate what has happened to your Soaring Dragon Sect but don’t worry, we from the Heavenly Crane Sect will be glad to escort you out from here…”

In the distance, he spotted a large group of cultivators, some of them he recognized as the people that he met when entering this place. There were a lot more of them here now, they were also quick to intercept the women and children that were just looking for more survivors.

After going through here he was not feeling any other life energy. He was more than convinced that there weren’t any other survivors. The holy core that he had was very receptive to life signals and along with his system minimap, he was able to perform a thorough scan of the entire area. From the millions of people that lived here, the only survivors didn’t amount to a hundred.

“Elder Guanting, I will have to refuse your generous offer, we only wish to search for our sect members, there could be more survivors.”

“Elder Zixin… I’m afraid I will have to implore you to leave this to my sect brothers, we will perform the search instead then we will be glad to escort you out of this horrible area, our Heavenly Crane Sect will accept you with open arms…”

“...That won’t be needed, we will be fine there are some branch sects that we will stay at instead you don’t need to…”

The old man that was talking to the old woman seemed somewhat angered that he was getting talked back to. Before the old lady could finish talking he raised his aura which made her back off for the time being.

“I don’t think you understand the gravity of your situation… there is no Soaring Dragon Sect anymore, those branch families you speak off have no foot to stand on as they won’t be able to stand up against even the middle-sized sects, you will come with us!”

It didn’t seem that the old man from the Heavenly Crane Sect would take a no for an answer. He wasn’t sure what their intention was but this group of survivors was composed mostly of women and children. They might hold them hostage or have the urge to integrate them into their own forces.

They were all strong cultivators for their age, after signing a soul-binding contract they could become part of the Heavenly Crane Sect. They could also be sold off to their members as potential brides. It was quite the catch for that sect as they were getting free cultivators without having to invest any resources into them.

‘It doesn’t look good for them but should I really get involved…’

He had already wasted enough time here, the red trail of energy that he could follow now was there. But, he knew that if he left things like this it would bother him for the entire trip. Thus he decided to clear things up between these two parties as quickly as he could.
“Excuse me, is there a problem here?”

“Huh? What… where did you…”

The people only realized that Zhang Dong was here when he chose to. With some skills, it was possible to blend into the surrounding without radiating any spiritual energy. Now everyone was looking up at him while he was radiating a gentle light from above.

“Ah, the renowned Golden Dragon, my brothers have informed me about you fellow Daoist but whatever do you mean? I don’t see a problem anywhere.”

The leader replied while the core formation masters scattered to the sides while riding their flying swords. Only the nascent soul elders that were with him dared to stay, it was five against one but not as he cared.

“Oh really? Elder Zixin was it?”

“Ah yes.”

The old lady was a bit perplexed that Zhang Dong returned and appeared out of the blue. It was clear from how the Heavenly Crane Sect elders were acting, that he was not someone they could easily offend. In reality. he wasn’t that sure as his fame was quite recent so some of these cultivation nuts would probably still try to check him.

“Do you wish to return with these fine gentlemen to their sect, or would you rather just leave the city instead? I have taken care of the dark miasma so you shouldn’t have a problem getting out and about this protective formation… I don’t think it’s really needed anymore…”

He proclaimed while pointing his finger into the sky. There the dome-shaped barrier was still surrounding everything from all sides. This thing required a lot of spiritual energy and resources to create but it would be quite easy to turn off.

Before anyone could ask about the meaning behind his words a tiny orb of energy appeared in front of this index finger. This little dot quickly grew in size, bolts of golden energy and bright light surrounded it now as Zhang Dong charged up this attack.

“W-what is he doing… take cover!”

The nascent soul elders were quick to back away as they could feel an unreasonable amount of energy behind this finger attack. Even more, after a beam of bright light escaped from it and collided with part of the protective formation. As if it collided with glass this bright beam attack caused the barrier to break into many tiny pieces of spiritual filament that crumbled into dust soon after.

The resounding explosion caused a massive shockwave to hit the spot everyone was in. But while they had to brace themselves for it, the one performing the finger technique just floated there without a worry in his mind.

“There the way is clear, well then did you make a decision?”

He asked while smiling at the scared cultivators below him, the question was posed but the people here didn’t know if he would take no for an answer.

Chapter 424

“This isn’t going as well as I thought it would…”

“Oh, what was that oh honored senior?”

“Ah, nothing…”

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh after being stuck at another location. His goodwill was biting him in the behind once more as he was stuck healing more people along the way. He wasn’t sure if Wang Long was doing this on purpose but it was certainly working in making him lag behind.

After getting out of that large city he continued to follow the trail of red. While most of the time it was a straight line in one direction, sometimes Wang Long rested in various settlements. Just as with the first city, some locations were then corrupted with demonic energy. He didn’t outright flatten the large cities but there was always something for him to cleanse left behind.

It also seemed that his new enemy was using his skills all over the place. Sometimes he would find a trail of dead plants left behind Wang Long’s flight path. Other times there were large holes in mountains that were clearly attacked by him. They all radiated demonic Qi at various levels which showed that Wang Long’s proficiencies in the various techniques were all over the place.

He apparently had a hard time keeping the evil Qi from not affecting the area while also not being able to control it when performing attacks. This went all in line with what Zhang Dong thought. Wang Long was clearly over-relying on his own system, the key to his victory might be this as he took some time to practice his battle techniques after he lost the system store.

‘That is if I ever reach him in time… I think I know where that bastard is going, this complicates things…’

“I’ll bid you farewell then.”

The group of people bowed before him while Zhang Dong flew away. After healing some villagers that were affected by demonic miasma, he was on his way towards a certain desolate area. It was a famous lawless zone that he had heard about when he was performing bounty work as his demon hunter persona.

It was in the far northern reaches of the empire. From what he knew, the first one had to go past a wide desert filled with monstrous sandworms. It was devoid of all life and covered in faint demonic mist. Past it was a large body of water named the sea of death.

It apparently had many sea creatures lurking in the deep. The water in itself was poisonous to the touch and constantly radiating demonic Qi. It was mostly impossible to get through it without some kind of flying treasure. Any ship would just be pulled down into the deep by monstrous creatures.

Then when someone was finally able to pass through these two natural barriers they would arrive on a large island. This was the true land of the demonic cultivators, it wasn’t as big as the empire but would have enough space to house a few middle-sized sects.

It was of course in a constant perpetual war. The demonic cultivators weren’t very agreeable with each other, they constantly fought for the spot of the next Demon Emperor. But with how little trust there was, it was almost impossible. Without someone dominating them all with pure might, it wasn't feasible.

‘I guess I’m in luck… Wang Long is probably going to become the next Demon Emperor…’

While there weren’t any potential evil emperor candidates before, now they had a prime candidate coming their way. Wang Long’s achievement of clearing out the entire Soaring Dragon Sect was probably known by the people living there. Some of them would welcome him with open arms as their new leader but others would need to be convinced.

His counterpart would probably oblige with that. Killing every single demonic cultivator would not make him bat an eyebrow. The carnage might already be taking place as he flew there. This complicated things as Zhang Dong was losing one of his advantages, which was having an army.

While the demonic cultivators could not be trusted, there were ways to bind them. Evil contracts and rituals could secure their loyalty if Wang Long was smart enough to use them. With their lives on the lines, these monsters in human form would toss themselves into battle for their master. Unwilling as they might be, they would have no other choice.

During his travels he didn’t just space out, he was still involved with his sects business. With his system, he could reach out to his faction members like Zhang Zhi who were in the process of taking back some strategic locations.

“Is Huo Qiang giving you any problems?”

“Elder Qiang has managed to compose himself as his position required.”

“Oh? That’s surprising, I guess he had grown up somewhat since those five years ago.”

Zhang Dong reached out to his number one fan Zhang Zhi. He was informed that the Dark Palm Sect area had been liberated from the other sects. With the number of nascent soul masters and his new title, it seemed that the middle sized sects agreed to capitulate without putting up a fight.

Luckily the United Element Sect had a good reputation for being one of the better righteous sects in the Empire. The other sects actually somewhat believed that they wouldn’t get stabbed in the back when they lowered their protective formations.

“Good, be sure to occupy the spirit stone mines. I want them to be quickly mined out to the last spirit stone! Don’t forget to place at least one nascent soul master at that expedition ground.”

With the old Dark Palm Sect lands in their grasp now, he could revisit that secret ground again. He wasn’t sure if he would need to go through the test phase again but there were probably some secrets remaining there that were worth looking into. His sect had enough people to easily go through those tower defense stages now he believed that they would be able to get through it with minimal casualties.

After he ended the call with Zhi he continued with his chase, even though he knew where his opponent was going now this didn’t mean that he didn’t decide to go elsewhere. Maybe if he was lucky he could get to Wang Long before he vanished into the dark criminally underbelly of the empire. Tracking his demonic Qi in that sea of evil energy would also be harder even with the help of the system.

But the journey there was long and even with his top speed, he would need another week to reach the border. So his journey continued and with it more affected people that Wang Long had gone through. With the constant slowdowns, a few more days were added to his journey.

Finally, he was now at the last large settlement closest to the demonic lands. This area was ruled by one of the more morally ambiguous sects. It wasn’t that evil sects were banned from existing on the entire continent, only when they gorged themselves too much on the evil arts were there actually problematic.

“Wait honored Golden Dragon let us guide you to the evil lands!”

Just like with the other places this one was somewhat affected by Wang Long’s evil Qi. After such a long journey Zhang Dong was feeling somewhat tired. Even though at his level he didn’t need to sleep at all, the stress from the impending doom was getting to him. At the question of one of the cultivators he just nodded, with them in tow he headed for what was supposed to be the entrance to the land ruled by evil and corruption, the Eternal Dark.

He wasn’t really sure about this small group of cultivators that were coming with him, but they were probably just trying to kiss his behind as always. To them, the brother of the Azure Emperor was a nice ticket into a higher position. Regretfully for them, Zhang Dong had no time for politics. While they were talking he just continued to mumble and nod while just looking at his system screen and preparing for the coming battles.

“So, this is the desert?”

Finally, after some time had passed they arrived at the first barrier, the desert.

“Yes my lord, this is the Evil Desert of the Damned, various demonic beasts and spirits wonder about these dead lands. Are you sure you wish to go beyond it?”

“Evil spirits? That won’t be a problem… but what’s that…”

While looking at the vast empty land that was covered with sand and storms, he spotted something. At first he thought it was just a regular storm but it looked somewhat strange by how it remained stationary.

“Does the senior need an explanation?”

One of the random cultivators that he picked up along the way asked him after seeing Zhang Dong starte into the distance. With a nod of confirmation, the man continued to speak.

“The maps aren’t very detailed but this place is very close to the northern edge of the empire. That torrent of dark energy in the distance is the great divide, no one knows what is beyond it but some speculate that it’s just another zone created by the evil cultivators.”

The man continued with the explanation but Zghang Dong knew well what was behind this wall of energy. One of the other empires was there but for now, they remained behind the barrier. Wang Long had taken one of the more roundabout paths towards his destination as he needed to go to the northeast if he wanted to reach his true destination now.

“I will take my leave then, you can go.”

He didn’t really have time to thank these people, he already cured some of their own so he didn’t feel like he owed them anything. The people just bowed while slowly floating back but as he was about to plunge himself into the desert he felt something.

His eyes were drawn back to the barrier between the empires. It wasn’t much but he felt a decrease in spiritual energy and the storms filled with a mish-mash of elemental energies started to die down.

“No… it couldn’t be…”

This didn’t look good but he thought that there was more time. To check he opened up his system map to look for something. His visit to the Azure Emperor gave him knowledge of the spots where some of the bridges should appear. He quickly overlayed these spots against his map and to his dismay this was one of the locations where a link between Empires was supposed to be formed.

“What is that… this has never happened before…”

The small group of cultivators that were with him spotted the change in the storms as well. The wall of energy that would even mangle up a nascent soul master started to subside. It was as if the sea of energy was parting in the middle to create a path.

“Shit… I can feel something… it's approaching.”

He looked at the group of people that was with him, they were still staring at the phenomenon taking place. Zhang Dong on the other hand knew that there was a potential war battle ahead of him. Thus he checked his spatial ring and brought out his sword which he placed on his hip for now, first he needed to see, maybe if he was lucky these invaders wouldn't be bloodthirsty.

Chapter 425

‘Are those people? They look kind of off…’

Zhang Dong was forced to wait as the chaotic storms of elemental energies slowly cleared out. The path that was left was about one kilometer in width. When he strained his eyes he could see some strange flying objects coming his way, it was clear that one of the bridges between the empires had opened up.

‘Is this the first one… or are there more appearing now?’

He had no way of checking for this information, probably the only one that could answer his question was the Azure Emperor. They did possess a magical map of the entire empire in that one secret location. While the Long Clan was added as a side faction, the people there didn’t trust him enough for him to communicate with them.

The only person with an approval rating over 50% was the Azure Emperor. But even he had clear doubts with Zhang Dong, their relationship had just started which was understandable. Even between family members, the number would mostly cap out at 60%.

Even with his enhanced vision, he had trouble picking out their forms but then, he finally saw them. From afar they looked like normal humanoids but then the large teeth became apparent.

The person that he spotted was about two meters in height and his skin was dark yellow. His hands were covered in wraps and he was wearing something similar to a tank top shirt. Thanks to this he could see the exposed bone spikes that were coming out of his arms.

Then there was the face, the man had no hair at all instead there were some kind of strange dark bumps. His mouth even when not opened showed off a large amount of sharp yellow teeth that grind against each other constantly. It didn’t seem that this person was quite able to close it as the abundance of teeth made it impossible.

‘Is it some kind of demonic cultivator? I can’t sense any evil energy from them… it feels more like Dao of earth.’

There were other humanoids of this kind there that varied in appearance somehow. They all lacked hair and had those spiky bone appendages protruding from their bodies. He even spotted some that had a more feminine shape but still had no hair on their body. The closer they got the more they radiated earthen energy and the skin looked dried up and leathery.

“W-what is that? Why are those people coming from beyond the wall? Quickly send a message to the sect, we might be under attack!”

The people from the sect that he came from finally noticed that there was someone moving through this parted storm. From Zhang Dong’s perspective, their sect would probably take the brunt of this attack and by the energies, some of these attackers were radiating, it wouldn’t be easy to defend.

The flying objects that they came from varied. Some ships were clearly made from bones of beasts while other were actually living ones. There was one in particular that stood out, a large flying worm that had some kind of strange building on its back. This creature radiated might at the level of a nascent soul cultivator and there were more coming from that building.

‘They don’t look like the type that would be willing to talk things out, but I shouldn’t judge a book by its cover…’

Zhang Dong was willing to give these people the benefit of the doubt. Though they might look like monsters out of a horror movie, it might have just been due to how their part of the empire was created. Maybe there were other ways to go about this war, there was no rule that he needed to defeat every empire.

Some could be willing to work things out and not shed the blood of others. The cultivator types were motivated by resources that were all finite. If there was a way to share some of them to evade conflict then he was willing to haggle a bit.

Regretfully it would quickly become apparent that at least this group wasn’t willing to talk. While he was waiting for them to get closer the people from the sect that escorted him here made a break for it.

They could clearly feel the pressure that some of the beings here were giving off and decided that fleeing was the best option for survival. Contacting their sect was one thing but surviving this was another. They didn’t even look Zhang Dong’s way when they decided on this as he was clearly only an outsider.

But the people that were approaching from this bridge between empires were quick to notice this. The person that he noticed at the front turned his head towards the group of fleeing cultivators.

He moved his hand towards his own shoulder and quickly yanked out one of those spikes that was sticking out. This bone spike increased in size in a matter of moments and soon it was clear to Zhang Dong what he was about to do.

The toothy person then took out a spear-throwing position. The right arm that he was holding this bone spear with started getting bigger. His muscles bulged out to strange proportions before he launched this projectile towards the fleeing group of cultivators.

Once thrown the bone spear produced a sonic boom and was quickly closing the gap. They clearly heard the resounding boom behind them but when they turned around it was already closing in on them. Before it fully reached them the spike burst into many slightly smaller ones, each one heading for a cultivator’s head.

“N-no!”

They cried out in horror as they tried to protect their bodies but these bone spears seemed to home in on them. Luckily for them, there was a person nearby that could protect them.

Not long after the initial sonic boom was heard it was followed by another strange sound. A certain white-robed cultivator appeared right out of nowhere between this small group and the flying projectiles. Without raising his hand he let them collide with the spirit shield that was surrounding his body.

The bone material was quite sturdy but even it wasn’t able to pierce through Zhang Dong’s natural defenses. They crumbled into tiny pieces that bounced off to the sides, when they collided with the earth below they caused small explosions.

‘Hm… about the strength of a middle stage nascent soul master, nothing I can’t handle.’

Zhang Dong just stood there and gave out a sigh. He had a decision to make, either he continued on his previous journey to follow Wang Long. If he did that, he would probably have to abandon this sect. They would probably all perish under the onslaught of these unfamiliar beings.

Then there was option two, in which he would remain here and hold them off. He wasn’t sure if there was more of them coming but normally a scouting troop would be sent out first in situations like this. Only after clearing out a path for the main forces' arrival would they venture forth through this bridge in full force.

‘If I take care of the scouting party… they might halt their advance for a while, it would also give these guys time to evacuate. Would I have been able to get to Wang Long if I didn’t get distracted…’

This was a truth that he would have to live with now. Maybe if he ignored the damage that Wang Long had done along the way, he could have gotten to him before these people arrived. Now he opened a path to more trouble.

‘No, I can just look forward, I knew that I couldn’t save everyone.’

He turned his head towards the group of people behind him.

“What are you waiting for, get out of here if you don’t want to die and pass on this message to the other sects, the empires beyond the barrier have come to take outlands, now begins the time of war.”

The other sects had no idea who these people were, if he didn’t inform them of the other empires they might think that it's just another demonic sect or something.

“Empires from beyond? War? What does elder…”

“Stop talking and go, I can’t protect you and hold them off at the same time.”

The cultivator that he was talking to, which was the main elder, quickly shut his mouth. Without replying he quickly zoomed into the distance and the people with him did the same.
As they retreated, there was another large booming sound from the bridge.

When he turned around the sky was slowly getting blacked out by a large amount of these bony projectiles. All of them were aimed at him instead of the group that was fleeing.

“You guys are quite the impatient lot…”

He at least thought that after blocking one of the projectiles they would think twice about attacking the cultivator capable of just bouncing it off with his aura. It seemed that these beings were as bloodthirsty as they looked.

‘Wish I had my dragon with me…’

Without his soul beast to perform large energy attacks, it was up to him. Luckily after paying a visit to the other world, he had learned ways of producing magical attacks with his spiritual energy. He was now able to use some of the ambient spiritual energy in the world to save up on energy.

Thus he reached out with his hand forward and quickly produced a magical diagram in the air. It was in the shape of a circle and had various strange symbols that looked like runes on it. This magical circle quickly started to spin around while giving out lightning energy, before the rain of fast-flying arrows hit him, the magical spell erupted forward.

A massive blast of lightning energy flew forward in a wide cone. The moment this energy collided with these bony spears they started crumbling under its might. The conal attack didn’t travel far as Zhang Dong’s focus was on defense first. Before that group of elders made a run for it, he felt like it would be best to not let any of these projectiles through.

This time around, the scale of his technique was quite grand. It seemed that these attackers were not fully braindead berserkers, after he managed to protect himself a second time. The large flying creature halted its advance and all the other flying ships also came to a halt. It was clear that now they were taking him as a serious threat.

‘Are the big boys coming out to play?’

After the bone rain subsided he started feeling beings with stronger spiritual energy emerging from the stronghold that that huge worm creature was carrying. While Zhang Dong was somewhat confident in his own abilities, he was not sure where his limits were at this moment.

His cultivation realm was quite new and he did not know if these beings followed the same rules as people from this empire. It was time to test if he was really ready for this coming war.

Chapter 426

‘They do have me outnumbered quite a bit, that is… if I allow them to get here…’

Zhang Dong floated in the air while the smoke subsided. The bone spears that were thrown his way were now nothing but smoke. These organic projectiles produce a strange-looking smoke after their destruction but it didn’t seem that it would be lethal even if he let his spirit shield down.

It seemed that the diplomatic approach was off the table, perhaps if he demonstrated some of his might to these attackers they would deem it smart to retreat. Some luck was at his side, even though this bridge was about one kilometer in width there wasn’t that much space for this army to move.

“You can’t move to the sides, now can you?”

A decision was made to produce a large wide-area attack. Before they could attack him again Zhang Dong’s aura exploded. Golden lightning bolts started to coil themselves around his arms and slowly traveled towards both his hands.

He slowly opened up his hands, his fingers spreading appart while a small orb of light appeared between them. The more he concentrated the larger this light became, from a tiny dot it expanded into something the size of a basketball. The energy was hard to contain but as he charged up he continued to compress this round sphere of light.

The cultivators that were fleeing could feel it, something was happening. Most of them were too afraid to look back, but even without doing so they could see the light bursting from behind them.

“T-this… what kind of terrible attack is that… we must flee! We will surely perish if we don’t get far enough!”

While Zhang Dong was mostly paying attention to his attack, out of the corner of his eye he could see his targets reacting to this turn of events. While they were quick to attack him beforehand, it seemed that they were now scared. Some of them even started to quickly increase their speed to get past the tunnel, it was clear that they were intelligent enough to know what his intention was.

Some of them were in luck as Zhang Dong did need some time to charge up this attack but most of them were still stuck in that bridge. It was somewhat in his favor that he appeared in this location at this point in time, it now gave him the perfect opportunity to blast these invaders.

The sphere of energy was now rumbling and pushing against his palms. He had trouble holding it in place, the energy wanted to burst through. But, this wasn’t the end of his technique, before he released it he looked forward. His eyes glowed and along with this sheen a magic circle formed in front.

This magic circle was followed by another larger one and then more. They numbered about a hundred magic circles that formed a sort of compact cone that was aimed at this gap. Only when the circles were formed did he point this orb of spiritual energy forward to release a blast of concentrated spiritual Qi.

It started off small but when it collided with the magic circle the ray of golden energy increased in size. All of these circles could slightly increase the techniques might, the more the beam traveled forward the larger it became. When it reached the last circle the beam of highly concentrated Qi shot out, its width was enough to fully encompass the one-kilometer wide gap.

A torrent of force exploded, it submerged everything in a golden glow that was a combination of Zhang Dong’s holy and lightning Dao. The screams of his enemies were quickly silenced by the massive sound of explosions that followed after.

Zhang Dong’s hands trembled slightly as he continued to pour all of his spiritual energy into this attack. His wrists were touching together while he pointed his palms at the magical circles that continued to enhance this ranged attack.

From the outside where the group of fleeing cultivators was, a massive hurricane sprung forth. It was as if a nuclear explosion went off in the distance. Any plant life and trees that were there were uprooted in a matter of seconds.

It didn’t take long, he wasn’t able to keep pumping out Qi without any end. After about fifteen seconds at the maximal output, he started to feel weaker. He couldn’t just gas himself out at the first attack thus he started to end it, the bright light started to subside and the radiance vanished after half a minute of the initial explosion of energy.

As always there was now a giant dust cloud covering the whole area. His beam attack had grazed some of the earth below and created a large crater in its wake. His aim was true as he managed to push his attack into the middle of this wide passage.

While the bridge was one kilometer in width it also possessed a ceiling. The attackers couldn’t just flee upwards to evade the attack and after the smoke had cleared he was glad to see that he had managed to deliver a devastating blow to the beings that attacked him.

‘That’s quite the devastation…’

This was probably the most devastating attack that he had ever delivered, the casualties were immense but without his old system, he would not be able to capitalize on points.

Just a moment ago the tunnel had been swarmed by many flying objects big and small, now, on the other hand, only one remained. It was the gigantic flying worm that was similar to the native sandworms living in this area. Even though it was there, it was clearly injured.

Its body that was obsidian was now covered in some strange green blood. Its front area was missing half of its head and some of those huge teeth were out in the open. Regretfully the fortress that it was carrying had managed to survive but it was also in quite a bad state.

While he couldn’t see it well, he was sure that the cultivators that were on the giant work had used all of their might and resources to somehow protect themselves from this wide area blast.

Even though he wasn’t able to kill them all, this wasn’t a concentrated attack, in his mind, it only proved that his opponents wouldn’t fare too well against him. If they barely took his long-ranged technique, how would they fare in a close-quarters combat situation?

‘They didn’t give me much of a choice but what will they do now…’

At this point, he wished that they would just retreat after his first ‘warning’ shot but instead, a blast of yellowish energy traveled his way. It came from within the crumbling fortress that was on that flying worm that was somehow still holding itself together.

‘Won’t give up that easily huh?’

Without thinking much about it, Zhang Dong propelled himself to the side. There was something about this yellowish energy that he didn’t like. It flew past him and collided with the soil behind him. While they were close to a desert at this side there still was some plant life.

But the moment this beam of light collided with the grass, he noticed a strange effect. At first, he expected the ray of light to produce some kind of explosion, instead, it caused the plant life to be petrified.

It seemed that his opponents had some tricks up their sleeves. Now instead of bone spears, he was pelted by these strange yellowish rays that could turn things to stone. Without wanting to check if he could resist this strange effect, he continued to dodge.

From what he could tell, he was getting assaulted by multiple attackers. They were quickly approaching him and he knew that they wouldn’t allow him to fire off another one of these blasts.

“I guess you don’t want to talk this out huh?”

Zhang Dong called out to the beings that were approaching him, they had abandoned the large worm and quickly pushed through the bridge to arrive on this side.

“The outlander is strong but not strong enough!”

One of the strange toothy beings shouted out. His voice was somewhat hoarse and carried a lot of animosity behind it. It did seem that these people had some intelligence but were clearly motivated by violence. Surprisingly they spoke the same language as the people from this empire, which meant that they clearly understood what he had said but decided to ignore him.

What was left of the army with thousands of warriors and flying ships, where six mad-looking humanoid monsters. They were all above the early nascent soul stage with their leader being comparable to a great circle master.
‘This cultivation is somewhat strange…’

While he could feel strength radiating from these people, it was more compact. The way they bolted towards him and used spears from their bodies as weapons was also telling.

‘Body refiners?’

While Zhang Dong was a dual cultivator with both body and Qi, most people stuck to one. These beings clearly had strong bodies, their skin looked hard as rock and they could even produce weapons from their bodies that would be considered high-rank weapons.

Even now as he was examining them, these monsters were grasping for those bone appendages and converting them to weapons. One of his enemies created a spear, while another dual blades. Another one produced a bow that looked like a combination of ligaments and cartilage for the string part.

‘I see, after seeing my ranged technique they decided to close the distance. They do have some battle sense at least.’

He had to give it to them. They quickly identified that Zhang Dong was a strong opponent with some powerful ranged attacks. While they were body refiners their strength lied mostly in close-range hand-to-hand combat. Regretfully for them, Zhang Dong was a dual refiner with quite the hard metal-like body that wouldn’t be easily broken.

It was now six against one but he could feel other beings on the back of that large creature that was still moving forward. He wasn’t sure but his instincts were telling him that the worm had some meaning. It would be best if it didn’t manage to get through the tunnel, if this was really just a scouting party then perhaps that worm and fortress were part of a base that these monsters were trying to assemble.

“So, you are determined to die here?”

He asked once more but he was not given a reply. Instead, he could see a change in one of the monster’s eyes. It was a strange sight as the middle of its pupil opened up and the strange yellowish ray of petrification was shot out.

Only now he realized that this was not a beam of light but instead some kind of strange liquid that these people shot out of their bodies through their eyes.

“That’s kind of gross...I’m not the kind of guy that likes to get covered in strange eye liquid on the first date…”

Zhang Dong was quick to dodge this high-pressure eye attack but the moment he did, his opponents pounced at him from all sides. It was finally time to unsheathe his sword, even though these people were high-level body refiners he was confident in being able to cut them down.

Chapter 427

“What’s happening, what was that explosion of spiritual energy? Did the Golden Dragon get angered by anyone?”

“No Patriarch, invaders!”

“What nonsense? Are the demonic cultivators invading us?”

“No, it’s something else they come from beyond the divide, the Golden Dragon decided to intercept their forces he referred to them as ones from another empire, he spoke of a great war coming!”

“Slow down, explain yourself!”

The group of elders that had escorted Zhang Dong out of the sect had managed to return. They were all sweating bullets as they even used forbidden techniques to increase their speeds to run away. The large technique that he had used was seen even all the way here and the ensuing shockwave had even destroyed some of the buildings that belonged to the common people living in this city.

While these elders had given a transmission that they were being attacked, the people from their sect did not truly believe that some enemies from another empire appeared. Only now after they had arrived and were behind their grand formation they could somewhat give a proper report.

“So… you are saying that these beings attacked you and the Azure Emperor’s brother is now facing them in battle?”

“Yes, Patriarch!”

Like in any other sect, they were now discussing their next move. After the large explosion of spiritual energy, they had no idea what happened. It was a really tremendous amount of Qi and they feared that the Golden Dragon might have already been dead.

The Patriarch found himself in a dilemma. It was as if he was between a rock and a hard place. From one side there was the Azure Emperor that could blame his sect for his brother's demise if he died. Would he eradicate them if he found out that they didn’t go aid him and just left him to some savage attackers?

On the other side, there were the unknown attackers, they seemed strong enough to make someone like the Golden Dragon use a powerful attack like that. They could not have been normal enemies and it was clear that the Long clan that this Golden Dragon belonged to knew something. The whole bit about them being from another empire and that a war was approaching could have been actually true.

“Damn out bad luck… call out to all the elders, everyone get ready we might be going into battle! We do not know who these people are, but we must heed the Golden Dragon’s words, if this is a force from another empire more could come! Ready the flying vessels, if they dare invade our lands we will answer them with violence!”

While the Patriarch made preparations for a bloody battle, Zhang Dong was still battling it out with the smaller group of beings that were on the level of nascent soul cultivators.

“GAH…”

“You guys don’t know when to quit!”

A toothy head went flying after being slashed from its body by a sword covered in golden energy. The first ones to suffer a casualty from this six-man group were the attackers from the other empire. They made the assumption that their soft skin opponent wouldn’t be able to compete with their hardened bodies at close range. They soon discovered that his body was no less softer than the sharp sword that he was wielding.

It didn’t take him long to kill the first one but out of the corner of his eye, he was still looking at the giant worm in the distance. After his attack, it had slowed down significantly but it was still going. He feared that on that fortress that it was carrying was some kind of teleportation formation, perhaps after his enemies had enough time, they would be able to call forth more of their brethren.

‘I guess it's time to test that swordsmanship of mine.’

While one of his opponents was dead, it was only the weakest. The five that stood now against him would probably not make the mistake of taking him lightly anymore. But there was one thing that Zhang Dong knew about these sorts of battles and buy how these monster-like beings were fighting, he was going to exploit it.

One of them charged at him with a bone blade in his hand, it descended with lightning speed onto his head. This wasn’t his only problem, at the same time a spear user decided to perform a quick thrust from behind. Their aim was precise and it only took a fraction of a second for the weapons to reach their targets.

But after another large explosion, the spear user’s face contorted into confusion. He felt that he had pierced through someone’s flesh but it was too similar to someone of his own race. Then when he looked at his bone spear, he noticed that it didn’t go through its intended target. Instead, it slipped under Zhang Dong’s armpit and pierced the shoulder of his own ally.

Instinctively he tried to quickly yank the weapon back to perform another attack but when he tried he was unable to. It felt like this spear was being held back by some kind of vice that was connected to some kind of huge mountain, he could not budge it at all.

To the beings doing this mistake would cost him dearly as when he was struggling with pulling out his spear, his opponent didn’t wait. Instead, he found him using that glowing sword. The blade’s aim was true and it connected with his abdomen. This wasn’t over as the moment he was pierced by the sword a massive torrent of energy was injected into his body electrocuting him from the inside.

Zhang Dong smirked a bit as he yanked out his blade from the being that was behind him. He had turned the disadvantage into an advantage. These people were very similar to high-level cultivators from this empire.

This of course brought a certain amount of status. Just as he thought, a person of high standing and power would not be able to work in a team too well. Even though they had him outnumbered five to one, he could still win by using their own allies against them.

The attack might have seemed coordinated but in reality, both of the fighters weren’t used to each other at all. The strike that was coming from behind him was used to his advantage. He just needed to shift a bit to the side and the dual-wielding monster from his front side was pierced by an attack he did not expect.

‘They have no idea how to fight in a group.”

This was the biggest weakness of cultivators that focused on themselves too much. They had no idea how to work with others. In such a confrontation where they needed to work together to combat a common foe, they would falter.

While the enemy that he electrocuted started falling he moved quickly to the side. The person pierced by the spear was momentarily stunned after being hit by his own ally which gave him ample time to perform his attack and dodge when those dual blades came his way.

“And so it was four!”

Zhang Dong shouted while encompassing his entire body with a golden sheet of energy. This energy diverged towards his shoulders and back area. Soon after two golden hands sprung out, each one of them holding a sword of light. The white blade that he was holding in his right, quickly doubled as he was now ready for battle.

He tossed himself into the fray while his opponents flew at him. With four arms and four blades in hand, he found himself able to combat even four nascent soul-like beings at once. But the longer the fight continued the harder it became, even though these enemies weren’t used to fighting with each other, Zhang Dong knew that with each passing second they would improve.

The fight turned brutal, after two of their allies had fallen before Zhang Dong the remaining four seemed to go into some kind of strange berserked state. Their muscles bulged out and their already large bodies increased in size. It was clearly some kind of technique that these beings all had, they had clearly increased in specs but this didn’t mean that they would be victorious.

Regretfully the invaders had clearly overestimated their own close-ranged capabilities. From four there were soon three and not long after only two combatants remained. No one could have expected for someone like Zhang Dong to be there just waiting to greet their forces. But there he was and soon he would be the only man left standing.

“You put up a gallant fight but … you have no way of winning, give up now and I might spare your life, that is if you answer some of my questions…”

Zhang Dong looked at the toothy monster, one of his arms was missing as he had cleaved it from the shoulder down. Instead of red blood, it was green and even as they spoke the cut-off limb was slowly healing and reassembling itself.

After facing off against these new enemies he was now aware of some differences between the races. They were clearly not humans and could regrow their limbs. They had a similar organ to a heart but it was in a different location. The best way to kill them was to chop off their heads, as humans they still possessed brains in the same location and could not live without them.

“You are strong outlander, but you will not stop us! We are many, we are the swarm, we will feast on your flesh!”

The monster could communicate but he certainly didn’t want to be taken in for questioning. While Zhang Dong would rather bring this person in to get some answers, there were more crucial things to take care of.

While he was distracted by these six enemies the huge worm had managed to crawl its way to this side. Its head was now slowly sinking into the ground right next to the entrance as it seemed that it wanted to bury itself here. The only question was, would the fortress go underground with it or would it remain outside like some sort of temporary fort.

The man with more teeth than jaw tossed himself towards Zhang Dong. A fast exchange of two masters brought along another explosion. Two of them passed each other in a blink of an eye.

A small gash appeared along Zhang Dong’s cheek. It was as if someone took a nail and ran it through a car. This scar burst into golden flames soon after as it started to heal up, but the wound on his opponent was much deeper.

“Damn idiot should have surrendered…”

The monster was cleaved in two exact halves which slowly parted in mid-air before descending towards the ground.

“What is that thing doing…”

Zhang Dong quickly turned to the giant worm which managed to bury itself underground. The large castle-like structure on its back now looked as if it was built here. The moment it was in place he felt some kind of strange vibration that burst forth from it.

Without thinking about it he tossed himself towards this strange construction. It looked like this structure was attempting to do something and before it could be fully activated he needed to destroy it.

Chapter 428

“I don’t like the look of that… I need to hurry!”

Zhang Dong’s form blurred as he increased his speed and bolted towards the large fortress in the distance. After the strange worm burrowed into the sandy earth the fortress began giving out a strange buzzing sound. It didn’t take him long to realize what was happening as a beam of light shot out from the middle tower of this fortress.

This beam shot up for several kilometers before splitting up. It was then that he truly knew these beings were trying to set up a protective formation here. This beam started forming a dome and probably when it connected with the ground it would be hard to enter.

He was somewhat able to measure the power of this protective shield that was being formed. Even for him, it wouldn’t be that easy to break through and this was probably not the end of their plan. If he was correct in his theory, the main plan for these attackers was to create a base.

To establish such a base in this world of his a protective barrier was only one component. The second one would be a large enough force to keep any opponents at bay. This could be achieved in two ways here.

Either they believed that the shield would last long enough for more reinforcements to come through the bridge, or they had some kind of teleportation array in the fortress that would soon be activated. If they could summon more of their kind here, then perhaps they would be able to defend this position.

Zhang Dong’s figure blurred and his after image was leftover behind the dome shield that quickly descended down. His true form on the other hand made it just in time. The barrier forced itself down into the ground and it was clear that tunneling under it would not work.

“Made it and here comes the welcoming committee, they still had this many left?”

The moment he burst into the range of this strange fortress the guards that were stationed here started gathering. He wasn’t afraid though, the quality of these warriors was nowhere near the ones that he faced outside, that is beside one.

What ensued was quite the one-sided slaughter. These toothy beings tossed themselves at him like madmen while screaming out in rage. But with a big difference in power, Zhang Dong only needed to swing his hand once to produce enough spiritual energy to make his attackers explode before they could get anywhere near him.

They still managed to slow him down and he had a suspicion that this was their aim. He could feel that inside of that fortress there was some kind of higher power along with strange energy fluctuations that were similar to what he felt during the times a teleportation gate opened up.

“Get out of my way.”

He bolted forward while the toothy enemies tried to stop him but with such a big difference in strength, they were all sent flying to the side. Their flesh was burnt by the holy flames that surrounded his body and turned to paste due to how fast he was rocketing forward.

Even then, the monster-like people did not stop coming. It was as if they were mindless drones with no mind of their own, their only purpose stopping him before they could activate the teleportation device inside.

After a moment Zhang Dong collided with a large gate made out of bones and strange dark flesh. It folded almost instantly as it was also not able to stop his full powered-up approach but as he was getting closer to his destination, he was forced to protect his head.

This time around, instead of a bony spear a large hammer flew his way. At first, he saw no reason to block or to move out of the way but the moment it collided with his flame barrier he had to perform an evasive maneuver to the side. The large hammer when colliding with his Qi was able to somehow erase it from existence and continue to fly unperturbed by it. It was clear that this weapon had some strange properties.

“Who the hell are you? The last boss?”

Zhang Dong felt the weapon graze his cheek as he utilized one of his movement skills that let him change his position. His joints and body cried out in pain at the sudden movement but with some of his healing arts, he was able to quickly mend the tears to his ligaments that ensued.

The large hammer that looked like a two-handed weapon made an arc and quickly returned to the person that used it. Quite a large one appeared, this one was clearly superior to its species as it was a lot larger at about three meters tall. Its body was covered in even more spikes but the most characteristic thing about it was the large dark horn coming from its forehead.

“You shall die here outlander, you will make a fine addition to my collection!”

The large being growled while talking, its strange-sounding deep voice would probably make most cultivators shiver in fright. Zhang Dong on the other hand wasn’t that impressed but it seemed that this opponent was more at his level.

“You’ll probably won’t just move out of the way and let me destroy the thing that’s behind that large gate?”

Without answering the monster lowered his head slightly while pointing with the horn towards Zhang Dong. The moment that horn was aligned with his head, he quickly stepped to the side. In a moment a ray of concentrated energy collided with his afterimage and with the spot that his face was in just a fraction of a second ago.

This was the second time he was forced to evade and it was time to fight back. When the ray of dark energy passed by him, he raised his hand and pointed out with his finger. A ray of concentrated Qi flew forward while spinning around like a drill while pointing at the monster’s head.

His opponent raised its weapon to intercept this shining force and like a truck flew towards Zhang Dong’s position. It was clear that this weapon would be a problem, its Qi canceling properties caused his finger attack to be dispersed without causing any damage at all.

After a couple of exchanges it was clear that this monster wouldn’t be going down as easily as the other six that he faced. Both of them jumped back and stood still while glaring at each other. Zhang Dong looked at his fist that collided with the hammer the monster was holding. It was really hard, he didn’t feel that he would be able to crush it with his current strength.

Even though his body was more metal than flesh, he could not keep his knuckles from sustaining mini-fractures. Without his healing capabilities, it would have probably not looked too good for him. Without being able to surround his body with a layer of Qi to further protect it, he was receiving some damage.

‘But, not like this creature is doing much better.’

He evaluated the situation and noticed that there was something off about his opponent. The horn was giving out some strange energy signatures and the longer the fight took, the more the monster’s body started to darken. There was a patch of unhealthy-looking black skin going from its forehead and increasing slowly as the fight continued.

‘Is it using some forbidden technique to boost its stats? Or is that something else…’

There was no way for him to know this opponent's biology. It was not a regular cultivator but from his perspective, his opponent was slowly running out of time. The problem was that he was also. This being was probably only trying to buy some time before some reinforcements arrived, if they did he might have to retreat.

“Sorry, but I don’t have time for this…”

When his Qi and body weren’t enough, it was time to use his sword arts. A golden sword appeared in his arm; its radiance caused this whole area to become as bright as day.

At first, the monster wasn’t impressed, its own weapon was clearly superior to the small flimsy longsword that Zhang Dong was holding. But then it felt something, the radiant glow died down, and instead a strange humming noise was heard.

To someone untrained, it would be a mystery but to this monster it was apparent. He was against someone that had mastered the blade to an astonishing extent. His hand that was holding his hammer trembled, not from fear but because his weapon started to vibrate as well. It was as if the superior treasure that he was holding was afraid of the blade that stood before it.

Zhang Dong didn’t make any flamboyant movements, he just grasped the hilt of the sword with both his hands while holding it above his head. It was as if he was trying to perform a practice swing. But to his opponent, it didn’t look that way.

It was as if time stopped for him, instead of the small human that he was fighting he saw an image of a giant. It was as if he was holding a sword as big as a mountain above his head and it was clearly going to be swung his way. Out of panic, he bolted forward, in his mind the only way to survive was to kill before he was killed.

In a fraction of a second it happened, Zhang Dong swung down his sword while unleashing a torrent of sword energy. The monster as previously tried to swing its hammer towards the focal point of this attack. Both of them collided, but this time instead of the hammer canceling out what was thrown its way and crumbled instead.

While the weapon was able to cancel out spiritual Qi, it could not do the same against concentrated sword intent. This Dao of the sword worked on different principles and continued to go forward along with this practice like swing that Zhang Dong was performing.

The being along with its hammer found itself being sliced apart into two perfectly equal parts. And as the image before its eyes parted to the sides he saw a somewhat gassed-out Zhang Dong.

The fortress before him was not better off, it was sliced apart by this simple move that integrated his whole sword Dao into a single swing. While the move was powerful it was hard to use and perhaps if instead of going towards him like an idiot the enemy would have dodged to the side, he would have been unable to use it.

‘Shit… I don’t think I can use this one repeatedly…’

Zhang Dong almost tripped forward, both his hands shaking. His body was crying out for help as he felt that some of the bones in both his hands had broken the moment he finished the swing.

‘I don’t have time to stand here…’

A golden sheen surrounded his body as he started to heal himself, while he defeated this monster it wasn’t quite over...

Chapter 429

“I guess it stopped when I cut it…”

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh of relief as he discovered that he had managed to destroy the device that was used for teleportation. After cleaving his last opponent in half he continued deeper into the large fortress that was now sliced into two parts.

This wasn’t all, the huge worm beast that had carried this thing all the way here was also dead. It wasn’t giving out any life signs and his spiritual sense was also not picking out anything. Everything that was here was now dead and he was the last survivor.

Only thanks to surrounding himself with a barrier of golden flames that could burn away anything that came close to him was he successfully able to not be covered in blood and guts.

The carnage remained outside as it seemed that everyone that was here decided to rush him. The reason for it was probably the huge enemy with the hammer behind them, they could either die in battle with him or get turned to minced meat by him instead.

Now he was looking at something that seemed like a teleportation gate. With the help of his Ai helper, he was able to successfully identify this alien technology.

‘This looks somewhat organic…’

Zhang Dong picked out a strange tube from the ground that was connected to the teleportation gate. At first, he thought it was a power cable, or for fuel but inside of it was some strange green liquid that seemed more like blood.

‘This almost looks like organs and veins… I can even feel some faint life coming from this, but it's fading quickly…’

The battle mostly took place in the courtyard of this large fortress. The huge one-horned boss also charged at him before he could really enter into the whole structure. His sword strike left it destroyed and after looking around for a moment he found a certain room.

“Is this a heart?”

On the ground, there was some kind of deflated organ covered in more green goop. It was radiating his sword intent and was clearly damaged by him. This seems like the power room but it had collapsed unto itself along with most of the fortress.

Without thinking too much he used his spiritual energy to raise the rubble around this section. The damaged organ was then floated over and deposited into his spatial ring. Now was not the time to examine these things but he needed to take some samples and have his sect members examine them later.

To his surprise, these monsters didn’t seem to have any spatial technology. He didn’t discover any rings or bags that could carry more items. Maybe they didn’t feel like they needed anything like pills and more weapons to carry around if they could produce them from their own bodies?

The boss that he had sliced in half was also deposited into his spatial ring along with a few other body samples that weren’t too damaged. There was also a strange sphere on a platform made from bones and with some of those veins attached to it. He could feel some strange energies coming from it, thus it also made its way into his belongings.

“How did they build this thing… did they disassemble some beasts or somehow grow this organic mass?”

This place was strange indeed but even more baffling was the mystery behind building it. From the outside, it looked like a pile of bones, but on the inside, it clearly had organic components, even things that looked like organs and a circulatory system.

While he was continuing with the examination he noticed that he had new visitors. They were fast approaching and there was quite a big group of them.

“It must be the cavalry? Fashionably late to the party, aren’t they?”

He was not in any danger as the new arrivals came from the same sect that he visited today. It was clear that after the elders escaped they rallied the troops to defend themselves. While he wanted to compliment their resolve, they would have been dead if they tried attacking these monsters alone.

From what he could tell, there were about three nascent soul masters coming his way along with some basic flying ships and some hundred core formation masters. This was about what a lesser middle-sized sect could offer.

They probably brought about thirty to forty percent of their forces here while the rest remained on standby. It was normal for them not to give up without a fight or measuring their enemies' might. These monsters were body refiners so their combat abilities were hard to measure with spiritual sense as the amount of Qi they possessed wasn’t that high.

“Body refiners… no wonder there isn’t anything here that can store spiritual energy…”

After wandering around for a few minutes and scanning everything his hopes of getting some loot were crushed. The only bounty was the strange hammer that he sliced in half, its spiritual energy disrupting capabilities were interesting and clearly, it was due to the material it was made from. Besides it, there was nothing else of much value that he could spot.

“They don’t need to craft weapons as they can just use their body parts and don’t use pills or spiritual stones to increase their strength, this will be an annoying enemy…”

For Wang Long, this might have been a nice opponent as they would drop spirit points for him. But to him they were somewhat worthless, that is unless he figured out a way to utilize these organic components that they were using.

Without anything interesting to do, he decided to go outside. This didn’t go unnoticed as he was quite the beacon of golden energy.

“I-it’s honored Long Dong, he still lives!”

The moment he appeared outside the cultivators that were approaching quickly stopped in mid-air. While he was playing the Golden Dragon persona he was still not used to being called by that name.

“Ah… yes that’s me… the Golden Dragon, and I have a long d... I mean, I am Long Dong."

He coughed into his sleeve while looking at the group of three elders that were approaching. These three were unknown to him but judging by their cultivation levels they were the leaders, the one that was in front was a late-stage cultivator and probably the Patriarch.

“Ma He, greets the Golden Dragon, we came as fast as we could but it seems that our help was not needed.”

The man was quite respectful as he bowed a lot lower than usual. Zhang Dong just waved his hand as he had no intention of staying here too long.

“Yes, I have managed to destroy the base of these invaders but I’m not sure when the next attack will occur, as you can see the way for them is open.”

He pointed towards the tunnel that was about a kilometer in width and three kilometers in height. While this might have looked like a grand victory, he didn’t really defeat that many people. These forces were about the level of a stronger middle-sized sect and might have been bolstered for the purpose of establishing a base of operations.

“I wouldn’t want to alarm you but I’m not sure if your people will be able to survive the second attack, worry not, I will contact my brother… he might be able to send some reinforcements.”

This was too far away from his own sect that had just secured the lands that they were owed. To defend this location he would need to place at least ten nascent soul masters along with Huo Qiang and Zhang Zhi to have a chance of defending it. They would also need to create protective formations and defensive siege weapons.

“But honored Golden Dragon…”

“I know, you don’t seem convinced but the enemies I faced were above your current level, there aren’t that many cultivators in this empire that would be able to battle on equal footing with them.”

While he wanted to convince these people that it was unwise to stay here, he could not control their actions. The biggest problem was that he had eradicated all of the enemies, which could give an impression of them not being all that strong. In actuality without someone at the great circle of the nascent soul realm, they had no chance of survival.

“You should better heed my warning, but I will not stop you if you want to remain here. If you decide to remain, this would probably be a good spot to place any long-ranged weapons that you have, while in the bridge between our empires the enemies have limited space to maneuver, they will be an easy target. Though after their first failure, they will probably come in larger numbers.”

His opponents were clearly not expecting someone like Zhang Dong to be waiting for them. There weren’t many cultivators or weapons that could create such a devastating wide-ranged attack as he did. If they had some way to relay information back to their leaders, they would probably consider the same thing happening again.

‘This fight has taken more out of me than I thought…’

While he looked fine from the outside he was running on fumes. That huge magically enhanced attack almost instantly drained him of half of his spiritual energy. Then he had to fight off many opponents and use a devastating sword art that injured his own body in the process.

He had been a bit hasty in this battle as he was racing against time. This had now left him out of gas to continue his journey forward. The desert and then the wide dead sea filled with many monsters was still waiting for him.

‘Shit, do I really have to postpone this?’

The reason he came here was to find Wang Long. But he felt that if his other opponent popped out at this very moment he would probably have to flee. With how much Qi he used up he would need some time to recover. Anything related to spiritual energy was already consumed as he needed it to bolster his system and then feed his three cores.

‘These guys didn’t even have any nascent souls, they are a terrible match for me.’

Regretfully he would need to retreat for now but this wasn’t the end. Thanks to his system he would be able to create a teleportation point that he could use later on. It would cost him dearly as this was not part of his own lands but it needed to be done.

‘If I’m lucky those monsters will take some time to return, I might be able to come back and set up my own defenses here.’

With that thought in his mind, he decided to create a save point. He would place it somewhat away from this direct location. If it was taken over by those beings before he could come back, he would be teleporting right into their base where they were waiting for him with some new countermeasures.

“I will have to bid you farewell then, I hope that you and your people survive this, we will need any help we can get to get through this war.”

With a few chosen words to Ma He he started retreating, first he needed to find a nice hidden location for this teleportation point, and then it was time to contact his dear brother, the Azure Emperor.

Chapter 430

“What do you mean they are all dead?”

*crunch*

A somewhat peculiar crunching sound was heard by several people in this large chamber. A huge demonic-looking man was holding a bloodied head along with the body that was now just dangling around. He then promptly engulfed it in a blaze before throwing it to the side where everyone could see it.

“You there, answer me!”

“Y-yes my Emperor, as the previous high shaman stated, the tribe that was tasked with the mission to the outlands had fallen in battle…”

“What tribe was that again?”

The man called the emperor moved forward while the other person continued to talk. With each footstep, he took the ground and continued to shake along with the other beings that were here.

“It was t-the Terakota Tribe, they w-won the honor by c-combat…”

“So, you are saying that something in the outlands proved too much for the Terakota Tribe? Thought that their chieftain was better than this…”

The large emperor looked to the side. There he saw various humanoid creatures that varied in all kinds of ways. All of them had their heads lowered, no one dared to raise their voice as everyone knew how much of a temper this Demonic Emperor had.

“Did the outlanders predict their arrival and sprung a trap?”

“W-well my Emperor it was…”

The shaman that was talking started stumbling over his own words while the Emperor continued to glare. He knew that if he angered this being of great power, he would be the next one to get his head squished and popped like a watermelon.

“Don’t waste my time shaman.”

“Y-yes my Emperor, w-why don’t I show you instead.”

The shaman was wearing a dark robe and his face was also hidden behind it. From inside of his sleeve he took out something that looked like a large insect with a gem on its back. When the Emperor saw it, he instantly knew what the shaman was doing.

“Good.”

He said while walking back to his throne and sitting down. Then after he was in a comfortable position the shaman placed the large bug on the ground. This insect moved into the center of the chamber before the gem on its back started to give out a green light.

Soon a beam of light traveled from this gem and produced a vivid image to everyone that was here. What they saw was the view from the large fortress that was placed on the huge sandworm beast during the attack.

It was a recount from their travels with multiple angles as if there were various cameras at the fortress. The shaman made sure to not bore the emperor so the image played right before the scouting party was attacked.

Without saying anything it continued to play, all the way from when Zhang Dong fired off a large beam of spiritual energy towards them all the way until he cleaved the Terakota Tribe chief in half.

At the end, all the people from the other tribes that were here were shocked. Every single one of them had a similar horn protruding from their head. The Terakota Tribe leader was not inferior to anyone from them in any way. They all believed that they would not fare much better against the frail-looking outlander that he had faced.

“Are you telling me that they were defeated by one man?”

“Y-yes my Emperor… there were other outlanders there but they quickly fled the scene while this bright one remained…”

Without saying anything the Emperor took out a certain weapon from the side. It looked like a giant cleaver which handle was made from some molten rock. He raised it up into the sky while a giant oppressive aura exploded in all directions. Then without warning, he turned around to swing his massive weapon once.

A large torrent of strange energies traveled forth towards the volcanoes and mountains in the distance. It didn’t take long for this attack to connect with the rocks in the distance. With one swing of his huge cleaver, the mountains were no more. All of the living beings on them groaned out in fear and indignation at their demise.

“This bright one… he will make a fine trophy for my wall, rally the tribes spare no men, I want that gate! Failure is not an option!”

The Emperor declared while hefting the massive blade that was covered in lava over his shoulder. He looked out into the distance with a giant grin on his face, it seemed that this hunt would be more interesting than he anticipated.

….

While his enemies were scrambling around to resume their invasion, Zhang Dong had teleported back to his own lands. Along his travels he had created some save points that he could teleport to but there was a limited number that he could use with his current system.

‘I need to call him…’

He gave out a sigh before tapping his system screen, on it was one of his new faction members, the Azure Emperor. While he did retreat from the pursuit of Wang Long, he still would like to ask for some help. In his mind, the talk could go in any direction but he hoped that Long Qing would see it his way.

It all depended on how fast they could rally the troops and head to that place. Zhang Dong was even willing to go back there to act as support. The somewhat narrow passage would not be that easily crossed if they managed to create a base of operations there. If they managed to plug that hole, it would save them a lot of resources later on as they would be able to control one point of entrance.

“Greetings, can you hear me?”

“... brother Dong… is that your voice? Where are you?”

It was clear that the Azure Dragon was surprised by the voice in his head. From what he could tell, Long Qing was probably looking around for the hidden Zhang Dong that was talking to him.

“Ah, I’m not at your location, I’m talking to you thanks to a certain technique of mine. You don’t need to actually use your mouth, you just need to think and I’ll be able to hear your thoughts, that is if you want me to hear them.”

While Zhang Dong could communicate with people through his system, this didn’t mean that he could hear their thoughts. Unless the recipient didn’t think of the words that they wanted to relay to him, he would not be able to hear them.

“Oh? Let me try then… Can you hear me like this?”

“Yes, loud and clear, also don’t worry no one else is able to hear our conversation, it will remain private.”

“Oh really?”

There was a small pause but soon Long Qing was back to talking, this time around to someone that was with him.

“Are you there?”

“Yes, did you hear that my wife? No?”

Due to this system feature not being able to pick up sounds of others or at least not until the Azure Dragon’s devotion rating went up, he couldn’t hear the conversation that they were having. It was clear that he was together with his wife, who was probably asking him some questions.
“She won’t hear me.”

“Did you hear that my wife? Really not? But he is being so loud…”

“As I said…”

Zhang Dong wanted to give his brother a smack across his face for not listening. It had been a while but he needed to get used to not getting his way thanks to his Patriarch status. After some back and forth, he was finally able to talk some sense into his new brother.

“You did what? Did you hear that honey? My brother managed to intercept a scouting party from the other empire and wipe them from the face of this empire! Didn’t I tell you that we could rely on him!”

“Could you listen to me for a moment…”

“Ah yes my brother, Haha! I’m a little distracted!”

Zhang Dong was afraid to ask but it wouldn’t be surprising that he contacted the Azure Dragon while he was having some fun time with his wife.

“Anyway… would it be possible to send some of the Long Clan elders or convince the Heavenly Crane Sect to send someone over there? I think if we manage to control that location we would be able to minimize the damage to the empire…”

“Minimise the damage?”

The Azure Emperor asked as if he wasn’t sure what Zhang Dong meant.

“Well… if we are able to block the progress of those beings, we won’t suffer that many casualties?”

“Haha, why would we suffer any casualties?”

“But the sects that are located there will be…”

“Oh? I see that my brother is a compassionate one, don’t worry, they can retreat further into our lands where we will use them to bolster our own forces!”

Zhang Dong was a bit shocked by this reaction but it did somewhat go in line with what a regular cultivator thought. In their eyes the only important part was their own faction which was the Long Clan. It didn’t seem that even the Azure Emperor cared all that much about his subjects that lived outside the Long Clan area.

“But we could get valuable information about our foes? We could have their weapons examined and maybe get some treasures?”

“Treasures? That could be useful… but I’m not sure if it will matter at this point in time.”
“What do you mean?”

Zhang Dong asked but there was something telling him that the news wouldn’t be good.

“Well, while you were battling the invaders, more of the bridges had opened up. The one you discovered won’t be the only one coming from that side so I’m not sure if we would be able to defend such a remote location away from our clan.”

The Long Clan had a map that showed them every bridge that appeared and would later appear. Thus they already knew about the arrival of the enemy. Even without Zhang Dong telling them to act, they were probably already scrambling around to bolster their defenses.

“So that means?”

“Yes, I don’t think I can spare any soldiers but if you need some personal guards I could send over some elders, I’m sure they will be honored to accompany the Golden Dragon!”

“Ah, that won’t be needed…”

Zhang Dong shook his head in disappointment as it seemed that he needed to abandon that location. Even if he built a base of operations there, the enemy could pop out a thousand miles away after a day. It wasn’t wrong to bunker up at your own sect where everyone had most of their resources.

“Is that so? Don’t worry my brother, this is only the beginning. Everything is going according to plan!”

“It is huh…”

‘Would be nice if I heard it first…”

It seemed that he would need to retreat for now. Instead of helping the other sects, it would be better to defend his own lands where everyone he loved and cherished was. With that in mind, he ended the conversation with his brother. While he didn’t like it, he would need to be a bit more selfish this time around.

Chapter 431

“So we are here, in the lands of the unknown...”

A man with an extensively long beard floated around while holding a staff made from wood. At the tip, there was a large round blue orb that this staff wrapped around. The old man looked out into the distance, his eyes shining brightly with a blue hue as he examined the situation.

“Grand Wizard, we have managed to transport the magical gates, we can proceed.”

“Ah, Sir Basil. Make sure that the regiment of Paladins is ready, we have some visitors, I don’t know if they are hostile, I will greet them first while you make the gate ready, we might need some reinforcements.”

“As you command, lord Argus!”

A man dressed in shiny white armor made a salute to the floating man. While it didn’t look that the knight could fly on his own, he was mounted on a horse with wings. Both of them radiated a strange energy that was similar to Qi yet different.

The man referred to as Argus floated forward. With his magical capabilities, he noticed a group of twenty people flying this way. They didn’t seem to be simple humans as most of them were flying on swords with one, in particular, standing out.

‘This place is very peculiar… The mana here is very thick, casting spells should be quite easy. This might really be the promised land of magics that the legends have foretold!’

Argus smiled to himself but his expression quickly turned sour. While his men were down on the ground and preparing the grand magic for protection, potential enemies were approaching.

“Identify yourself, from which sect do you hail from?”

The old man flew forward to intercept the approaching natives. He was sure to quickly put some distance between himself and the place where they had come from. They had traveled through a wide tunnel of energies that was quite wide.

At the part that they came out, the land looked somewhat devastated. All to the sides were massive elemental storms that even this grand wizard had no hopes of subduing. But, when all of them looked ahead they spotted lands with lush forests and ample water.

“I welcome thee, my friends, I mean you no harm.”

Argos smiled at the group of people but he never let go of his grand staff. The people that flew over stopped before him but were clearly on guard. He did not know them or how they would react to his magic but if it was possible he would rather not get into conflict with them.

“Friends? Who are you? This is the territory of the great Crimson Blood Spider Sect! You don’t look like a member of the other sects… are you a rogue cultivator?”
The men that he was talking to had a certain air around them. Their robes were pitch black and on the back, they had a red insignia that looked like a venomous spider. Argos could sense the killing intent that these people were radiating, it was clear that they weren’t the gentle type.

“A cultivator? Like in a garden? No, my name is Argos, I come from a faraway land and I would wish to…”

“Silence! Do you think we are fools! Did you think we wouldn’t sense those people? You dare!”

Before he could even start, the diplomatic approach had fallen through. He didn’t know how but through means unknown to him one of the people there could sense the paladins working in the distance.

Normally as a grand wizard, he would know if something like that happened as there would be mana used. These people on the other hand felt somewhat different, they weren’t using mana the same as he was. It was clear that they possessed powers alien to him, but this didn’t mean that he was frightened.

“My friend, just calm down I’m sure we can…”

“Silence, you will come with us or face our poison.”

A shroud of green miasma started surrounding all of these people while Argos remained calm. He could not go with them, it was clear that if he surrendered then he would either die or be imprisoned by these natives.

“I’m afraid I’ll have to refuse your offer…”

He replied but as soon as he did, the natives that were flying on the swords bolted towards his position. There was something strange with the rings that they were using. Argus felt something akin to spatial magic as they swished their hands to produce weapons.

Regretfully for the attacking cultivators, there weren’t dealing with the average magus. The moment they tried getting close they found themselves being repelled by an invisible barrier. Even though they tried, any attacks performed against this mana-barrier were useless; they even received a rebounding effect that caused damage to them instead.

“I guess it can’t be helped, go to sleep.”

The floating wizard pointed out with his staff and performed a very quick chant. The moment he was finished a strange violet haze appeared around the core formation cultivators that were trying to attack him. It covered their faces and in a matter of moments, they were in a deep slumber.

“What is this technique? Watch out brothers, this old man isn’t that simple!”

Argus swung his staff around and quickly disabled every one of the sword-flying cultivators. But then when he attempted to do the same to what looked to be the leader his spell was repealed.

Soon a battle ensued between the two old men, one slinging strange poisonous arts that when touching any of the flora quickly died. The cultivator from the Crimson Blood Spider sect was astonished. Tried he did but he was unable to pierce through that mana barrier that was produced.

His enemy on the other hand didn’t have any problem pelting him with long-ranged attacks. They all had a strange feeling to them, similar to Qi yet different. Soon enough he found himself engulfed in a massive ball of flames and had to retreat. Luckily for him, the old man that he was fighting with didn’t seem to be interested in chasing after him.

“I will remember this, you will rue the day you met me!”

But as he was escaping, he felt something. There was something coming his way, even though he noticed it, it was too late. A golden bolt of energy pierced through his chest without any resistance whatsoever.

“H-how could this be… how could a nascent soul master like me fall so easily…”

The poisonous cultivator could feel it, his nascent soul had been irreparably damaged. Somehow this attack could even affect his soul and it was clear that he would soon die. Before the darkness took him, he glanced towards the point from where this attack came.

There he saw a strange man wearing glistering golden armor. The attacker was still in his throwing position and after he straightened out a golden spear appeared in his hand, probably returning to him after the deed was done.

“Argus, you are too soft, we can’t let any of these savages live, they will clearly alert their allies and come in bigger numbers.”

The old wizard looked at the dying man that promptly fell down into some bushes. Then back to the man dressed in full plate mail armor with only his helmet missing. His looks were quite stunning, long locks of golden locks and a chin that could cut diamonds.

“Lord Lucius… so I see that the Golden Braves have managed to get through the gate.”

This wasn’t the only man dressed in golden armor, several others started popping out and quickly dispatching the men that he put to sleep.

“Wait…”

Argus shouted out but the men in golden armor ignored his calls.

“Wizard, don’t forget that you are only here to give aid, you are nothing more than an advisor.”
The man named Lucius proclaimed while also shouting to the group of golden knights to leave one man alive.

“One is enough, we will question him, make yourself useful Wizard and make him speak with your magic if you do now wish for this savage to suffer.”

Argus gave out a sigh as he continued to watch. The teleportation gate had been opened, his only duty was to make sure that the area was livable for the main force to arrive. With The coming of the golden braves, his role was now marginal.

From here he could see that the people from his side were slowly entering through the teleportation gate. While his reason for coming here was to pursue knowledge, the kingdom he was a citizen of wanted something else. They desired riches, power and prestige.

…..

“We greet the Golden Dragon!”

“Ah yes.”

Zhang Dong was now back in the flying city of the Azure Emperor. With some guidance, he was now on the way to the secret room that he had visited before. After the talk with his brother, it was clear that the Long Clan did not see it his way.

His reasoning for teleporting here instead of his own area of influence was one. The map that the Long Clan possessed showed a detailed representation of the empire and the bridges between them. He didn’t really have enough time to examine it when he was here the first time.

‘Bob, I need you to examine that map and if you can copy it to some extent, I can’t keep returning here to look at it.’

‘Affirmative.’

Now with the help of his new title the gates to the Long Clan were open to him. He could wander through the halls unimpeded to some extent that is. When confronted with some of the grand elders or the Azure Dragon faction they didn’t seem to like him that much.

This was probably due to the fact that it was a hard pill to swallow that there was something on the same ground as the Emperor. In this world devoid of any deities people looked to cultivators and immortals instead. The Azure Emperor was akin to a god in this land and now there he came, someone that could affect the balance.

“How may I help you?”

This was his second time here but he did not really know the way towards that area. At the time being, he was standing at something similar to a reception area.

“Ah yes, could you fetch one of the high elders? Tell them that the Golden Dragon, Long Dong is here, best if it's someone that could show me around…”

Previously his brother the Azure Dragon showed him the way but as the war effort was slowly underway. He needed to know his way around this place, maybe even gather some allies if there was a reason to retreat here with his closest of kin.

“Oh wait, never mind, I see someone that can do it instead…”

Zhang Dong looked to the side and spotted someone familiar.

“Hey there, Long Shen was it? Mind giving your uncle a small tour?”

Chapter 432

“What? Won’t give your favorite uncle a hug? Have you been practicing your swordsmanship? Maybe if you do, you will be able to be as good at it as your uncle!”

“Y-you…”

Long Shen, the oldest son of the Azure Emperor, looked quite dejected after Zhang Dong shouted out at him. There were other people around this place and also around this young master. They of course knew who the Golden Dragon was so they could not say anything without being talked to.

“What, you are so glad to see me that you are at a loss for words?”

Zhang Dong moved closer while somewhat strutting as if he was in a rush. His nephew recoiled in horror as he clearly wasn’t sure what to do. Previously he attempted to embarrass Zhang Dong but it all came to bite him and his siblings in the end. Now this man that his father held in high regard was before him again.

“Don’t be so stiff, are you worried about what happened in the past?”

“Well, I…”

“Don’t worry about it, we are family are we not?”

Zhang Dong slammed his palm against Long Shen’s back which made the young man stagger forward. The people in the back gasped out in shock as they couldn’t believe it. They somewhat expected their young master to recoil in anger but instead, he just fixed his clothes without saying much.

“Y-yes, we are family… Did you want something from me, uncle? If not, then I will be on my way…”

“Actually, I do need some directions and I think my cute nephew probably knows his way around this city!”

“C-cute?”

It was quite strange, in reality, Long Shen was older than Zhang Dong that was close to being forty. It was hard to measure the age of nascent soul masters that ascended in their early years thus no one made a fuss.

“Yes, now could you show me the way to one of those three elders? I think one of them should be able to guide me further.”

The three old bags that whined to the Azure Emperor were probably the best bet of him getting to that map chamber.

“One of the three elders? Ah yes…”

To Zhang Dong’s surprise, the young master didn’t seem that against showing him around. Either he was feeling forced due to his status or perhaps he had become a better person?

‘Probably closer to the first one, he isn’t that good at hiding his emotions.’

While he wanted to tease the man some more, it would be better to not go overboard. He didn’t want to waste any more time than he had to. If he continued to alienate Long Shen they might get into a fight which he would probably win but could leave the Azure Dragon’s son unable to continue.

“Ah yes, Elder Laixie should be close by.”

Without further ado, the two left while the young master's company removed themselves. While they could stick around him when someone like the Golden Dragon appeared they couldn’t just follow if he didn't tell them that they could.

‘Elder Laixie? It’s probably that old woman.’

Both Zhang Dong and Long Shen were nascent soul masters, it didn’t take long for them to cover a lot of space. Even then it was somewhat hard to maneuver through the large crystal tower that housed hundreds of thousands of people in it. While it was quite gigantic from the outside, it was even larger on the inside.

The elder that he was looking for was in one of the many chambers that had spatial technology on it. The area on the inside of it was many times larger than he had expected, it was somewhat similar to what the spot he met the Azure Dragon was.

The only difference was that it was obviously a fake environment. He could feel that the sky was just an illusion as well as the sun that was shining down on him. The whole place looked like a vacation villa with a forest around it but even though it seemed that it stretched for many kilometers it was about one in diameter.

‘I guess something like the Dimensional Regalia isn’t easily created even for the Long Clan.’

Keeping in mind that he was going to the residence of one of the top three elders, it meant that they probably were granted access to their clan's most treasured technologies and magics.

“This is where the elder lives, I’ll excuse myself then…”

“Ah yes, have a nice… and he is gone…”

Zhang Dong was stuck looking at the spatial magic and integrated formation that he didn’t react to that well. During this time that took only a few seconds, Long Shen decided to remove himself from the area. When using his spirit sense he could feel his nephew rocketing away at full speed.

“He must be shy…”
“Hello, is anyone here? Is Elder Laixie here?”

He talked while walking towards the building on the small hill. The people that lived here probably realized that he was here as he felt something scanning his body for clues as he entered. Of course, it wasn’t able to as he shrouded his body with a thin layer of protective Qi. The people here knew that someone entered but they didn’t know who exactly.

“Who are you? Long Shen already left?”

The voice that he heard belonged to the elder that he had met for a short time. Surprisingly she was the only person here and didn’t even bother to come to greet him.

“Yes he did, it is me, Long Dong, you know, the Golden Dragon…”

While the woman didn’t tell him that he could go in he continued to slowly walk towards this large mansion. The woman was a top elder of the clan but she was in theory below him in status. Even though it was only on paper, she would normally have to lower her head before him.

“I don’t think we had an appointment…”

He continued to move forward, the gate was wide open and on the inside, he saw the old woman wearing a more traditional robe. She was tending to her garden of spiritual herbs but mostly just looking at some that were radiating Qi.

“Yes, I must apologize for that but I need someone to help guide me, I would like to…”

As he tried to continue he saw the old woman look at him sternly. She moved her finger to her mouth as if she wanted to tell him to be quiet. Then he also realized that she had been whispering while looking at a certain closed flower.

“That flower is… a spiritual sunrise lily?”

Thanks to his deep knowledge of all things thanks to all the books he read, he was quickly able to identify the plant. The woman was a bit surprised and this was probably due to this flower being mostly mistaken with a similar one named the sun lily that was slightly different.

Now that he looked back to the fake sun above, he could spot that it was certainly more red than usual. After adding two and two together it was clear what the woman was doing.

“Ah, is the elder Laixie trying to grow the sunrise lily?”

“I see that the Golden Dragon is very knowledgeable, you probably know that this flower needs to be brought up in near silence and tranquility to develop the sunrise seeds inside.”

“Ah yes, they are quite the rare seeds that can be turned into various elixirs to nourish the fire aspect.”

“Yes, I’m not sure what you came here for Golden Dragon, but I must remain here because this is a critical point in the life cycle of the sunrise lily.”

He could tell that the old woman was nourishing the plant with some of her Qi. This also explained why this place was deserted a loud noise could cause the flower to not produce any seeds. It took many years to just grow one flower as it wouldn’t bloom if there were more of its kind around it.

“That is true but…”

It was clear that he wouldn’t get the woman to budge from this place. Then when he tried to explain himself the woman continued to sush him. It didn’t seem that the war that was here made these elders worry too much for some reason. They were certainly convinced that even if all failed they would be safe in this fortress of theirs.

Thus the only way to make this old lady move was to bring this flower to bloom. Thankfully with the amount of knowledge that he had gained he would be able to do such a thing. The biggest problem would probably be to make her agree to it.

“Ah yes… her isn’t that the Azure Dragon? oh no, why is he wearing that alluring dress?”

Zhang Dong pointed into the distance behind the old woman. She of course was taken aback by something so preposterous but was also unable to not look in that direction. The notion of seeing the handsome Azure Emperor in some kind of dress was probably too much. While curiosity got to her, he quickly went for it.

“There is no one there… wait w-what are you doing!”

The old woman screamed out in shock as she saw Zhang Dong quickly pluck the flower from the ground. To her knowledge this would certainly make the plant die, it was something that she had nourished for many years but before her eyes, it was now gone.

“Oh don’t you worry, just give me a second I’ll have it bloom before your eyes.”

She was furious with him and even though he said that it would be fine, she pulled out a sword instantly.

“I don’t care who you think you are!”

“Now let's not be hasty grandma, just give me a moment…”

The flower was out of sight in his hands as he started nourishing it with a combination of select elements. He was sure that it would work even after plucking it from the ground but the old woman went crazy.

“Hey now, that was dangerous…”

He dodged a swing from her blade while flying away. The woman started chasing him around this area and he was even forced to leave it. Soon the whole crystal tower where the main long clan was based was in an uproar. Mentions of their grand elder chasing after the emperor’s brother quickly reached everyone.

“It’s hard to concentrate like this, if I didn’t know better I’d think you really wanted this lily to die!”

“Stop with the excuses!”

They flew long and wide. Even other elders and clan members started chasing after them but soon they all stopped as a strange phenomenon occurred. The area was covered in a crimson-like haze that resembled a rising sun.

“T-this is… the rising of the heavenly lily? But it was only a regular sunrise lily…”

The old woman stopped flying while her jaw dropped, from within the palms of the man she was chasing an unbelievable phenomenon was taking place which prompted her to pass out on the spot.

Chapter 433

“H-how…”

An old lady was clutching a radiant flower with seeds that were pulsating with a strange power. After chasing a man that hailed as the Golden Dragon for destroying her treasured herb, she was now left speechless. She didn’t know how but the Sunrise Lily that could be used for various pills and elixirs had transformed almost before her eyes.

“It’s a Heavenly Sunrise Lily…”

“That’s why I told you to wait…”

Zhang Dong was standing in front of the old woman that continued to stare at the glowing flower. It was so bad that he even had to give the old lady a poke on the shoulder to wake her up from her trance.

“You should better put that flower into stasis, even though it has bloomed it won’t last forever you know.”

“Ah… you have my gratitude.”

The old lady quickly used a special technique on the flower that would help it last longer before putting it into her spatial ring. Afterward, she looked at him with a strange glint in her eyes.

“I must apologize for my previous outburst, I let emotions cloud my judgment, please accept this apology Golden Dragon.”

Laixie clasped her hands together while bowing her head quite low. There were various people looking out from the side. The two caused quite the ruckus in this large crystal tower that housed most of their inner clan members.

“Elder Laixie admitted her wrongdoings?”

“S-she is showing allegiance to the Golden Dragon?”

Most of them didn’t know what was going on. This one was one of the top three elders in the whole clan. They had only seen her bow her head before the Azure Emperor, now she was doing it before his so-called brother. Not many people had really accepted the new player in town that was Long Dong but now after seeing one of the elders bowing before him, they were starting to take him seriously.

“Ah yes, it’s fine. Don’t sweat it old girl but I didn’t really come to you for the flower, I need some directions you see…”

The old woman nodded but wasn’t sure what Zhang Dong’s request was as she didn’t really give him time to explain himself.

“Directions, where would you like to go?”
“When I first came here, my brother brought me to a chamber with that map, could you show me the way there?”

“You wish me to direct you to the secret war room?”

The old woman started rubbing her chin. It was clear that the area with that map was not just something that everyone could visit. But he was convinced that his status should help him gain access to that area.

“Ah yes, now I remember, you had left quite abruptly after the speech, the Emperor was planning to give you access to the War Room. Very well let me guide you towards it.”

‘It seems like I was worrying for nothing.’

Apparently, he was already granted access to this war room. He feared that he would be denied it, but after further consideration, he had already seen the map when the Azure Emperor gave him a short tour.

When leaving that area they just walked to another teleporter that let them outside which was also the reason why he didn’t know where it was exactly. He did check his system map but not like he could bust through the walls of this tower, the long Clan would probably see it as treason or something.

Thus he headed out while following after the old lady. This time around he was sure to pay attention to where he was going. The old woman guided him through what was the giant crystal tower, both of them ended up in some kind of strange large chamber with quite the high ceiling.

There were actually quite a bit of people here. It looked to be some kind of hub and in the distance, he could see people getting on teleportation platforms. They quickly disappeared while covered in blue light. Zhang Dong had to give it to the Long Clan, while his own sect was somewhat advanced they didn’t hold a candle to them in scope.

‘They must be using a massive amount of spiritual energy to run all of these teleporters, then there is that protective barrier and god knows if not more…’

His first opinion of this place might have been faulty as they did clearly build this place to last. It was clear that this was the reason why no one was taking the war that seriously. Perhaps they even had some way of fleeing that made them even more confident.

“Greetings Elder Laixie, what brings you here today… and isn’t that the…”

“Yes, this is the Emperor’s brother, Golden Dragon Long Dong.”

While he had grown accustomed to saying his new name, he still found it strange when other people said it out loud. It was even more peculiar when this name came from an old lady like this.

“I’m sorry honored Golden Dragon, We didn’t expect that you would grace us with your radiant self today!”

The people behind a counter that the old lady brought him to started prostrating themselves before him as usual. He just waited for all the ass-kissing to end before his guide could continue.

“Please give the honored Golden Dragon his identification treasure, it should have been prepared beforehand.”

“Oh?”

Zhang Dong was a bit surprised but it seemed that moves to accommodate him had already been done. Perhaps he should have stayed a bit longer here but if he did, then he would probably not been able to intercept those invaders.

“Ah yes, let me see. Here you go, please place your hand on the crystal orb.”

The clerk that was here brought out a light blue orb that fit more with a wizard than a cultivator setting. He looked at it, then scanned it with his spiritual sense and discovered that it was some kind of scanning device. There didn’t seem that there was a problem with it, thus he just placed his hand on it.

To his surprise, it worked in a similar fashion as the scanners at his own sect. He could feel that this item was trying to read his spiritual sense in some way but if he so desired he could just block it.

“Ah yes, we have your identification crystal with us.”

After the orb did its scan the person behind the counter went to a side room. He could hear sliding doors opening which then were followed by silence. After about five minutes the person returned while holding a small yellow crystal in his hand. On it was the symbol for the Golden Dragon which clearly belonged to him.

“It does seem like it's for me, I reckon these will allow me access to the teleportation arrays around this crystal citadel?”

He asked while somewhat knowing the answer. Others were moving around this area and when they attempted teleportation they always brought out similar-looking crystals. They were all blue and somewhat uniform in design, it was clear that his was a bit more special.

“That’s right, just hold your crystal in front of the seeing orb and you will be able to use it.”

With the crystal in his hand, he turned to the old lady that came with him. He was somewhat aware of what this item would help him do but it was always best to ask for confirmation.

“Let me explain, everything that is important is locked away. There are several layers of protective arrays that seal off the most important places to any non-main clan members.”

The old woman continued to explain while they went towards the largest teleportation station in this area. It was supposedly the only one that would allow him passage into the war room. While he was curious why the Azure Emperor was able to get him there without going through this one area, it was clear that it was due to his title of Emperor.

This area was watched and any teleportation attempt would be logged in the clan database. Even his first attempt and the destination that he was taking was probably going to be marked down. Even this golden crystal would probably not allow him to go unseen.

He was greeted by more cultivators as he approached the console. The old lady gave him some instructions while also telling him that he should be able to visit the war room all by himself now through this place.

It was a strange feeling as he was able to somehow connect through his spiritual energy to this system. In his mind he could see several places that he could access thanks to his golden crystal. But even with it, there were some places that he was not allowed to venture into, most of them belonging to the other three elders and the Azure Emperor.

Finally, after digging through it he selected the war room. With nothing else to do, the old lady bowed again before removing herself from this area. It didn’t seem that she was bothered by him visiting one of their secret locations anymore but that was probably due to there being many nascent soul leveled elders guarding it at all times.

‘So here we are…’

Once more he was back in this place, the biggest difference was quite obvious. The moment he appeared two nascent soul masters gave him the stink eye. But the moment they noticed his face they quickly turned away.

‘I guess my fame travels fast.’

It was clear that someone like him would be known around this place. Being a new big player in town he would garner interest from a lot of people.

‘There it is… this doesn’t look good…’

What he was interested in was the map though, even though there were more guards the map was paramount. Just like before it was there and shining but there was a big difference to the one that he previously saw.

There were various red areas on it, each one at the border. When he moved closer he focused on the place where he tracked Wang Long to, there too he saw the red mark, it was clear that these were the tunnels leading to the other empires.

‘There are none around the area of my sect though…’

He noticed that down to the south of the empire where the location of his city was, there were no closeby red marks. Only at the north, east and west sides did he spot the bridges. The closest one that he could see was the southeast one that would align with the empire of cultivators that he visited for a short time.

‘Okay then, Bob get to work, we need to analyze this map before anyone kicks us out.’

He ordered his Ai while placing his hand on the large table in the middle of the room. From it a holographic map was being projected, if he could figure out what made this thing tick he wouldn’t need to rely on this Long Clan as much.

Chapter 434

‘Well, that cost me an arm and a leg…’

Zhang Dong looked at his ever-dwindling spirit point pool. After teleporting all over the place and finally scanning the map he was running on reserves. Luckily it was a worthy investment as now he would be able to copy the design.

It was something that he didn’t fully understand, the map was connecting to something in this world. It wasn't satellites but something similar, it was receiving information that created this display. Without his AI there would be no possible way of him accessing this outer source.

Bob gave him a roundabout explanation of how this worked. They were in a sense just using the Long Clan maps password while accessing this database on the outside. There didn’t seem to be any firewalls or roadblocks that prevented two of these maps from existing at the same time.

Zhang Dong’s best guess was that whoever created it either didn’t believe that anyone would be able to copy the design or didn’t care. Besides a system user, there would probably not be anyone capable of doing this. The system users were part of this whole predicament and perhaps there even was a way to buy a similar map on the system store.

‘That about covers it… should I go or look around some more…’

There were other people in this room with him, while at first, they did seem somewhat unwelcoming after a while they just started ignoring his presence. With the war having started they probably had other things to worry about. But for some reason, they didn’t really seem to be panicking too much.

‘This war room is a bit too silent… I’d expect there to be some grumpy-looking general shouting at people and ordering them to move out…’

The Long Clan’s main area was right in the middle of the empire. The enemies were flowing in from all directions and there seemed to be more than just three empires flowing in. From what he could tell there were five or six of them.

From the east side came the ones that he interacted with, the toothy ones. From the west side, there was the Emerald Phoenix Empire that he had visited before. This empire came from the upper east side while from the bottom east there were sightings of strange men in golden armor. Then from the north, he also heard of two distinctive camps being formed.

Zhang Dong's city was in the southwestern regions. There he would either meet with the monster-like people that he already tousled with or another empire altogether. In his mind, it would be better to face off against opponents that he had already met.

They were all body refiners that weren’t that great at attacking from range. Those bony body spears might have looked deadly but in reality, it would be hard to hit a very mobile cultivator from range. The best way would be to keep distance as they were clearly more suited for close-quarters combat and pelt them with a vast array of ranged attacks.

“So, about that Goliath thing that my brother mentioned…”

“I apologize but this is not something I can give you information on Golden Dragon. The Azure Emperor is the only one that can answer your question and at the moment he is away.”

Before leaving he was also interested in this thing that the Azure Emperor mentioned. From the name, he figured it to be some kind of large beast or construct? Maybe it was some kind of huge flying ship that would make his Argonaut look like a child’s toy? Regretfully no one was willing to disclose any information and he was not too keen on hanging out with his brother that much.

While Long Qing seemed like a cheerful fellow to hang around with, he wasn’t much different than other cultivators. This he proved by denying aid to him, it was clear that he only cared about his own city and the people living in it.

The map in this chamber clearly showed the movements of the invaders but they were just waiting. From what he could tell, they were anticipating the middle-sized sects and the smaller clans to all be forced back towards the middle of the empire.

Probably after gathering all the nascent soul masters under their own banner would they start their counterattack. He wouldn’t be surprised if the Heavenly Crane Sect along with the Long Clan forced the smaller sects to act as meat shields.

They would probably send out some of their nascent soul masters to direct them. Only if the situation became dire, would they act and offer up some of their own resources. This wasn’t a bad plan but this depended on the strength of their opponents. If they waited too long, the enemies could become too powerful to resist and at that point, they would have lost most of the middle-sized sects.

‘What about me… I can’t just fly around and rescue people…’

Zhang Dong found fault in this tactic but he also couldn't deny it. As a leader himself, he knew that everyone was working with limited resources. They couldn’t just offer up aid and put their cultivators at risk to save other sects. Without knowing if the other party returned the favor later it was better to not risk losing your devoted sect brothers.

‘I guess I’m not that much better than these guys…’

After giving out a sigh he remained in this chamber for a moment to look around. Besides the map, there wasn’t really anything of note. Without having any allies in the Long Clan, there was not much he could affect.

He could either try waiting here to convince his brother to help out but he was sure that he would be told to take his people and move them here. But they would probably only allow him to bring the most elite members from his sect and family. The rest of the citizens would be then left to fend for themselves.

“Well, tell my brother that I’ll be returning to my own sect.”

The man he was talking to looked to be in charge here. He was not one of the three high elders that he met before. Luckily he was taking his status as the Golden Dragon seriously.

“I will pass on the information so that it reaches the Azure Dragon’s ear, but it would be faster if lord Golden Dragon visited the Azure palace himself, the Emperor should be coming back soon, it shouldn’t take more than a week.”

“A whole week?”

“Yes, because of the coming invasion we must be careful of anyone trying to infiltrate our area, only the Emperor has enough skill to see through disguises.”

“Ah, is that so…”

It seemed that Long Qing served a similar role of a spy detector like he did to his own sect. There would probably be a lot of panic due to these invaders. During this, it would be smart to replace some of the refugees with spies.

In this world filled with disguising techniques, some of the prominent cultivators could even be replaced. If such a thing occurred they would be sitting on a time bomb without knowing when someone would stab them in the back.

‘I guess I could just call him with my system… but not like he can show me his superweapons while he is out…’

Zhang Dong had gone through all the books and through some of the clan’s secrets. He did not know everything but it would need to be enough. Without any proper pull here, there was also no way of prying away some of the clan’s resources out.

For the time being, he would need to rely on his own people. They had been taking over the lands of the once active Dark Palm Sect, now these lands were theirs.

“I’ll be leaving then.”

After checking everything out he decided to use the teleportation station to get out. The crystal they gave him was also very interesting and Bob was already trying to examine it. It would require more spirit points to crack so for the time being it was put on the backburner.

…

“Husband, you have returned? Are you alright? Have you been eating enough?”

After getting out of the war room, Zhang Dong went to a more secluded location and teleported back to his new home. He used the faction teleportation to arrive at the location of his wife. The moment he popped out, Liena jump on him as if she was afraid that he was a ghost or something.

“Eating? Well, I didn’t really have time to make any stops but don’t worry, I had somebody nourishing pills with me.”

He could only smile while petting Liena on the back. During his chase for Wang Long, he made many stops along the way but not to take a break. For someone of his caliber, this would be enough as at this point his body was far removed from regular humans. He could survive months, perhaps even a year without eating anything.

“How are you though? Have the kids been good?”

“The children? Yes, every day you are out they ask me where you are… I’m slowly running out of excuses, you should go visit them if you have the time. You do have time now, right?”

“Well…”

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh, he would really like to enjoy his time with his children and lovely wife but he couldn’t. There was so much going on outside that he didn’t know if they would have a home to return to the next day. Any of the empires could pop up in their lands and it would end in a bloody conflict.

“I’m not sure I will have that much to spare in the coming days, you know what is at stake yourself…”

Everyone had been informed about the state of affairs. The evacuation of the sect didn’t go through last time so they didn’t need to worry about that anymore. Their citizens from the city started flocking back though as they were left in the forest area to survive in tents while battling beasts in the wild.

“I know but at least show that you are alive, it will mean a lot to them.”

Zhang Dong nodded as he knew that to his family he was gone for five years. He had returned only recently and they were probably worried that in the coming war he would vanish yet again. His relationship with his kids had been somewhat rekindled but he knew that if he wasn’t there again it would quickly deteriorate.

Thus he made a decision to go see his children while also contacting various members of his sect via his system. Someone like him that was a powerful cultivator could easily multitask so playing patty cake with his daughter and talking to Huo Qiang at the same time wouldn’t be that hard.

‘So, you have secured it?’

‘Yes, it looks the same as it did. Will we be going through the tests again? I don’t think we can enter it at this point, will the juniors be tasked with this?’

Huo Qiang asked while looking at a familiar ruin. It was the same one where he and Zhang Dong met for the first time and also the place where part of the Dark Palm sect just vanished. Now it was in their territory and waiting to be explored again.

Chapter 435

‘That will be enough.’

‘Are you sure Patriarch? We could still take over more of the lost lands?’

‘No, this will do, the more land we have the harder it will be to defend. The spirit stone mines will do nicely and also remember to take any thunderstones that you find.’

‘As you command, Patriarch.’

Zhang Dong closed the connection with Zhang Zhi that was wrapping up their hostile takeover. Most of the Dark Palm Sect’s old lands had been reclaimed by his people. He was not interested in the cities though, what he wanted was access to the secret ground he once visited.

There he hoped to find some help to get him past this coming crisis. If not help then perhaps some answers concerning the true nature of this world that he was in. With the secret ground now being in his own territory and his new status as the Golden Dragon, there was no one to stop him.

“Daddy?”

“Ah sorry, did I space out?”

He looked down, there in his lap was his young daughter. She wasn’t the only person he was with, his son was playing in the courtyard with the new toy robot. It seemed that the youngster wasn’t as scared of him anymore.

“Hmph! You should pay more attention!”

Zhang Xiu puffed out her cheeks while turning her head away from her father. The two were playing some cards, a game that he himself brought into this world. His child was quite smart but even she couldn’t beat someone that was using spirit sense to peek at their cards. That is if he actually used to win but instead, he let the child be victorious instead.

“Haha, daddy was just sad that he lost so much, you’re just too strong Xiu.”

Xiu started smiling brightly after getting praised by her father. The little girl was quite fond of challenging people to various exercises. He didn’t know where she got it from but whenever she lost in anything she would pester the person for a rematch until victory was hers. Thus it was better to surrender unless he wanted to have her cling to his thigh to constantly ask for another go.

“Why don’t you go play with your brother while mommy and daddy talk?”

“Okay!”

The small girl left after Liena spoke up. After the kids were away playing, she posed a question.

“Are you really going to try to enter that secret ground by yourself?”

“I see that word goes around…”

“Did you really think you could hide this from me?”

Zhang Dong gulped as he didn’t really want to tell his wife that he was placing himself at risk. The place he was going was sort of a no man's land. After the Dark Palm Sect discovered it and even after their downfall other sects and clans attempted to claim it.

Even though some of them managed to get past the initial part just like the Zhang Clan did, it was a dead end. Each time when it was finished there would be a giant suction force sucking people through a large gate. Afterward weeks, months, and then years would pass without anyone coming back.

Due to this, the area had been deemed a hazardous zone, no one was allowed to enter it. The sects had lost many nascent soul elders to the strange trap. They were unable to figure out if they were doing something wrong and Zhang Dong had a suspicion that no one besides him could actually get past that locked gate.

“I will be fine, I will just teleport back here if something goes wrong.”

“You didn’t ‘just’ teleport the first time you went missing.”

“Well… that was a bit…”

“Different? So there are places that you can’t just get back from!”

His wife narrowed her eyes at him while he turned his head away. It was true the system he was using wasn’t omnipotent. The place he was going to was built by a previous user that was somehow able to hack it. It wouldn’t be strange if that person knew a way to keep him from teleporting out of there but in Zhang Dong’s mind, the danger was minimal.

It was that secret ground that set everything in motion. The first cube that he absorbed set him free of the system that was now different. His theory was that he was probably the only person that would be accepted by that immortal abode. The whole place was probably made as a test for his kind. Only people with an altered system would probably be allowed to fully enter it.

“I’m just going to check it out a bit, I’m not going to use the testing ground, I hope to find a side entrance…”

Zhang Dong started to explain himself to Liena. She knew that he wasn’t just a regular cultivator, his old name was also revealed a long time ago/ In his mind the testing ground was just bait to get system holders in. There might be a different entrance that he could go through now.

“Fine, go and leave me and the kids again, we will be just fine!”
“... Don’t be that way my wife, I’m not doing it for selfish reasons, I think the knowledge there could help us through the coming war.”

Liena puffed up her cheeks in a similar fashion to her daughter which made Zhang Dong chuckle. While he knew where she was coming from, it had to be done. The mysteries buried in that strange place could help them through this coming event and this might be also the last time he would be able to examine it. When the war started there might not be space to maneuver, it could be even destroyed during the fighting.

“Fine, but you better contact me regularly!”

Finally, his wife gave in as she knew that there was no way to stop him from going. But he would certainly not put himself at risk there. The situation was not so dire for him to grasp at straws yet. He was strong enough to battle with the toughest nascent soul masters on the continent already. His cultivation was constantly increasing and with more spirit stones coming over, he would only continue to progress.

Thus after having a moment with his wife and kids he set out to the place where it all started. To his knowledge, the secret ground was later named the ghostly immortal’s abode. It was rumored to have been created by a long-dead cultivator and everyone that tried to venture past the gates had never returned.

Time was of the essence so he used up the last of his spirit points to teleport to Zhang Zhi’s location. Thankfully his most trusted retainer had been tasked with securing spirit stones for him.

“Zhang Zhi greets the Patriarch!”

While the samurai was not surprised by him just popping out of the blue, the other sect members were. The moment they saw their silver-haired leader they dropped their heads. Not everyone was used to seeing him but Zhang Dong had already gotten used to how much he was revered in his own sect.

“At ease, I think you have some spirit stones for me?”

Zhang Zhi nodded while handing him a spatial ring. Inside there were many large and small spirit stones along with thunderstones that were just crystallized lightning energy. With these in his position, he could finally resume nourishing his cores. After absorbing so much holy energy and soul energy he was only missing lightning to make a small jump.

“I will be entering the secret ground myself, make sure that I’m not bothered by anyone.”

“T-this…”

Instead of a resounding ‘Yes Patriarch.’ he received a lukewarm response. Zhang Zhi apparently didn’t agree with this plan and he knew why.

“You don’t need to worry, I’m not going to be taking any tests that this immortal’s abode offers, I’m just going to see if I can find a side entrance, if I can’t find anything I’ll just return.”

“As you wish.”

It was clear that Zhang Zhi was opposed to letting him just wander in there on his own. But the other cultivators would just get in the way. Then if he found a side entrance, he wasn’t sure how the abode would react to non-system users like his sect members. They might find themselves whisked away like all the other nascent soul masters before them.

After taking the spatial ring he made his way towards the secret ground. Even before entering it he could feel the presence of a formation here. It had been created to keep lower leveled cultivators out but for him it was childsplay.

Soon he ended up at the exact location where his old clan ship arrived. Zhang Dong stopped for a moment as the memory had been imprinted in his brain. On one side he remembered his now-wife Liena sticking out her tongue at him. Then in another location was Huo Qiang that was surrounded by women and alcohol.

“Time really does fly, I didn't think I would be returning here.”

In all honesty, Zhang Dong would rather spend his time with his family than be out adventuring. If it wasn’t for the impending doom he would just be homemaking toys for his son while trying to catch up.

“Before this all started I never thought I would have my own kids… I guess some good came from this strange world…”

He shook his head to snap out of it. This was not the time to reminisce about his old life that he hardly remembered. The old him from earth wasn’t there anymore, his new persona of Zhang Dong had since taken over while Matt was now a distant memory.

‘Bob, be sure to scan the area for any potential entry points.’

‘Affirmative.’

While getting closer he took out some of the spirit stones from the spatial ring he received. Soon they turned to dust as he absorbed them for more spirit points. With his reserves replenished he would now be able to teleport back to Zhang Zhi if there were any problems.

“Still looks as gloomy as I remember…”

He passed through the entrance, the place was deserted. It was clear that no one had enough courage to make another trip. But with his knowledge and the help of his little AI partner he was sure that there was something he could find here.

‘Hidden entrance point found, forwarding data to the map.’

No sooner did he enter the abode that he received a message from Bob. His system map was marked by him instantly, it seemed that there really was a way to enter for him. Now it remained to be seen, was there something there to help him or would this be a dead end.

A note from Kuropon

I've decided to pause Patreon for the next month which means that my stories will be on hold for about a month. If you want more info please go to the Patreon link.

https://www.patreon.com/posts/61615744

Chapter 436

“Are you sure we are going the right way?”

‘Affirmative, the entrance is exactly 457,45 meters north-east.’

“Ah yes, sure it is…”

Zhang Dong looked at the red marker on his minimap. While what Bob said might have been true he was calculating the distance in a straight line. At this moment in time, he was walking through some dark corridors filled with cobwebs.

This part of this secret ground was unknown to him as he had never visited it before. The last time he was here they were all shoved into the testing chamber and teleported away. All the other passages were blocked off by the Dark Palm Sect cultivators. Finally, after all these years he was able to examine this place in detail.

There was actually a series of corridors under the whole structure. When looking at his map he was now somewhere under the trial chamber. Apparently somewhere under here, there was a secret entrance that the Dark Palm Sect didn’t discover.

“Some of these tunnels had been dug up, probably they were trying to find another entrance like me.”

It was clear by how it looked down here that the Dark Palm Sect and perhaps the sects that came after it were excavating this site. There were half-finished tunnels everywhere, it was clear that they tried to dig their way behind that large chamber door.

“This rock structure… No wonder they were itching to get in.”

Zhang Dong punched one of the walls after injecting his fist full of Qi. The ground shook but instead of the wall being smashed into pieces his knuckles were injured. The material that the walls were made with was clearly something above the level of regular cultivators.

The stone was incredibly hard but not the same as the one that he discovered at the cube location. There was also no dark spot in his minimap which confirmed his theory that this was something else. The person that made this structure was probably someone with a system like him. It was possible that he either bought the knowledge on how to build this place from the system store.

He arrived at his destination. Many tunnels were leading to this large cavern that had been dugout. He could see at least half a kilometer of nothing but white walls from left to right. The cultivation nuts clearly didn’t give up lightly and tried to find some kind of weak spot here but weren’t able to continue.

‘This makes it seem that the immortal abode is here and it doesn’t just teleport us to some kind of distant location.’

These white walls spread in all directions. He could feel some spiritual energy that was reinforcing them and absorbing any hits that he delivered. In most cases, such structures required some sort of power source to keep their effects. But it could also just be some special material.

“It should be somewhere here…”

He floated up into the air, the walls were quite smooth and uniform in all directions. On the ground, he could see some destroyed tools such as pickaxes that were probably used to attempt a breach. With the help of his minimap marker, he was finally able to find the entrance spot.

“Well then, do your thing, Bob… I don’t really feel anything out of the ordinary here…”

After pressing his palm on the smooth wall he tried to examine it with his spiritual sense. There wasn’t anything that he could spot, it was clear that without the system he would be unable to venture any further.

‘Interfacing… please wait…’

Zhang Dong felt a bit apprehensive about overusing Bob. It was still unclear to him what this AI program was. For the time being it was helping him, without Bob he would have been unable to return from that other world. But this also didn’t mean that this being wouldn’t somehow betray him in the future.

There were stories of cultivators leaving a slither of their being in items. Then they would use some occult means to inject them into other cultivators. Slowly they would grow in power and finally at a certain juncture they would strike. When the cultivator was at a weak point they would try to overtake their very soul and body. What if Bob was leading him into certain doom and the person that made him would try to take over his body?

‘That’s a possibility but with how big my soul has gotten I’m not sure if they will have it easy…’

This was a possibility though it was somewhat far-fetched. For the time being, he could only throw this reasoning to the back of his head while venturing forward. As he was worrying Bob finally was done with his interfacing and a strange sound of pressurized air came from the wall.

‘...Task complete, opening… please stand by.’

He flinched slightly as a door appeared before him. It opened upwards while accompanied by screeching. It was clear that this opening had not been used for quite some time, even some dust had crept in.

‘I guess here goes nothing…’

It was finally time to take the plunge inside, he couldn’t really see much as there was no light. Even though he tried to use his spiritual sense to see what was inside he couldn’t see anything past the entrance. There was probably some kind of high level formation blocking him from peeking inside.

‘Well, I found a side entrance as I told you, I’ll be going inside now, I’m not sure how long it will take me.’

‘Please be careful.’

As he ventured forward he made sure to inform his wife as he promised. He wasn't sure how long it would take him or if he would be able to use his system to communicate with her after entering his place.

Finally, he propelled himself gently forward and vanished into the darkened room. As soon as he was inside the entrance closed behind him. Now on the inside, his golden aura lit the way forward as it was clear that the space he was occupying had not been used for many millennia.

‘The air in here is stale…’

He found himself in another corridor to the side he could see something orb-like stuck to the wall. It was some kind of round crystal that he was somewhat familiar with.

‘Bob… Can you turn on the lights?’

After a moment these round objects that were embedded in the wall started to flicker. Even though they were clearly unused, they still were in working order. The path forward continued to be illuminated before him and in the distance, he could see a fork in the road.

‘Before that… can you hear me?... hello…?’

Zhang Dong frowned as what he had feared came true. He could not contact his wife or anyone else from his sect. It was clear that this person that made this was going against the person that made the system. Thus it was natural that he would have something in place to block it from interfering.

Even then he had hoped that thanks to Bob he might be able to contact his wife and others. But even with the hacked version of the system he could not. Perhaps he would need to gain full access to this immortal abode before he could send his message.

‘Are you still working Bob?’

‘Affirmative, all systems are nominal. The faction function is being blocked, do you wish to examine the issue?’

‘Yes do that while I look around.’

Without anything else to do he moved forward. The corridor was now quite bright and even though there were no cobwebs here the place seemed quite old. It was clear that whoever lived here before was long gone.

At first, the corridor was mostly empty with the same sense blocking walls keeping him from peering outside but soon he ended up at a fork in the road. While he could see the end of the path he came from, this one stretched for far too much for him to see.

There were three paths he could take, one leading forward, one to the left, and another one to the right. He looked up in hopes of finding some kind of sign but there was none. It was clear that whoever made this place didn’t care about intruders knowing their way.

‘Everything in here is made from this strange material, I can’t sense anything…’

He could only narrow his eyes while floating up. The corridors were about four meters wide and ten meters high which allowed him to see further in. While two of the paths were the same there was something he spotted on the right side. Instead of the white walls, he noticed something out of place which made him decide on this way.

‘Is that… glass?’

It was somewhat surprising but he was sure that he was seeing a reflective surface from a distance. After arriving at the spot, the thing he discovered put things into perspective.

“Wait, isn't this… I’ve been there before…”

What he saw was not a room or anything but a wide expanse of land. It was a forest area, the same exact zone that he was sent to when he was taking the trial with the other core formation cultivators at that time.

What he found was a window that gave him a clear look down but the distance from the landmass below was quite tremendous. There must have been some kind of spatial formation here as there was far too much land down there.

Below him was the vast area where he met his wife and Huo Qiang. The memories of battling strange monsters and the trials with the seven sins folded his mind. He quickly recalled some key landmarks which were actually there. The only strange part was that there didn’t seem to be any monsters around.

“Maybe only when the trial gets triggered from the outside do the monsters appear?”

This place probably took up a tremendous amount of spiritual energy to run. It would be smart to turn it off while there are no people taking the test. The area was also shrouded in darkness and only thanks to his enhanced vision and ability to see in the dark could he see anything.

He was at the right place but where should he go? The paths continued in various directions and there was no way to know where to go. His minimap was also not showing him the way as the system blockers extended past the communication blocking.

“This might take a while… but perhaps I should go in the direction of that final trial?”

Without knowing where to go, he decided to go towards the zone where he faced off against the pride demon. There he found all of the current books and scripts that made him what he was today. Perhaps there he would find some more answers.

Chapter 437

“It’s not as big on the outside as it is on the inside, a strange sight to behold…”

While floating through the wide corridor Zhang Dong spotted more windows into the trial grounds. They were spaced out by somewhat a large distance but this distance seemed to expand by at least ten times when he peeked to the inside.

This was the first time that he saw this kind of spatial formation that was divided. While he traveled a hundred meters in the corridor it was as if he went through a whole kilometer on the inside.

He continued to look but there were no of those monsters to be seen. The inside was in some kind of stasis that would probably only be removed when a group of cultivators came to challenge the test.

Then finally after going in one direction he came before a door. It was not closed to him and he didn’t need to use Bob to hack it either. After entering through it he found himself in another area with more windows. There he could spot areas that he had already visited, ones that he faced of the seven deadly sins-themed bosses.

Like the other areas, there was nothing in the rooms and the signs of combat were gone. He tried to recall those days, some of them were spent battling the monsters. He could clearly remember damaging the surroundings in some of the fights but it seemed that this place could somehow repair itself.

“Is someone living here that repaired it? or is there some kind of formation that can put it back into place?”

Even if there were some type of beings doing the repairs he expected them to be more like the monsters. The easiest way would be to create some automatons that performed restorative efforts after a test was done. From what he knew, the tests couldn’t be carried out constantly. This place clearly needed time to repair itself for the next batch of combatants.

“Should I try breaking through it…”

After tapping on the glass a couple of times he realized that it was also made from some strange material. It was not as hard as the walls though and would probably be unable to resist his punches. The trials didn’t allow nascent soul masters in them so these windows might not have been made resistant enough.

For the time being, he decided to not cause trouble. Perhaps if he attempted this the whole place could become active or some kind of defensive mechanism could be triggered. If the walls could be made from this strange resistant material then perhaps so could defensive constructs.

Thus he arrived at a flight of winding stairs that brought him up, there he also discovered the library from where he borrowed most of his current knowledge. All the books were still there and if other cultivators were here they would probably already be busting through the windows to get to those old scriptures.

But this didn’t seem to be the end so he continued to go up. The whole place was giving him a strange feeling. He clearly wasn’t able to see these glass windows when he was on the other side but from here he could peek inside of the testing ground with ease.

It was as if someone or something was watching them battle for their lives for their amusement. But perhaps this was something of an age long past, this whole place looked deserted. There was no sign of anything living going through these corridors, the whole place was probably just operating on some old directive.

“That’s quite a drop…”

He continued to go up the stairs for some time but they didn’t seem to end. It was clear that he had entered through another spatial formation that extended this tower of stairs even further. But without any directions, he could only continue and finally after about an hour of traveling he arrived at the end.

“Only the worthy may pass?”

There were actual words written above this chamber, their meaning didn’t really matter but there was something peculiar about it. The words were not in mandarin, no they were in English.

After coming to this world he had seen some strange mix of cultures that didn’t fit the theme of this world. He realized that this was probably due to many other system users shaping their cities to fit their more modern style. Seeing English words was not out of the ordinary but it also made it obvious that they were meant for people like him.

Thus he took a step forward and placed his hand on the large door ring. The moment he did, he could feel an outward force scanning his body. Before he knew it, there was a click, and as he started pulling the door quickly creaked open.

With haste he let go of the ring-shaped door handle but even when he waited for something to attack him there was only silence. With slow steps he moved forward to peek inside and what he saw was not something that he expected.

“This room… Is that a beanbag chair?... This…”

The room wasn’t that large but it reminded him of his old apartment. There was a gaming chair right next to a desk with three large curved monitors. Nothing was turned on but the PC that the monitors were connected to would probably have some nice RGB coloring.

This room reminded him of the secret one that he made at his own sect. It seemed that whoever lived here had a similar longing for their old life as a gamer. To the side, he could also spot a large bed and a projector next to it probably used to watch movies or perhaps spy on the people performing the tests.

“I guess this is the place where the system user hung out?”

The chamber wasn’t too big and there were some windows there. When peeking out of them he had a clear view at the last area where his old Zhang Clan did their tower defense session. But after going around a couple of times he couldn’t really find anything, it seemed that he would need to turn that computer on to see if it worked.

‘Bob, can you sense something?’

‘Negative, unable to connect.’

“Hm… oh, haven’t seen this in years…”

Hidden away to the side was something that he used to be familiar with. It looked like an old console but in actuality, it was a router. Even though he wasn't that pedantic about his man cave where he only placed monitors in, the rest wasn’t really fashioned to mimic the look of technology from his old world.

He felt like he was back home, the thoughts of returning back from work to only turn on his computer and play games for the rest of the day flooded his mind. But it was a flood of stagnant memories of not doing anything interesting every day. Probably if he was not so bored with his life back there, he would have ignored that e-mail as some spam attempt.

But this wasn’t the time to reminisce about his old life. The person that he was before was now only a small part of his persona. His whole family and sect depended on his next few decisions and he needed more information to decide.

The computer along with the router were turned on by him and even though these things were quite old, they did work. He saw a strange logo on the monitor that looked like some kind of crystal flying sword which was probably the calling sign of the person that created all of this.

It didn’t take long for the PC to boot and place him in the operating system, but there was a little problem.

“Password? Hey, Bob could you… wait…”

At first, he wanted to have Bob use some of his magic to hack into this system but he noticed a question sign to the right side. On it was a tip for the password. He grabbed what looked to be a gaming mouse and placed the cursor over this question mark.

”Guess What Came In The Mail Today?...”

He had to pause for a moment before realizing that he probably knew what the answer to the password was. He slowly hovered his fingers towards the keyboard that was lit up like a rainbow and started typing.

“This guy sure is something…”

Zhang Dong wanted to facepalm after writing in the password. The person he was dealing with had a similar juvenile sense of humor as he did before. But he wasn’t sure if the person ever expected someone to come here and look through his computer.

He was greeted by a background of a rather voluptuous lady dressed in some ribbons that covered most of the naughty parts in a strategic fashion. There wasn’t really that much on the desktop that he could see besides a few folders and what looked to be executables.

There was no use staring at them so he started clicking away. The first thing he clicked was an icon of a camera, it took only a moment for it to show him some kind of software with hundreds of small icons.

When clicking one he was shown the inside of the training ground that for now, was devoid of much movement. Luckily the plants were still alive and there was some kind of small breeze so he could see some small amount of movement.

After clicking through it he was sure that this was the monitoring system. While he found all of the places that he visited before he could also see the outside of this secret ground. He could even see Zhang Zhi in the distance patrolling the area and unaware that he was being watched.

There were also some chambers that he hadn’t seen before. One of them looked to be something like a dining area, then there was a large pool with crystal clear water with waterfalls. But even after clicking through place after place, he didn’t discover any signs of life or any leftover automatons that could tell him what had happened here.

“This one… I think this is behind that large gate…”

At least the secret to what was behind the door that sucked those cultivators in was revealed to him. He clearly recognized the other side of it which led to a large teleportation platform. There wasn’t anything in there, it seemed that anyone that was sucked in had been teleported to another location.

“Not much to find here… what does this folder have…”

He turned his attention from the camera system to one of the folders that was named ‘Old videos’. After clicking he found a massive amount of old footage that came from other trials. There was even footage of people dying or being sucked into that teleportation chamber.

Then after fiddling through some of that footage he found a subfolder. It seemed that this was what he was looking for. After going into it, he found some recordings and from the thumbnail, he could see that the person was sitting in the same chair he was in. It looked to be some type of video diary of the person that created this place, it was finally time to see what this was all about.

Chapter 438

A note from Kuropon

Well, I'm off for my break o/

“Testing, one…two…three… Think it’s working… this feels kind of strange.”

Zhang Dong was looking at a person in an old video. There was some kind of date on it but it didn’t make much sense to the system they had now. This made it seem that this was recorded before the current dating system was put in place.

‘The current dating system dates back to a hundred thousand years, it probably started right after the last war between empires. If the timer gets restarted every hundred thousand years, there is no way of knowing how old this is.’

First, he took a good look at the person that was recording himself. Just like any other system users that he had seen, he was quite handsome. It was clear that the people chosen for this position wanted to make themselves look the best and he was the same.

The person looked more like a traditional cultivator but he wasn’t that young. His hair was a mix of black and silver that had appeared due to age. Either the person had gone with the elder option in his e-mail or he had just spent quite a bit of time in this world. But judging that it would probably take many years to build a place like this, he was sure it was the latter.

He didn’t look as old as some of the elders, at most he was about fifty. But it would be hard to tell his true age with just the appearance. Nascent soul masters lived to around a thousand years and depending on their cultivation they could keep their youthful look even into their older years. This person had the system with them, so even here he could already be nine hundred.

“I did it, I have managed to create this testing ground. With it I will be able to find more people like me, by that I mean people with a system! I know that you are out there, I can’t be the only one…”

It seemed that this person was really the one that figured out the secrets of the system but as it was starting to get to the good part, the video was cut off. Zhang Dong realized that this computer was quite old and even if it looked fine from the outside there was a limit at which data could be stored.

When he tried to click the next video after it, he was shown a corrupt image with no sound. Other ones wouldn’t even start playing and Bob was also unable to reconstruct the corrupt data.

‘It’s already a miracle that this thing didn’t crumble into dust, it's at least a hundred thousand years old…’

Without much to do, he continued to go through the many videos one by one. Finally, he was able to play a part of it, in this video, the man looked a lot older. His skin had some wrinkles and his hair was now almost fully gray. His eyes also looked tired, it was as if he didn’t sleep for some time.

“Log number 59… ah whoever cares, not like anyone will ever see this… but anyway…”

The man gave out a sigh while leaning back in the gaming chair recreation.

“I have been unable to discover any other people like me, it has been many thousands of years, no one was able to finish this trial and no other system could be discovered. I have been putting myself into stasis to prolong my life but there is a limit on how much time I have…End log”

The video cut so he continued to the next one.

“Log number 245… I’m getting tired, so I went outside to stretch my legs… my old sect is no more, I don’t recognize anyone… I don’t think anyone from my bloodline is alive anymore…”

“567… It has been a hundred thousand years… the war cycle has repeated… but no other of my kind has appeared and I know the reason. I have made an error in my calculations, unless I cut off from the source no one will come… without a new system user the empire has no chance of winning, they have retreated into the center but they will survive… I know what I must do…”

“569… I know how to remove myself from the system but I’m too old to survive the procedure. Only when close to death is this possible and by prolonging my life artificially I will certainly die, I must leave this in the hands of someone else. I have updated the trials but I’m unsure if it will work… there are too many variables that could go wrong… I have decided to ascend.”

“571… I am planning to ascend today, this will be the last time. Even after living for this long, I do not wish to die, I am afraid… I know that something is waiting for me, I don’t know what it wants and why it created this game-like world, I know that there are others like me but I’m unable to travel to them at this point, I only hope that the person watching this can meet me on the other side…”

“The ascension to the immortal realm is impossible for anyone other than a system user. I made a discovery, there were several realms between the immortal realm and the nascent soul realm that had been stricken from history. Without this knowledge, it is impossible for regular cultivators to bridge the gap. The step from the nascent soul all the way to the immortal realm is certain death.”

“Only if you give yourself to the system, is ascension possible but what awaits on the other side, I don’t know… After ascending you will be forced to leave this realm, it will be unable to contain your new realm and reject your very being. I hope that I’m wrong and what waits for me on the other side is not certain death but I’m out of options, I have no way of prolonging my life anymore so I hope this message reaches someone who can pave a new path…”

After going through all of these videos he had an idea of what had been happening here. Each video showed the man being older and older. It seemed that he was using some type of device to halt his aging, something akin to cryogenic sleep.

The man would put himself to sleep for thousands of years and come out on certain occasions to check if the testing ground brought any system holders out. He also spoke about altering the system but being unable to fully cut himself from it. He was still connected which was the reason that he was unable to find any other system user.

This made him remember that fateful day when he was cut away from the system. He must have been injected with this man’s program but only when he almost died did it sever him from the source. He had almost died back there but he was somehow able to survive which was a miracle of its own. The person here was unwilling to go through the process himself and chose to ascent to a higher realm.

This was a very widespread trope in the xianxia world. There were certain limits to the world the main protagonist always found themselves in, after reaching that ceiling what remained was to go through it. This would be done by reaching a higher realm of power and then ascending to a brand new world.

Then they would find themselves somewhere with more realms and new locations to discover. Their adventure would continue again where they would have more time to progress and go against stronger foes. It was like a perpetual adventure where there was no one to it until the person became a full-fledged god-like being that could do whatever they wanted.

The person also confirmed one of his theories, there were other realms beyond the nascent soul level. It did seem strange to him that there was a massive leap from the nascent soul level all the way to the immortal realm. But it seemed that this was by design, it was supposed to limit the non-system users from ever achieving this degree of power.

“This timeline, he ascended somewhere around the time there was a war between the empires…”

The Azure Dragon had informed him that the battle had been mostly lost in the old days. Only by sacrifice and bunkering up in the previous capital were they able to last through it all. This would mostly mean that this person built this secret ground two hundred thousand years ago and it lasted to this day when the new war had started.

Somehow this man had probably been victorious in his version of the empire war. Then he figured out how to hack the system before attempting to make contact with other system users. He was probably trying to gain some allies to figure out what everything was about.

Zhang Dong was unsure of the extent of this man’s hacking capabilities. He was unable to totally strip himself of the system but it didn’t seem that any of the watchers were utilized to get to him. Perhaps because he wasn’t causing any world-ending calamities or altering the rules of the world, there were no repercussions.

When he visited the world of sword and magic, he was a being that affected the power balance. Perhaps only when someone past the nascent soul level threshold would the system mods become alert. His current enhanced core formation realm might be a problem now because if he ever made it into the higher realm, it could go against the rules.

“I guess I’ll have to prepare… but this doesn’t really give me any answers…”

These revelations weren't anything new to him. In some sense, he knew more things than this person as he had actually visited another world. It was apparently a miracle that he was even alive after the incident in this trial.

But it did bring up some questions, what was waiting for him out there. If he reached a new realm here would he be forced to leave his family and friends behind? It was apparently impossible to sustain oneself in this world after attaining the immortal realm. What was waiting out there for him? It could be just another world to explore and have fun with or death.

“Not like I want to be immortal… if I can see my kids grow up and have their own families…”

He gave out a sigh as he didn’t really care that much about living for longer than a thousand years. What he was fighting for was his new family, if he could assure their survival then it was enough. But if this world could be erased at a snap of a finger was also a possibility.

For now, he decided to look around some more. Perhaps there would be more information about the coming war. The person that created this testing ground certainly said that they went through their own adventure. If he could find some new weapons to aid him in the coming battles, then it would still be a very fortuitous encounter.

Chapter 439

‘There really isn’t much here…’

Zhang Dong, was now looking at a room that had been turned upside down. After going through the PC he attempted to find other information that could at least help him out of the current problem.

The person living here was probably the same that he saw after running into the first proper cube. At the twilight of his years, he decided to ascend to the immortal realm as he could not fully cut himself away from the system.

There were some possibilities here, the man could have been over-exaggerating of what happened after one ascended. He could have still been alive to this very day. This old man was convinced that there was something out there and that it was out to get him. If he transcended the nascent soul realm fully, he was done for.

From Zhang Dong’s perspective that was one of the possibilities. There were various other worlds out there besides this one. This person might have just been transported into the next stage of the adventure and with the increased realm could have lived to this day.

There were traces left of him in those energy cubes that were trying to contact him. While he wasn’t sure if it was the same person it pointed towards him. There was no new information in this room that he didn’t already know. If he didn’t visit the other world before coming here he would probably be shocked to make this discovery.

‘This guy probably didn’t keep many books or notes around…’

He started rubbing his chin after looking at the room that he turned upside down. The person he was dealing with was a system user. The system could store all the information in the user’s brain. There was no purpose of writing things down or keeping any outside data storage.

What he was looking, for now, was any old records about the war that this old system holder went through. The computer that was working the data was encrypted and corrupt. He had Bob try to examine it all but there was just too much to go through.

It wasn’t possible to divide the important information, he could only order Bob to decrypt from the start to the end. If he got anything worthwhile out of it that was unknown to him, the first batch of information could just give him a list of useless techniques that he already knew and not the historical records he needed.

He wanted to unplug this ancient computer and take it with him. There was a small problem as it was connected to the router which granted him access to the cameras in this place. It also could be used to open some previously hidden rooms that led out of this room. Thus for the time being he decided to leave it here, after he was done exploring he would decide if he would take it with him.

It seemed that everything had been plugged into this PC but it was an ancient treasure. It had probably been two hundred thousand years since this place had been constructed. This device could be just as old and it was slowly falling apart. The materials that they were made with were strange and unfamiliar to him.

‘I guess I can only continue, can’t put a teleportation point here. It was clear that this person didn’t want other system users to just be able to invade his home.’

After using the computer he was able to open a side room. The door slid to the side to reveal another corridor that he was now going through. This time around the journey was a lot shorter.

“Was this the rest of his home?”

When he walked out he was greeted to an overgrown mansion, it was covered in various plants and vines. This place had not been put into stasis which probably caused everything to continue growing. Besides the plants he could not spot any life signals though, not even insects existed.

This home looked like a regular house that would probably be able to contain a family of four or five. There was a wooden fence along with a garage that was open. In the garage, he could see a replica of an old car model that he once saw in a magazine.

“Did he remake his old family home here?”

It seemed that the cultivator that created this place had a longing for his old life, one that was stronger than Zhang Dong’s. He cherished his current new family more than the one he left. This made sense as this man did put himself through some kind of life-prolonging process.

He clearly didn’t care that much about the people here, if he did growing old with them would probably be more important than leaving. To Zhang Dong doing something like outgrowing his children would feel strange, he would rather pave the way for them so that his kids had a brighter future.

But this did align with this person’s goals as well, he needed to know what was out there. A chance of this world being erased at a whim was a possibility. From what he could tell that only when a system user was dead or ascended was another one chosen. Thus if he killed Wang Long something that he had not planned could come to pass.

‘What if this world was reset or put into a new state of being by an overseer…’

This was one of the biggest fears that he had now. What if the death of Wang Long put everything at risk that he had fought for. What if instead of letting this world continue there would be a reset switch pressed and everyone that he loved disappeared?

Previously he was not sure about Wang Long’s origins but now after watching the videos it was clear. The man clearly stated that unless the original system user was somehow severed from the system a new one would not be summoned.

Through his encounter with this place, he had died and severed the connection to the system. He had become a free agent while Wang Long was now the current official system holder. When he died another one would be summoned but the second scenario was already playing out, the war between Empires had been started.

When the thread connecting him to the main system was erased he was still a core formation expert. There weren’t that many changes that he made to the world, there was no reason to reset the scenario. Wang Long could just start from another location as not even a year had passed since he was summoned to this world.

But now there was a big difference, if he died in the middle of this struggle would the world be altered by an outside force? This was a possibility, he needed more answers, for the time being containing Wang Long in a prison would be the better option but also harder to accomplish.

He finally continued inside, the whole place was overgrown with weeds and signs of corrosion was everywhere. This home looked like it had come from some kind of dystopian future. The moment he went to open the door the hinges came off and the whole thing fell down.

On the inside, grass and vines were everywhere. The stairs to the second level had collapsed and everything here certainly didn’t last the test of time. Nothing looked usable and it was clear that this was just a place that this person used to relax.

This was not why he came here, after going through that pc there was supposed to be a special chamber that he was looking for. There was supposed to be an entrance here. He finally found himself in what looked to be an office. Old destroyed books and a half-collapsed desk were there.

On the desk, he spotted a picture frame that depicted a family of four. Somehow the picture had survived to this very day, it had to have been made with more resistant materials. On it, he could see two kids with their parents. The boy that was next to the father reminded him somewhat of the old man that he saw in the videos.

“This must have been his previous family, he certainly longed for the good old times… the entrance should be behind the bookshelf…”

After glancing at the photo he moved to the wall, there he discovered another passage to a large white room. The walls looked to be made with the same hard material.

“Hm, perhaps this stuff can’t be made into anything else than this white wall?”

He hoped to find some indestructible weapons for the coming battles but perhaps these walls were specially made through some contrived way that didn’t translate into smaller items like swords. This room was large and down in the middle, there was some kind of container.

“This is…”

This container had many large tubes connecting to it which hadn’t aged that well either. From the PC he used this was clearly the stasis room which meant that this container had been used to prolong this man’s life.

He somewhat expected to see some old bones that were leftover but instead he only found some rags. The material had decomposed through the years but it was certainly something that was worn before.

“Was this the place where he also ascended?”

The container looked a bit more modern with its design, the metal it was crafted from was somewhat rusted over but the shape had been kept. This looked like some kind of cryogenic pod that the creator of this secret ground had probably used to sleep through many thousands of years.

The tubes that were connected to it had faint traces of spiritual energy in them. Zhang Dong thus theorized that this device was somehow absorbing spiritual energy from some kind of source.

“There it is!”

When he followed the residual spiritual energy he arrived at the wall, but this time around this wasn’t a dead end. With the help of Bob that came from this place, he was able to access a hidden panel that revealed a hidden power source.

“A nucleus.”

It was one of the cubes that he always looked for. These small treasures could store a lot of energy and last through the ages. His predecessor knew this well and certainly used it to power at least part of this place.

At first, he was planning to take it and absorb all of the spiritual energy it had. There was a small problem as he didn’t think that it would have much power left. If he removed it from here, the whole secret ground could collapse or become open to any invaders from the outside.

“I guess it's good to know that It’s here, I could use it as a trump card if I ever need it but for now it is probably safer here than in my possession.”

There were still some spirit stones for him to go through. Advancing too fast could also bring the ire of an overseer on him. Thus, for now, he would let this relic rest here while he sought after other options for the coming war.

Chapter 440

“This really does look quite eerie…”

Zhang Dong was rocketing forward while surrounded by a golden shield of light. After going through the old house he had managed to figure out a way to get into the trial ground. But regretfully there was not much that he could use here.

The whole place was devoid of life and in some kind of stasis. Even the plants that seemed to be alive were surrounded by some uncanny energy.

‘Did he use the same technology that kept him alive on these plants as well?’

While he could enter this area while shielding himself with his spiritual energy, the rest was covered in some kind of strange aura of stasis. Bob was trying to analyze it and he also found some old research material that could help him figure it out later.

This strange energy was probably the reason why this place survived for this long. All the monsters and creatures that he had encountered here were probably just constructs made from spiritual energy. After the trials were done they would vanish and the whole place would start recharging itself.

The cube that he found in the room with the pod was the focal point of this whole place. Even now it was generating power while also taking it from somewhere. Probably another hidden spirit vein was buried deep underground that even his system scanner couldn’t reach.

After flying through the air he found the places where he met his wife and other friends like Huo Qiang. If he wanted he would even be able to go to the section where he met the seven sins and where the library was. For now, he decided to not as he had already scanned every book that it had, there was nothing to gain from there.

It would be better to keep this place operational and powered up. Even though it was now in his lands this could give his enemies an edge. But they were not system users and not above the person that made this secret ground. They would even find themselves trapped and then sucked into the teleportation array.

“This is disappointing but maybe I can use this thing…”

What he was looking at was a deactivated map. It was the treasure that was used by his clan members for the tower defense system. Even now it was able to produce a holographic image of the areas surrounding it but he was thinking of using it differently.

“It’s strangely similar to the one at the Long Clan, perhaps this guy had lifted the design?”

Zhang Dong could only speculate but it looked like the system user that he saw in the videos had used some of the designs here. This thing was either copied over or just bought from the system store and then altered. With the help of Bob he would be able to access it, then reprogram its functions to mimic the map at the Long clan.

“I’ll be able to monitor the whole empire, that thing was able to even track the movements of the invaders…”

This would probably be one of the most important items that he could get. It would allow him to predict the movement of his enemies and act accordingly. With the real-time holographic map, he would know where to place his forces before anything happened.

It was nicely preserved and still in working order. The stasis that this place was placed in probably helped preserve even magical treasures like this. With some skillful hand movements, he used his spiritual energies to levitate this while map into the air and then quickly deposited it into his spatial ring.

“Doesn’t seem that there is anything else that interesting here, I wish I could take this fortress with me but it probably won’t work without being connected to the secret ground… unless… ”

Zhang Dong had taken the bulky map with him but there was still the small fortress that was used for the tower defense part of the trial. It was used by his people to create defensive structures after killing monsters.

Clearly, the killing of monsters did nothing as everything was fueled by spiritual energy here. It was just fake currency and the secret lay in the secret ground itself. Then, if he could take this small fortress with him, could he recreate the system to quickly fortify his own sect? Perhaps he could feed it other things than spirit stones to make it create cannons out of thin air like during the test?

He had come prepared to take some bigger structures with him. Around his neck was a medallion that looked strangely similar to the dimensional regalia. It was a heaven grade replica of the immortal treasure with the same function. The space inside it was vastly smaller but it would be large enough to take this structure with him.

This procedure would be somewhat harder and require more spiritual energy but at this point in his life, Zhang Dong was quite powerful. The whole structure trembled as it rose into the air while being covered by his golden aura. The medallion around his neck started glowing as it shot out a beam of blue light.

When the beam collided with the large structure it started to quickly surround it with light. After the building was submerged in the light it vanished. After peeking inside he could see the building standing on a large plot of land.

The inside of this treasure was about a kilometer in diameter which was quite enough for several of these structures. His plan was to have bob analyze both the map along with the fortress and connect them to his own system. Through it, he hoped to mimic the functions of the tower defense system.

This is why he took away the map first as he wanted to disconnect it from this structure and then later place it at his sect ground. There he needed his people to monitor it as he still wanted his generals to do most of the strategic planning for him.

“I guess this is for this part…”

Zhang Dong looked at the empty region devoid of any life. He tried to recall the area where he had faced the demon of pride and burned up his life energy to save the people here. It brought a smile to his face as it showed him that he had it in him, the drive to help others over himself. But now things were somewhat different, with a more tightly knit family he didn’t know if he wouldn’t put them over the lives of his other sect members.

It was time to leave so he continued with his search. He visited all the places that he had been through as well as some other hidden away secret stashes. There were some hidden away locations with some treasures like weapons and old pills. These he had probably missed while stressing out to get back to his clan during his time here.

While the books from the library were mostly useless, the swords and spears could be used by his people. Everything that was of some worth was tossed into his spatial rings or the regalia replica. The items that he was taking were mostly of earth grade but even they could tip the balance in the future.

After spending some time flying around the testing ground he was satisfied with his earning and retreated back into the room where he found the computer. At first, he wanted to leave it be here but after discovering the room with the cryogenic pod he had changed his mind.

As long as he didn’t remove the cube that was powering the whole structure the whole secret ground would still somewhat work. Though after he removed so many treasures it would be impossible for anyone to finish this trial. If anyone was sucked in, they would find a defensive structure to keep the monsters away, they would be forced to use only their own martial prowess.

“So, you are positive that if I remove this I won’t trigger some kind of defensive mechanism or get me stranded here?”

“Affirmative.”

Bob replied in his cold robotic voice while he was looking down at the bunch of monitors and cables. It seemed that the person that made this didn’t think that anyone would be getting in here so there were no defensive measures. Which was somewhat strange as he did seem concerned with the ‘higher being’ that was out there.

‘Perhaps he convinced himself that his system was impenetrable from outside?’

Getting in here was truly impossible for people at the nascent soul level. There was probably no one that could get in here unless they had something like Bob.

‘Maybe he didn’t care or didn’t believe that the higher being could be stopped even if he tried?’

He could only shrug at his attempts of putting things together. Thus he focused on gently taking the whole computer and all the other items like the router along with the monitors and even the gaming chair. The whole room made it into the replica regalia while also keeping all the cables connected to the proper sockets.

“There, that should do it… everything seems to be in order…”

The person that left those videos was not as knowledgeable about the world as he had hoped. The old man was unable to cut away from it and instead ascended into the immortal realm, probably with the help of the system and thousands of years of gathering spirit points.

This war seemed like the main event that would give the system holder enough points to push through. But it also didn’t feel like it was handing the victory over on a silver platter either. The scouting party that he battled with was not an easy opponent, even for him that had managed to reach about the power level of a great circle nascent soul master.

Finally, the time to return home came so he headed out of this empty room. Just as Bob mentioned the area didn’t shut down and he was able to return to the place that he entered through.

He did not have to go through the other corridors anymore as he had searched through everything. There were some plans of the secret ground on the PC and they confirmed that he would be unable to find anything of worth.

With the help of Bob, he opened up the entrance and left this place for now. The cube would continue powering this area and if anyone dared to take the trial they would probably perish or be teleported to another location.

“Hello, yes I’m fine, I’ll be coming back now, please gather some of the engineering staff, I need them to look at something.”

After coming out he notified his wife of his well-being. It was time to get everyone informed and to prepare, soon the war would commence, the time was nigh.

Chapter 441

“You are really a spirit energy black hole…”

‘Insufficient spirit points.’

“Yeah… yeah…”

“Patriarch, is there a problem?”

“Ah no Zhi… wait a moment I just need to gather my thoughts!”

Zhang Dong turned around so that no one could see him pull out a palmful of spirit crystals. They quickly crumbled down to the ground as he started absorbing them. He was now in his sects war room, the map that he lifted from the secret ground was here and Bob was hogging all the resources to figure it out.

With the inclusion of the evolving fortress and this map, he was forced to go through all of the spirit stones that his sect had brought over. The mine was being quickly drained of its resources but it still wasn’t enough to get everything working. For the time being, he focused the reserves on the map as knowing where the other empires were, was more important.

The people in this exclusive room didn’t say anything but they were clearly confused about what their Patriarch was doing. He just kept moving back and forth, sometimes he would touch the thing that he had brought with him and then hide behind the corner to do something. Some of them even noticed some shiny powder on his robe that seemed to increase each time he came back.

“Oh? It’s glowing!”

One of the elders pointed to the device in the room that was now giving out a greenish glow. Within moments a holographic representation of the old fortress popped into view but soon it started to flicker.

‘There we go’

Zhang Dong gave out a sigh while allowing Bob to connect this holographic map to his system. At first, the image was of the fortress that people used during the tower defense phase of the old trials but soon it began to shift.

“Wait… isn’t that our Spirit Spring City?”

The map first showed a detailed representation of the whole city and the sect. Thanks to it now being connected to Zhang Dong’s system that had a detailed faction section it was quite precise.

It continued to zoom out as Bob started uploading the data that he lifted from the Long Clan’s world map. Soon the whole empire appeared in view as the map's holographic color shifted from green to gold. The radiant glow was a clear indicator that he had managed to fully absorb this technology into his system.

“This is the map of the whole empire?”

“That’s right, but this isn’t all, just wait a moment, gramps!”

Zhang Jin that looked a bit younger after passing into the nascent soul level asked. Soon red dots started to appear all over the map along with some arrows and different indicators. The arrows were at the border regions and indicated the bridges through which the enemies were slipping in.

It took a few moments for the map to take shape but it painted a picture to everyone. All of the elders left their seats to get closer, everyone knew that the red markers represented their enemies but they did not show the full strength of their forces.

“This treasure… Does it really represent the truth?”

“It should, do you see the red markers, they represent where the enemy forces are located. This map can somewhat measure the concentration of spiritual energy in the area. Thanks to that we can somewhat ascertain the strength of the enemy in that area but it’s not perfect, look over here.”

While explaining Zhang Dong pointed to the area where he tracked Wang Long to. There the concentration of red was somewhat weaker than on the other sides of the empire.

“It might look like the forces here are weak but in reality, they were mostly composed of body refiners.”

“I see, the treasure is unable to accurately measure spiritual energy that is focused inside of a body refiners body!”

Huo Qiang that was rubbing his chin chimed in from the side, the other elders nodded at his statement that was too obvious for them to even mention.

“You are correct, now everyone look over there.”

Zhang Dong pointed to the lower regions of the map where the United Element Sect was. The map was already connected with his system so he could select his area of influence and change its color to blue. With that everyone could clearly tell where the borders of their sect started and ended.

“This is where we are, we must now decide, do we protect all of this land or do we move back and wait…”

The power of the enemy was mostly unknown to these people, so he was sure that they would probably not want to give away even a smidge of their current territory. Cultivators that belonged to factions were highly territorial and would see it as an offense if someone invaded their lands without a proper reason.

“Do we even need to decide? We will just crush anyone that tries to enter our lands!”

Huo Qiang smacked his fist into his palm while puffing his chest out. Even at this very moment, Zhang Dong could tell that his muscular friend wanted to do nothing more than charge into the fray.

“I see that you are itching for a fight Qiang and we might be in for one soon.”

“Do you mean?”

“Yes, look here, these are called bridges and through them, our enemies are coming in. This one wasn’t there before and it is close to our borders. I fear that we might be getting some unwanted visitors soon.”

While at the Long Clan headquarters he had examined the map. There was no indication of a bridge appearing close to his sect but now it was different. A new opening had appeared and it was close to his sect ground. While they still had some time it was probably better to reinforce their defenses at the borders if they intended to spare the locals from seeing bloodshed.

“This area? Isn’t that the border region closest to the Dragon Gate Sect?”

Asked Zhang Liena.

“It does seem that way, I’m not sure if they will be able to defend themselves.”

Zhang Dong looked at the faint red area that was around the big red arrow. It looked like the forces that were pouring in weren’t giving out any strong spiritual signatures but this was the west side of the empire, the same side that the body refiners came from.

“Qiang, would you take some of the elders and…”

“You don’t need to say anything senior brother, I will meet those bastards in battle!”

He could only smile as he saw his red-haired friend pumping himself up for the coming battle. Zhang Zhi was next to him and after meeting his gaze he knew that there would be another babysitting session in store for him.

“Then it’s decided, Zhang Zhi, be sure to inform our friends from the Dragon Gate Sect of the coming danger, if they allow us to help them but you don’t need to go out of your way.”

While he would want to keep everyone safe, he was responsible for his own men. The Dragon Gate Sect was somewhat on friendly terms with his sect so he would give them aid if they required it but he would not force it on them.

He expected the invaders from the other empires to start sending out more scouting parties. Probably if the defenses of the Dragon Gate Sect proved inefficient they would outright attack, if they managed to survive they would probably return with a larger force later.

The map was in working order and the elders in the meeting room started discussing the coming days. For the time being, he decided to listen to their conversation to see what the natives of this world would decide on. It wasn’t much of a surprise though, even when he tried to change them, the ones at the top of the ladder rarely did.

“Patriarch, I’m not sure it’s wise to involve ourselves with the Dragon Gate Sect’s business, we should focus on reinforcing our lands.”

“I agree, the other sects would never give us aid if they were in our position.”

Everyone clearly didn’t want to send any aid, at most they would give them safe haven after their lands were occupied. They would probably welcome any additional strong cultivators into their ranks to then use as meat shields instead of their own. Luckily not everyone was of the same mind as the older members of the sect.

“I for once think we should give the Dragon Gate Sect some aid, they treated us properly I wouldn’t group them with the Limitless Sword Society.”

Zhang Jin voiced his opinion, his grandfather was of the mind that they should show some compassion. The actions of his grandson didn’t go unnoticed, he had been helpful to others which gained them some allies.

“This is true but this doesn’t mean that we should risk our sect brothers to save them, if it wasn’t for our Patriarch they would have not had any problem in robbing our lands!”

Soon a discussion about lending aid to other people in the empire started. While it was mostly chaotic where the elders just continued to shout at each other, Zhang Dong was somewhat glad. In the past there would probably not even be a side that showed any compassion, they would obviously only protect their own assets and ignore the rest.

Now on the other hand, through his own actions, he had shown them that goodwill could be rewarded. While the cultivators kept to themselves they did have some sense of honor. If someone helped them they would feel obligated to return the favor or they would receive bad karma.

“Okay everyone settle down.”

Finally, he raised his hand after it was getting a bit too loud.

“Let us discuss a different issue, we need to arm our sect brothers and sisters, some of them need more training while others can be drafted instantly. We will use the merit system to help us with this but I do not wish to force anyone if someone denies the call they will be given an opportunity to leave the sect but if they do, they may never return.”

He did not want to force anyone to fight but he would not allow them to come back after victory was achieved. While there probably wouldn’t be many deserters he didn’t want anyone that would flee and cause others to die in the middle of the fight.

“We also need to discuss our budget, food supply, and other resources, let us get into it…”

Chapter 442

“Lord Xu Qing, the United Element Sect, sent us a message.”

People started murmuring around the large hall. On one end was Xu Qing, the current Patriarch of the middle-sized Dragon Gate Sect. Along with the Demon Subduing Sect and the Limitless Sword Society they made up the three powers that were situated around the lands that Zhang Dong’s sect was.

Ever since he had taken out Zhan Jie, the previous Patriarch of the Limitless Sword Society, they had remained vigilant. They had kept an eye on that strange Sect that had a somewhat concentrated power base. In their opinion without their Patriarch they were nothing much yet with him, they were a dangerous foe if offended.

In the beginning, they had all of their infiltration attempts foiled. All of their spies had vanished without a trace which forced them to abandon this form of action. It was clear that they were being assassinated inside of that sect. They could not voice a complaint as they would be confirming their fault.

But after years of silence, it seemed that the United Element Sect had become silent. Even after their Patriarch had vanquished a strong opponent in Zhan Jie there were no requests. It was as if the man had vanished which prompted everyone to ponder.

In the end, they could only speculate that he had been injured during the bout and resting in his own territory. That is until they recently saw him during the empire-wide announcement where he was shown off as the Emperor’s blood brother.

Xu Qing and his people had quite the panic attack when this came to light. As one of the sects that had somewhat enforced their will on the United Element Sect, they were now frightened. They would not be able to retaliate against someone with the title of Golden Dragon.

If he wished to take revenge on the sects that left them so little after the Dark Palm Sect’s demise, they could do nothing but accept their fate. Thus they needed to take any call-outs from the United Element Sect very seriously. Even more, after they pushed the Demon Subduing Sect out of the lands that previously were occupied by the Dark Palm Sect.

“Have they decided to set their eyes on us? What does the message say? and what of their movements?”

Xu Qing asked while looking at the messenger. The man was your regular core formation cultivator and he was quick to voice out the news.

“My Patriarch, as you know we have reports of many nascent soul masters appearing out of the United Element Sect’s lands, the number that appeared close to our borders is… fifteen…”

The people from the Dragon Gate Sect sect gasped at this revelation. This was quite a large force considering that the United Element Sect was supposed to be a middle sized sect just like them. But from the information they had gathered the number of nascent soul grandmasters was quickly increasing.

“How many do they have…”

The Patriarch leaned back in his chair while going slightly pale. Such a force would be hard to compete with and from the old reports it didn’t seem that these nascent soul masters were of the old generation.

They were still somewhat young and able, which meant that the United Element Sect could be hiding even stronger reserves at their main sect building. They had managed to go against the mighty Soaring Dragon Sect, it was clear that they could not go against them.

“Continue, what do they want?”

Everyone steeled themselves for what the messenger would reply as they feared for the worst. Would they ask for an unreasonable amount of resources? Would they try to enslave them or take away their lands? Maybe even worse, it could be just a war proclamation before an immediate attack.

“They have given us information that we should expect foes arriving from the northern reaches and that they would probably arrive here within the week. They wish to offer their aid in the coming battles if we agree to let them enter our territory…”

“Foes arriving within the week?”

“Do they think we are stupid! Who would believe such an obvious lie!”

“That’s right, they want us to disable the protective formation so that they can have an easy way into our sect grounds!”

The old men and women in this hall erupted in anger after the messenger delivered some of the accounts. To them it was obviously some kind of scheme, if they let those nascent soul masters in, they would probably not live to tell the tale on a later day.

“Silence! Was there anything else?”

Xu Qing was also surprised by this declaration but he managed to keep his composure. He didn’t think that they would tell such a bad lie to make them lower their protective barrier. It was more probable that there was some kernel of truth in there.

“Ah yes my lord, they had sent over a jade with information for the elders, I assure you that no one dared to look inside.”

Xu Qing nodded while looking at one of his retainers on the side. It was a large man with a spear floating to his side. He moved in quickly to take away the jade with what would probably be some more information concerning this issue. The man looked at the jade and scanned it with his spiritual sense before bringing it over to the Patriarch.
“It is safe to use Patriarch.”

Xu Qing nodded while grasping the jade, quickly he went through the information that it contained. His eyes started bulging out as the information flooded into his mind. What was inside of this jade was a shortened version of what was happening in the empire and how the Soaring Dragon Sect was in danger of being attacked by invaders from far away.

Normally he would have agreed with the other elders and thought that this was some kind of elaborate scheme. But this did confirm some of the information that his own spies had dug up. There were already mentions of strange creatures roaming the lands in the north. Other sects had also reported being attacked in various locations in the empire.

He made sure to place spies all over the empire. While his sect wasn’t the strongest out there, they made sure to be one of the more informed ones. Reports of sightings of the Golden Dragon also reached their ears as he had been pursuing someone to the northwest point of the empire.

“Patriarch, you can’t be thinking of opening our gates? This will make us look weak if the other sects…”

“What if the other sects? Do you think they would be able to just turn down the blood brother of the Azure Emperor? We thought he had become a cripple but he had grown into something that we can’t deny, also…”

The request from the United Element Sect was worded rather cordially. That sect was obviously on the rise, they would not need to act that respectfully to get their way. Normally they would have used Long Dong’s famous name to strongarm them into submission.

This they did not do, there could be various reasons for this. One of them could just be a pretense, a way to seem just and honorable. But there was another one that this Patriarch was afraid of, there could be truth in their words.

What if they were on the cusp of being attacked by a powerful foe? What if this Golden Dragon deemed it necessary to lend them his help as he believed that they had no chance of winning?

“We need to bolster our defenses at our northern border first…”

“Patriarch! Can we really believe…”

“Silence!”

The Dragon Gate Sect elders were forced down to their knees by the pressure that Xu Qing was exuding and quickly went silent.

“If it was just the United Element Sect talking then we could just refuse but this is the Golden Dragon we are talking about. You all have witnessed the Emperor’s decree, if this Long Dong wished, he could just take over these lands and we could not lift a finger to stop him.”
“This doesn’t mean that we will just bow down and make way for them, we will examine this situation first. Sent the message that we will welcome the Golden Dragon but with that, he keeps his forces outside our lands…”

Xu Qing was somewhat willing to believe in the information that the United Element Sect was giving them. It went in line with what he already knew, this didn’t mean that he was fine with that many nascent soul masters parading around his lands. Long Dong was the Emperor’s brother, he could not stop him from entering as he carried the Long Clan name. Thus the decision was made and it would be carried out.

“W-we understand Patriarch.”

The rowdy elders that bowed their heads as they understood that they could not go against someone that was the blood brother of the emperor. They quickly moved out to send a reply to the United Element Sect.

In it, they welcomed Long Dong into their sect while using some mild words to indicate that they would not wish for his forces to come with him, at least not ones with multiple nascent soul masters. After some back and forth they were given a reply that the man in question would be arriving along with a couple of core formation masters and one other nascent soul one.

Thus the day came that the once strong Dragon Gate Sect had to bow their heads towards a visitor from the south. Most of them would remember the day fondly, the golden aura that he exuded felt quite warm. The people gasped out as they witnessed that magnificent radiance, it was as if a grandmaster descended into their lands to bless them.

There was a uniform gasp by the masses and myriad of cultivators that were on guard. The large Dragon Gates that were a staple of this sect were opened to allow him and a couple of cultivators to fly in.

Even though they were tiny compared to the huge gates that reached up to a kilometer in height, there was something to the radiance these people exuded.

“I greet you my friends from the Dragon Gate Sect, as you might know, I am the Golden Dragon, do not be alarmed I have come in peace!”

Zhang Dong floated forward while making sure to use one of his oldest abilities that was the senior aura. With it, he could ease the emotions of these people that were thinking that he was here to occupy their lands.

‘This is a good start, now to prepare them for the coming battle…’

Chapter 443

“What do you think?”

“About that Golden Dragon fellow?”

“Yes.”

“He clearly just wants to toss his weight around, the bastard just became the son of the Azure Emperor, he can now do whatever he pleases, if it was me…”

“Hah, not everyone is an old bastard like you!”

Two core formation cultivators were arguing with each other while being on guard duty. They were sitting in a lookout tower that helped them look into the deep expanse of this region. Due to the world being so large even this border region was humongous.

A few days ago they had received a visitor at their main sect. His name was Zhang Dong but now he went by the name Long Dong. These two were from the Dragon Gate Sect and word had reached them that he had entered their main sect. The Patriarch had decided to welcome him and open the gates but neither of these two felt happy about that.

“But what could the Patriarch do? If this Zhang Dong calls for the Azure Emperor our sect would be eradicated.”

“This is true and we best not forget that they did manage to defeat the likes of Wang Long…”

The deaths of so many nascent soul masters didn’t go unnoticed. Wang Long revealed himself to be some kind of monster that was even able to make a behemoth like the Soaring Dragon Sect disappear. Then by proxy, the United Element Sect had to be stronger that anyone had originally anticipated.

“What do they truly want? There isn’t really anything that we can offer them that the Long Clan wouldn’t be able to give them, our secret texts should be of lower quality…”

The two cultivators were a bit confused about the entire situation. Why was someone that famous forcing himself into their sect. Was he really just trying to get back at them for the things that they did in the past. To their knowledge their sect was very lenient with them, they didn’t even take any of the Dark Palm Sect’s territory and left it to the other two sects.

“Maybe their pride was hurt that much? Do you think they will do anything brazen?”

“I hope not… my daughter is with child now and they are back at the main sect…”

The two men looked to be in their fifties but were somewhat older. They had a large chunk of their families in the main city, if someone like the Golden Dragon decided to kill anyone there no one would really be able to stop him. But while they were discussing this event they noticed something.

“Hey… did you notice?”

“Notice what?”

“The daily patrol… they should have returned by now…”

One of the elders squinted with his eyes while rising from his seat. He enhanced his eyes and other senses with spiritual energy while peeking into the distance. They were at the border region which had many other cultivators like them patrolling the area. Normally a small group of other sect brothers would have arrived by now and gave a report.

“Come to think of it, they should be here…”

The other man nodded, both of them had been stuck working here for years with no changes. The days tended to blend with each other and time just passed without anything interesting ever happening. Thus only now did they notice that there was something strange happening.

With haste, they pulled out their communication jades to try and call the patrol leader. Even when they tried there was no answer, it was as if there was no one there to receive their call.

“Was there an attack? Or did that idiot forget to take his communication jade with him?”

“Not very likely, should we report this to the main sect or wait?”

The two looked at each other before nodding, it was clear that something was off. Nothing like this had ever happened in the years that they spent here. While the patrols weren’t always punctual there were never this late. One of them quickly looked to his communication jade but before he could forward the information a strange sound entered his ear.

Before any one of the two could react a strange spear that looked like it was made from white bone whizzed past them. The speed was truly tremendous, it was an unexpected attack that embedded itself into one of the men’s shoulders.

The cultivator cried out in pain as he was pulled with the spear towards the wall through which he was propelled outside. The other core formation expert was quick to react as he heard a second bone spear coming his way. But even when evading, the projectile managed to scrape his side while taking a chunk of his flesh with it.

“We are under attack!”

He screamed with all his might as he tried to alert the people that were here with them. At this spot, there weren’t any nascent soul masters, only a couple core formation experts with mostly formation establishment soldiers. They were mostly here as lookouts to call for help if they ever spotted a force that they could not handle.

It was quite rare to get unwelcome visitors, even rarer when they didn’t attempt to converse with them. The whole wall was now getting pelted with strange bone projectiles that just went through it like it was made from cardboard.

“Who are they? Who dares to attack the Dragon Gate Sect!?”
The people here called out in indignation at their fate. They couldn’t sense their attacker's spiritual energy even though they were getting attacked only when some strange shouts reached their ears were they able to finally spot the enemy.

A strange sound of a horn was heard before the attackers made themselves visible. Their bodies were larger than an average human’s and their teeth were quite elongated. At this point in time, there was a swarm of them charging in their direction while some others were chucking bone spears at them.

It was clear that it was some kind of enemy attack, the opponents looked like they were part of some demonic sect as their bodies were disfigured. The call for help was quickly forwarded to the other sect members at the borders but it was met with silence.

“Why is no one answering? It couldn’t be…”

The cultivator was clutching his side where the spear took out his flesh. He had quickly eaten a couple of restorative pills but they were working slowly. Normally he would have gotten a reply but now it seemed that the others were having troubles of their own. Either more of these creatures were attacking all the other towers at the border or they were blocking out the communication jades in some way.

Without knowing the situation there were two choices, either they stayed and fought or they evacuated. These opponents were strange as they lacked a steady spiritual energy signature. They had managed to surprise attack them but this didn’t mean that they were stronger.

“Defend the border, the elders will surely arrive soon, we just need to halt their advance!”

The injured man called out to the panicking sect members while pointing out with a large saber towards the approaching enemies. But his display of strength was met with resistance, and another bone spear confronted him. This time around he attempted to deflect it with his saber but as he clashed with the strange projectile his large weapon snapped the moment it collided with the white bone.

“Impossible…”

The man pivoted to the side as he managed to escape death yet again, this time the spear of bone penetrated his shoulder just like it did with his sect brother. He was tossed down from the tower along it. While flying through the air he could hear the lamentation of his sect members, they were getting slaughtered by the strange attackers.

When he landed on the ground he found himself in more pain. The spear had lodged itself into the hard ground along with his shoulder. He grasped it with his hand in hopes of pulling it out but his strength was leaving his body. There was some strange liquid on this projectile and it was somehow making his body unresponsive to his call.

“N-no it can’t end this way, someone please…”

The man lay struggling on the ground while watching many smaller bone-like arrows rain down from the sky. The hail of javelins was just a little taste as these smaller bolts blocked out the sun as if it was raining.

“Haha, I see that I arrived just in time!”

Before the white death could get close though a quick rise in temperature was noticed by this cultivator. The sky was going up in flames as a huge horned creature appeared between him and the swarm of bony projectiles.

He could hear the voice of a man that was laughing joyfully as this inferno intensified in scope. The arrows that were once there started evaporating in the blink of an eye as they collided with the massive thick red flames that looked like a second sun.

The monster that was radiating this heat seemed familiar. It quickly dawned on this core expert that this creature was a soul beast. It was clear that a nascent soul master had come to save them but there was no such soul beast in their Dragon Gate Sect. Yet he knew it finally, he recalled the name of the second strongest person in the United Element Sect.

“This Huo Qiang will be your opponent, don’t disappoint me now!”

The man’s voice echoed through the skies as the enemy ranged weapons were eradicated from sight. His soul beast remained in place with its hands crossed over one another. It was radiating massive amounts of heat that was focused to the outside of their borders. It was clearly protecting everyone here from the projectiles and doing a fine job.

Soon the core formation cultivator managed to dislodge the spear from his shoulder. The paralyzing effect faded away after a few minutes and he was able to free himself. Without thinking much about it he gritted his teeth and called forth his flying sword. With it, he headed back to the now mostly destroyed watchtower.

There as he emerged from behind the wall he saw a spectacle worthy of legend. A muscular man that was covered from head to toe by flames was mercilessly combating the invaders. His fists rained down on them like small meteors, with each hit another head exploded. It didn’t seem like these boney monsters were a match for him.

“T-this… Huo Qiang from the United Element Sect?”

As he called out the man also noticed that in the distance a flying ship appeared. It was not one of theirs and carried the insignia of the United Element’s Sect. He quickly snapped out of it, this was the middle of the battle and he was a warrior too.

“Brothers and sisters, the United Element Sect has come to aid us, let us fight together with them to protect our lands!”

The man shouted while picking up a new weapon for himself. The battle was not yet won, there were many enemies left for them to defeat and running away would be a blemish on their honor, it was time to show the invaders that they would not just lie down and die.

Chapter 444

‘It’s the same body refiners that I met in the northwest.’

Zhang Dong was looking out from a distance while Huo Qiang was engaged in battle with the enemies. His reasoning for not helping him out was to let his allies train, it didn’t seem that there were any of those unicorn ones in this group of soldiers so he could leave the fighting up to his nascent soul masters.

While Huo Qiang was first to dive into battle he was not the only one. Many of the recently ascended sect masters were spreading out through the borders. Thanks to the working map treasure at their base they could easily monitor the movement of their enemies. They could predict where they would show up and thus shorten their time of arrival.

‘Huo Qiang is doing well but the others.’

He started rubbing his chin while glancing over his faction system. There he moved some of the elder’s names that were battling their opponents into a separate window. Now he could monitor things like their life-bar and even spiritual energy bar.

Huo Qiang was certainly overwhelming the invaders with his plasma ifrit but the other nascent soul masters were still unpracticed. They were using up too much of their Qi while also suffering damage against the commanders of this attack battalion. Luckily for them, the opponents didn’t come in large numbers.

‘They should be able to survive this, if one is in danger I’ll use the teleportation feature.’

This was war so casualties were going to happen. It would be impossible for him to be everywhere and at everytime. His warriors needed to learn to fight for themselves and he could only wish them good luck while offering them more power. For the time being, he somewhat put his own elevation of power to the backburner.

What he needed was more minions to carry out his bidding. The more nascent soul masters he could produce the fewer battles he would need to participate in. His plan was to let his sect members battle the regular masters while he focused on the horned ones that seemed to be more powerful than the rest.

‘Even with the map they are hard to spot, these guys just don’t give away that much spiritual energy…’

When he peeked at the other sides of the empire the enemies there gave out a brighter red glow. The people he was up against though were body refiners that were somewhat hard to get a feeling on. Only when they were in sight would he really know if he was facing a potential threatening opponent or just another soldier.

It was somewhat hard to convince the Dragon Gate Sect’s Patriarch of his intentions. This did cause some casualties as he was not able to send his forces to bolster the defenses at the border. Instead, he had them wait on standby in the distance before jumping in.

Due to this some of the border defenses were overrun in other locations. This one was somewhere in the middle so Huo Qiang was able to get here in time. His men were spreading out to take back the fallen lands. When looking at his own version of the empire map he could see them being successful.

It took some time to clear things up, the whole battle was strange as the enemies tossed themselves into the fray without any fear. They never turned around and continued to charge in a maddened rage towards the enemy that was before them.

‘Is this in their nature or is something else driving them to be like this?’

Zhang Dong had been in some fights and met demonic cultivators that sometimes fought like this. He had witnessed such behavior in their minions that they didn't have a way out unless they managed to do their master’s biddings. Perhaps there was a force they feared more than death or perhaps they were convinced that if they ran away, they would die anyway.

“They certainly put up a good fight, at least there were no cowards among them!”

After the battle was done Huo Qiang arrived at his location. He didn’t look injured as the strongest cultivator that was there had been below his level. The early stage nascent soul masters had managed to force their first victory as well.

“Is that so…”

“You don’t seem happy brother?”

“Well, it was a bit too easy but I might be overthinking things…”

“Can I leave this place to you, they might attempt to launch another attack and now the Dragon Gate Sect won’t be able to deny us anymore.”

“Leave it to me, Senior Brother! Just send me some booze if it takes more than a few days!”

“Hah, sure just don’t drink too much, I need for you to be sober.”

Zhang Dong decided to leave things to Huo Qiang here. While it didn’t seem that these toothy attackers had fled there still was a chance that some of them might have slipped in. The people in the nearby cities and villages were at potential risk that needed to be cleared out.

While his people were going through their own battles he would return home to see his wife. She had remained back at the sect as they needed to at least leave one of the strongest cultivators behind. Lately, she had been complaining that he was leaving her behind too much yet he did not want her to get involved in the fighting just yet.

“So you are finally back?”

He was greeted by a somewhat cold tone when he arrived back at his new house. His lovely wife was laying on her side while watching the kids play with some toys in the green courthouse. She was in a gazebo-like structure that was supplied with a comfy bed for this purpose.

“You seem mad my wife…”

“Mad? Why would I be mad at my husband that constantly leaves without saying a word.”

“Uh, don’t be this way… I need to see to our sect members, we are at war now I won’t be able to remain at this place for long…”

Zhang Dong moved closer but Liena decided to puff out her cheeks while turning her head away. It was understandable to him that she was mad, her husband had been gone missing for many years and after returning he was off to a war. She was acting like a child now but he knew that she obviously was aware of what was at stake.

“I am here now and I think it’s time for you to progress further with your cultivation!”

For the time being, he decided to shift the conversation in a different direction. Liena had remained a bit stagnant with her cultivation after he had left. Tending to the sect and young children had kept her away from training as much. Huo Qiang had passed her up due to not having those responsibilities.

“Progress my cultivation?”

Liena perked up at the mention of her cultivation. She was still a cultivator at heart, so bringing up the possibility of increasing her Dao would always work. Though she quickly turned her head back and continued to pout right back.

“Don’t be like that my wife, I have prepared an area in the Dimensional Regalia, it will be just the two of us.”

“Just the two of us?”

Zhang Dong nodded while approaching his pouty wife and giving her a gentle pat on the shoulder.

“That’s right, granny Maling will tend to the kids so we will have plenty of time to work on your cultivation!”

Her eyes darted back and forth as he could see her reacting favorably when he mentioned that it would be just the two of them. His intent would be to supply her with more spiritual energy so that she could raise herself into the middle nascent soul stage, then spend some time with her to help her set her foundation better.

“... Fine then, let us depart!”

Finally, after some convincing, he had managed to get Liena to move. She now had a bright smile on her face instead of the cute pout. Before leaving they were sure to tell their kids to listen to Maling, who was a bit disgruntled that she could not work on her own Dao now. Zhang Jin was away at the border together with Huo Qiang for the time being, so it was up to the old girl.

Zhang Dong brought his wife over to a nice spot next to a waterfall. The Dimensional Regalia was now a small world in itself. It had many living beings and plants living in it and he was sure to reserve the most beautiful area to help his wife progress through her bottleneck.

But while he and his wife were having a nice moment another scene elsewhere was playing out. In the western reaches of the empire at the recent bridge that had opened up, there was a large fortress that he had seen before.

It was clearly brought over on a large beast worm that had borrowed its way into the ground. There was a small difference though, the inhabitants of this place were not quite the same as the gray-skinned ones that he had made contact with twice.

“So those worthless bastards from the Terakota Tribe are no more?”

“Yes chef, they had made some progress but had fallen in battle, the scouts report seeing a being made of pure flames.”

A man that was wearing light leather armor was talking to someone sitting on a large throne. Both of these ‘people’ had a red tint to their skin and the one that was on the throne had a large horn protruding from their forehead.

“It doesn’t matter, they had lost their chieftain but I thought they could at least pave the path for us better, truly useless until the end.”

While the red-skinned man also possessed a set of sharp chompers they were nowhere near as long as the people from the Terekota tribe that Zhang Dong ran into.

“We will need to show our tribes superiority!”

“It will be done my lord, the troops should be ready to march out in a few days, the transfer gate is fully operational.”

“Good, what of the golden one? Has he been spotted?”

“No my lord.”

“The Emperor has taken interest in that outlander, we will gain much favor with him if we can present him to the Emperor.”

The man with the horn on his head leaned back in his throne made of strange metals while smiling. For him and his people, this was an opportunity to rise above all the other tribes. Anyone that brought the man to the emperor would be given a boon.

“We must get to him first before the other tribes discover his location! Now go and make the lands run in the blood of the outlanders, leave no one standing!”

“Yes, my lord!”

Chapter 445

“...Are you paying attention?”

“Huh?”

Zhang Dong along with Zhang Liena were sitting down in the lotus position while holding hands. Both of them had taken some free time during these dire times to progress their cultivation. Mostly they were focusing on Liena’s but the Patriarch’s wife seemed to be focused on other things.

“You’ll have to excuse me but my mind had wandered elsewhere, let us continue.”

Liena closed her eyes once more while her husband chuckled. It seemed that she was preoccupied with the fact that they were finally alone in a peaceful spot more than the cultivation process. Soon they managed to resume with the transformation into the middle stage of the nascent soul level.

Thanks to his faction system he was able to somewhat boost her to the limit of her stage. There wasn’t much that he needed to do besides that but by helping her circulate her spiritual energy with his own he could further speed up the process and guarantee a smooth ascension.

Both of them rose into the air while covered by a blue glow of Qi. At first, it was a pale color but it soon changed to their own elemental Dao, in this case, green for wind. While he was no expert when it came to wind energy, he was knowledgeable enough to stimulate Liena’s Dao with his own knowledge and fill in some of the gaps.

Such a feat was only possible due to his extensive knowledge that he had gained through the years and also because he was very familiar with his wife's body. All of the meridians and spiritual pathways had been already discovered during their life together. He could very easily guide his Qi in gently to push Liena past the threshold.

‘There it is… that should do it.’

At the last junction, his hands moved away from Liena’s that soon floated further into the air. Her entire body was enveloped in a cocoon of thick green energy that started producing a repelling force. The winds in the area started picking up while she ascended into the middle stage.

Zhang Dong could feel his wife’s power rising to a new stage which caused him to smile. The change was quite instantaneous and he could confirm it by checking out his faction window. She was only the second middle stage nascent soul master in his sect which would make everyone in this empire raise a brow in disbelief.

The United Element Sect was a peculiar faction that through his upgrading process could compete with others even at lower levels of power. When he was a middle stage cultivator he could easily battle with late-stage nascent soul masters and win, even the ones on top could be dealt with if he was smart about it.

Huo Qiang and Zhang Liena weren’t much different. He had produced immortal grade cultivation manuals for them as well which were similar to his own. While they would trail behind him in raw strength they could easily compete with the masters in this world.

Probably if all three of them had more time, they would have been able to grow into quite the monster trio. If all of them were able to reach the great circle stage before this whole war started, they could probably steamroll any army by just working together as one.

‘Can’t have it all but this war could take up to a hundred years, so perhaps taking it slow won’t be such a bad idea.’

Zhang Dong floated down to the ground while looking up. His wife looked quite enchanting while being surrounded by her wind dao. If they weren’t in a hurry he would wish to spend some private time with her but for now, her lovely image was etched into his mind. This would have to last him for the coming days as he intended to join Huo Qiang back at the border region of the Dragon Gate Sect.

“Congratulations my wife, you are now officially a middle stage master but I think that you could wipe the floor with most of the sect leaders from the other sects now.”

“This does feel wonderful… but I can feel that you don’t wish me to test this new power.”

After managing to progress she floated down to land in front of Zhang Dong. It was the truth, she would need to remain here to act as the protector of the city and sect. Someone had to do this task and he would rather have his wife remain here at home than to go outside into the carnage.

The sect's protective formations were strong, no normal cultivator would be able to get through them. It would require a combined effort of many along with siege weapons and even then it would probably take over a month to get through. For this very reason, he wished that she remained with the children. Knowing that she was safe would ease his mind greatly and help him keep a cool head during the future battles.

“Yes, that would be my wish, it would be best if you remained here.”

Luckily it seemed that she wouldn’t be arguing with him much as she just gave out a chuckle.

“I’ll be sure to protect everyone in your absence but if something does happen, return immediately. ”

She suddenly leaned in pronouncing the last bit a lot louder than the rest. It was clear that she did not want him to play the hero anymore. This was pronounced by her leaning towards him and bopping his nose with her index finger.

Zhang Dong already knew that his lovely wife didn’t appreciate that he was going out of his way to help others. There was nothing to gain from those acts and he constantly endangered his own life. The part where he vanished for five years by helping dispose of the last monster probably didn't help either.

“Ah you know me…”

After giving out a nervous laugh he decided to slowly move for a strategic hug. Liena squirmed for a few moments but soon she quieted down. They just stayed for a moment like that before parting without saying anything. While she would consolidate her new realm here he would need to check up on another thing.

Thus he rose into the air and flew away. There were other matters to attend to and the first one concerned the fortress he borrowed from the secret ground. It had the ability to quickly expand defensive measures after being fed spiritual energy which he was hoping to use for the coming battles.

The whole structure had been relocated from the replica medallion into the original. There safe from any distraction he had his mad scientist part of the sect work on it. After gaining access to the map from this very same fortress Bob wouldn’t need as much time to hack it. But even then, he needed others to manufacture copies that he could relocate to strategic locations.

After a few moments of flight, he arrived at the research facility. Thanks to the faction system he did not need to worry about security. When he returned there were some new faces that needed to be removed but inside this closed-off world, there was no need to hide from his sect members.

“Greetings Patriarch!”

The moment he arrived he was greeted by people in lab coats. This section of the sect had been established before he disappeared. Due to his old world tastes he had manufactured white lab coats that made everyone look like a mad scientist.

All of them were specialists at crafting and their knowledge was quite extensive. Some of them even reached the knowledge level of their own Patriarch that could devour books like they were nothing. One of them was the leader that also hailed from the original Zhang Clan.

“I don’t want to rush you but I’m not sure how much time we have also…”

Zhang Dong looked at a sphere that was floating next to the main scientist. It had various glowing symbols on it and a big eye in the middle. This eye darted around as it looked at various people that were passing by.

“How is the helper that I gave you, was it of any use?”

“Yes Patriarch, you must tell me how you managed to create such an intricate puppet! It’s making our work a breeze!”

This floating eyeball that he was looking at was in reality an extension of Bob. His Ai was able to interface with outside constructs that he had created himself. They were part of his system and he was part of them. Thanks to this he could have Bob help his people out in deciphering the fortress while spending fewer spirit points by doing it directly.

“So did you find something out?”

“Yes we did, please come this way, Patriarch.”

The small group of scientists was eager to show him something. Soon they moved to the area where he took the map from. In its place, they were trying to assemble something less intricate that would be easier to manufacture. The area was now covered by some strange tubing that was connected to the middle part.

There was a large table with a strange rock on it. The color was the same as the walls and it looked like the scientists here had taken it as a sample. It was now gently floating in the air while sometimes changing shape into different forms.

There were cables going out from this table and they were all connected to what looked to be a modern-day computer. It was one of his own designs that seemed to have been improved after five years had passed.

“Is this what you wanted to show me?”

“Yes Patriarch, we weren’t sure what to start with so we decided to examine the walls that this place was made with. Then we made a discovery, not everything is the same, some parts are built from this peculiar mineral.”

From the explanation he got the scientists discovered that the entire fortress is not made from the exact same material. Not every part of it could alter its shape as most of that was focused on the outer walls.

“This treasure can alter its shape after being infused with spiritual energy, please look!”

After hearing a click the table the rock was floating on started to shine brighter. The grayish piece of rock started to quickly react and expand inside. Soon it changed to the shape of a sword.

“Hoh, good work.”

Zhang Dong without thinking reached out to grasp this sword. It felt like a regular longsword but after a few test swings, he noticed that there was something off. Soon the shape started to alter itself again and the construct quickly crumbled.

“As you can see Patriarch, we have to work out some kinks.”

He nodded while removing dust from his robe that it was covered in. His people managed to alter the shape so it meant that they were on the right track. Perhaps soon enough he could deploy a similar fortress for field testing but only if his people managed to recreate the materials that it was made from.

“I will leave you to it then, report to me if you make any progress.”

After his short visit, he was off once more, back outside where the battles were taking place.

Chapter 446

‘I need more resources…’

Zhang Dong was standing with his arms crossed in what he doubted the command center. It was the room with the new world map and a bunch of his own people. After leaving Liena to stomach her new rise in power he was off to strategize.

“Kuo, give me a report, how much did these invaders push into the Empire. Prioritize the areas with spirit stone mines.”

Zhang Kuo was also here, he was responsible for carrying out his orders while also informing him about the state of the Empire. Even though he had the world map in his system he didn’t have the time to constantly monitor it.

He gave his retainer a task to carry out. Kuo would need to monitor the map and inform him about areas rich with spiritual energy, mostly ones that possessed large pockets of spirit stones. The reserves were all spent and the mine that was in the old Dark Palm Sect area was almost spent.

Without the spiritual energy, he would not be able to create more nascent soul masters to aid him in the future battles. Perhaps he was rushing it but if he could get a strong foothold in some areas the enemies from the Empires would have a hard time progressing later.

There was a bridge in the southwest that was closer to his own sect and it was an important strategic location. The toothy monsters that he fought in the northwest area were there and he had already shown that he would be able to destroy their base.

This time around he would need some help from his own people as they had managed to set up their fortress. He wasn’t sure about its defensive capabilities but he expected it to be a harder nut to crack than having to kill off the half-dead monster worm before.

“Ah yes Patriarch, these are the locations closest to our position that have the properties that you listed, this region that belongs to the Shadow Phantom Sect has quite a potent area with vengeful spirits…”

Spiritual energy was not the only resource that he was looking for. Holy energy, soul energy, and lightning energy were the other three that he needed. Spiritual energy was just the easiest to come by but also the worst to work with. It needed to be transformed by the system to what he needed which would waste quite a bit of it in the process.

“Good.”

“Patriarch, can I voice a concern?”

Kuo looked at Zhang Dong and only when he replied did he resume speaking.

“You may speak.”

“Thank you, Patriarch, are you planning to head to these lands? Wouldn’t it be better if you remained at the sect if you fell in battle while wandering through the Empire…”

“I know, I won’t jeopardize my safety but I don’t think that we will get another chance to ste… I mean take the resources back from the invaders. They will be better of use in our hands than if they fall into theirs don’t you think?”

One of the main reasons that he wanted to go there now was that there would be widespread confusion. The middle sized sects were mostly weaker than the invading forces so they would be surely driven back towards their main cities where they would defend themselves.

Then there was the looming danger of Wang Long. What was happening in the northern-west reaches of the empire now? The area was also showing invader movement and they would surely go towards the demonic sect lands as well.

To his enemy, these creatures were spirit point machines. Many of them were at something similar to the nascent soul stage which would surely give him an opportunity to level up fast. In their next battle, he could be faced with many other strange techniques that he might not have an answer to. Thus the only way out, for now, was gathering as much of his own resources as he could.

Perhaps he would be draining the old sects from resources while they were in a state of panic but it was better if they fell into his hands than into the enemies. He was also not sure if the body refiners could even use any of the spiritual energy pockets that were here.

‘Spirit stone mines aren’t the only thing that can store Qi, there are many various herbs, pills, and natural phenomena with similar properties I just need to gather them up while I still can.’

The order was finalized and after saying goodbye to his children he was off again. The first area that he would be going towards was the previously mentioned Shadow Phantom sect.

They lived in a mostly desolate area with not many living creatures around. Instead, there were many ghosts and souls of the dead floating around near a certain location.

Apparently, it was some old battleground on which millions upon millions of beings had perished. The vengeful spirits then started to take shape and change the environment. The creatures there were changed, shifted into something more terrifying. It would be an ample source for soul energy.

Thanks to having a talk with the Dragon Gate Sect’s Patriarch earlier he was free to use their teleportation gates. With them, he was able to quickly appear closer to where the battles were taking place.

At the time being Huo Qiang was patrolling the lands with some of the other nascent soul masters. None of his people had died during the last attack but some had to return to the sect to be treated at the hospital. Their lives weren’t at risk but they would need a few weeks to get their full strength back.

To arrive at this next location he was also getting a shortcut thanks to his new title and connection. The Dragon Gate Sect mostly had good relations with other similar-sized sects. Thanks to this they could connect their teleportation gates to locations outside their own.

“The gate is ready for the Golden Dragon.”

An old man in a robe bowed before him while he looked at the blue water-like surface that the teleportation gates were known for. When he stepped through it he would arrive at the location of The Red Lotus Sisterhood, a middle sized sect that was composed only by women.

They had a trade agreement with the Dragon Gate Sect and thus he would be able to arrive at one of their trade cities. Of course, they already knew that he would be coming, his current name just carried that much weight. Yet without the connections that these middle sized sects had with each other, it would probably take a while to explain everything to them.

His vision blurred as he stepped through the gate. It was just a moment as he found himself on the other side. There he was greeted by quite the spectacle, jade beauties were everywhere and one was paler than the other. Their complexion looked like bright white paint which was even more accentuated by the red clothes and lipstick they were all wearing.

“What the…”

After getting used to the healthier complexion that his own wife and people around her had, their look gave him a scare. He even recoiled a bit after seeing the nascent soul elder that was in the front. She was an old granny that looked like a really shriveled-up white raisin with way too much makeup on. From the Qi flowing in her body, she must have been close to a thousand years old and at the twilight of her existence.

“We greet the glorious Golden Dragon, you have truly graced us with your fabled presence.”

The many women were quick to prostrate themselves before him. While he wasn’t sure if it was on purpose, many of them were wearing slimmed-down robes. These robes looked to be cut out in strategic locations to allow people to see some of the voluptuous curves of these ladies. If his wife was here, she would have probably given him a smack to the back of his head for taking in the sights after spacing out for a second or two.

“Ah yes, that’s me the Golden Dragon but you don’t need to trouble yourself with my presence ladies from the Red Lotus Sisterhood, as the Dragon Gate Sect has already informed you I will be only passing by, there is no need for this grand welcome.”

The vixens knew what they were doing. The moment he was there they were attempting to tempt him with their bodies. The smell of perfume was everywhere and thanks to his knowledge he realized that there were certain rare aphrodisiacs mixed into it all.

This world was cruel and uncertain, even more to the women. The easiest way of gaining power was getting a powerful husband and the backing of their family. Some Sects specialized in diplomacy more than anything else. While this Red Lotus Sisterhood was not particularly strong they had a wide range of connections by marriage. If they happened to be attacked by someone they would quickly gain the help of various powerful families in the area.

It was clear that they had set their manicured hands on this Golden Dragon. He was the new commodity in the Empire and with only one wife. Everyone was already aware that the Azure Dragon didn’t take in any more concubines but what of his younger brother?

This was quite the opportunity for any young lady, becoming the concubine of the younger brother of the Emperor would give power to their family. Perhaps they would even be able to carry the Long Clan name.

Long Dong was an enigma to everyone, with the war still not reaching the whole empire they were not aware of the reason that he was here. No one knew that the Shadow Phantom Sect would be soon getting invaded by a race similar to monsters. He had still many kilometers to fly through before he got there and would probably only get there as the fighting had started.

“Our Ancestors wouldn’t allow it, please let us welcome you to our lands. Our Sect is known for its hospitality.”

The old woman replied while he was thinking about ditching. If he was a single man or prone to cheating this would probably be a good place to have some fun. Yet he didn’t take much pleasure in mindless bedroom fun with other women than his current wife. Thanks to the connection with his wife he was able to keep it in his pants and decline the offer.

“No.”

He declared in a lower tone which caused the many ladies to panic slightly. They could feel his aura expanding everywhere to indicate that they were starting to cross the line.

“A-as you wish, Golden Dragon, we won’t hold you up.”

“You have my gratitude, I will excuse myself then.”

Thus he left before anyone discovered why he was starting to slowly lean forward, the next location being somewhat spooky.

Chapter 447

“The souls of the damned are unruly tonight, what could have affected them this much, the time of the reaping has not yet come.”

A man holding a scythe along with an old-looking lamp with a candle was looking out into the murky darkness. There he could hear the usual screams and lamentations of the spirits. The land before him was desolate, devoid of any living beings.

While to any other sect such a place would have meant certain death to his Shadow Phantom Sect it was the source of their power. Even now a colorless spirit was floating around this man and he still recalled the time that he had captured it to reach the core formation stage.

The people here had developed strange arts to live together with these rage-filled beings. A vengeful spirit was formed when someone’s life was taken abruptly and they still had longing for this world. The longer such a spirit became the more probable the creation of its damned form was.

These spirits longed for life and anything that had it. Thus they would quickly gravitate towards any living beings in the vicinity. Only if one could alter their spiritual energy with the correct techniques would they be safe. Otherwise, the ravenous evil spirits that roamed the area would chase them down and swallow all of their essences.

This man was one of the watchers of this desolate area. Not even nascent soul masters were powerful enough to protect themselves fully from the ghostly energy thus their lands didn’t see much bloodshed. Besides the phantoms and their sect that was shrouded in many layers of protective barriers and illusionary ones, there was not much here.

While the ghostly cultivators aren't that strong they had enough freedom to reach to the height of a middle sized sect. They didn’t wander out from their lands too often as the resources that the other sects possessed didn’t really progress their cultivation realm.

They also lacked many natural resources besides the thick layer of ghostly energies that were hard to handle. Thus even though their life was shrouded in darkness they didn’t really care about the dealings of the other sects and remained truly neutral.

This caused information not to travel very far and thus they were mostly unaware of the current state of the empire. A few days ago there had been a strange incident in these lands that caused the spirits to act strangely. This man here was dispatched as the more prominent elders were far too busy with their own problems to even care.

“The spirits… they are angry… has someone breached the sanctum?”

The man here was only a core formation elder and his spiritual sense didn’t reach far. But after getting this close he could sense that something was happening, someone was battling with the spirits. At first, he thought that perhaps a cultivator from the other sects had been unlucky and lost his way here.

“No, how could this be… the spirits are being altered? Their soul energy is shifting…”

The area with the phantoms was shrouded in greenish energy but there was a pulsing light slowly forming in the middle. It looked to be dark crimson and there were several beings in the middle.

This cultivator had quirky techniques that allowed him to peek through the thick mist surrounding this area. He could see that the people there were different than your usual cultivator. Their skin was all red and instead of ears, they seemed to have something similar to bat ears.

During this very moment, their mouths were gaping wide open. It looked bizarre as what would normally be a human’s jaw was part of the mouth and wide open. Their mouths parted at this area to produce a large toothy maw that was somehow gobbling up the angry spirits.

“Demonic cultivators? Why are there so many… I must alert the elders!”

The man quickly pulled out his communication jade to send the message but before he could go with it he felt a presence next to him. With all his might he moved his scythe to his side only for it to be hit by something hard.

This hard thing was much stronger than he anticipated. The scythe that had phantom energies gathered around it snapped in half while he was tossed to the side by the attacker. His arm that was previously holding the scythe was in a world of hurt but even while flying through the air he kept his eyes on the attacker.

It was one of the red-skinned creatures that he saw eating the souls of the damned. Its hand had elongated nails that were enhanced with somebody refining techniques. Even before he could gather his footing the creature attacked once more.

Large wings sprouted from its back as it propelled itself towards his position. The quickness this creature had was above what he was capable of. The communication jade that he was clutching in his good hand was quickly used. Even though he would surely die the people at his sect would be alerted to their presence.

Soon the man’s head was flying through the air. Yet even though his flesh had failed this was not quite the end to his existence. The core that he possessed was a phantom core, through which he would be able to remain in soul form for a short amount of time. It was a lesser form of what a nascent soul master was capable of.

While his form was similar to a vengeful spirit, if he managed to find a new host body he would be able to keep his life. What he needed to do now is to quickly return to the sect ground, being a core formation expert he would be given a replacement body from one of the lesser sect members.

While the person’s soul would be absorbed by his, the sect would be given back a stronger more experienced member to rely on. This was not something one could do repeatedly but the first time always had the biggest chance of being successful.

‘I must flee before I lose myself!’
The man’s spirit jolted towards his sect ground yet the monster that had decapitated him didn’t seem fooled. It was as if he could see the soul escaping from the body and continued the chase. Just like with the other souls the creature opened up its mouth to gobble him up.

“This is a delicious hunt, there are so many of them here, ripe for the taking.”

Soon the cultivator’s soul had been gobbled by this strange invader. He licked his lips as the mouth returned to something that looked more human in nature. The creatures that were gorging themselves on the vengeful souls soon gathered together. The body of the man who was beheaded was grasping something in his hand which was quickly discovered by them.

“They might know that we are here.”

“Does it matter? The hunt has only started, let them get ready, it will only make their flesh sweeter and souls taste better. Let their souls be devoured by fear while we devour this appetizer here.”

All of the red-skinned creatures here started to chuckle as they thought about sinking their teeth into their prey. The souls of the damned were quite the meal to them and the main reason why they chose to go towards these lands first.

….

‘I should be arriving soon…’

After evading the pale grasp of the voluptuous ladies he was close to reaching the lands of the Shadow Phantom Sect. This middle sized sect was not that prominent, they mostly remained in their lands where their powers were the strongest.

This wasn’t something out of the ordinary. There were many sects that gathered to places of power and just defended their location from others. Not everyone could boast universal power whenever they traveled. The cultivators tended to alter their techniques depending on the places they trained in, these just occupied a place with some strange phantoms on it.

‘There is not much information about this place, but there might be something else that is keeping the decrepit souls trapped here.’

Kuo had given him a report but there was not much known about this place. Universally everyone agreed that the souls were produced from some battle that took place many thousands of years ago, perhaps even before the last war between the empires.

But from Zhang Dong’s knowledge, there should be something making the souls stay. Perhaps some creature that had grown in energy past these many years or some kind of strange mineral. There were some options that could aid with his current cultivation problem yet for that to happen he would probably take away the protection from this Shadow Phantom Sect that was relying on the evil spirits as a natural repellent.

‘They sound like a semi demonic sect for playing with vengeful spirits which would make things easier. Nevertheless, I need to get stronger and those invaders are already here.’

He didn’t like the fact that he would need to strip the people here of their natural resources yet it might have been the only way for the empire to survive. If the invaders didn’t get to them, then there also was Wang Long that would probably continue killing people until he had enough spirit points to ascend into the immortal stage.

For that simple fact, he might have to ignore his strong sense of morality and look at the bigger picture. What he could do was simply tell them to relocate towards either his sect or the Long Clan or Heavenly Crane Sect. Besides his own people, he believed that those two factions would be able to defend themselves for the longest.

“Hm, looks similar to those dark lands in that other empire.”

Finally, he was here, the whole place was shrouded in dark and the clouds were very thick. Regretfully even though the clouds were dark it didn’t seem that there was any lightning energy hidden in them. It wasn’t a weather-based phenomenon but an alteration due to the strong vengeful spirit energy that made everything be covered in gray mist.

Before going in he glanced onto his map. Thanks to it he could somewhat tell where he would find the invaders. It wasn’t perfect but from what he could tell they were moving towards where the main city of this sect should be.

“Guess the vengeful spirits can’t stop their advances?”

Normally a body refiner would have more trouble with phantoms. These creatures that were composed of soul energy were quite different. The easiest way to combat them would be to be able to utilize soul power by the cultivator. Then the second-best method would be through strong concentrated spiritual energy. Punching the dead souls would not prove very effective.

“Did those toothy bastards have soul energy arts like me? Guess I’ll find out when I get there.”

Soon Zhang Dong disappeared into the grayish mist, his plan was to intercept the attackers before they got to the main sect city. If he was too late, he might have a lot more vengeful spirits to contend with.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 448

“What are these vile creatures? The phantasm gates have been breached, are they not affected by the soul-draining phenomenon at all?”

A group of cultivators dressed in dark gray robes was looking out into the distance. At this very moment, their protective formation was starting to fail. The illusory one that was there to trap any unwanted guests in a forest labyrinth that constantly changed shape didn’t amount to anything.

The red-skinned beings that looked to be some cross between humans and bats were progressing towards them without stopping for more than a few minutes. It was as if their ancient sect grounds were useless. The ghastly energies that they relied on were being absorbed before them, it was as if they didn’t serve for anything more than a meal for these beings.

“Demonic cultivators? Who are these creatures? They don’t look like any sect that I know.”

Cried an old shriveled-up man that was hovering in the air. His eyes were shut tightly but he radiated an eerie grayish light. The other elders seemed to be seeking guidance from this old man that looked like he lived for more than a thousand years.

“Patriarch, what should we do, if this continues these creatures will be out our doorstep in but a moment.”

“We must defend our lands from these vile creatures, I will not have the sect under my watch!”

The old man’s aura rose up and solidified at the lower end of the later stage of the nascent soul level. Other old elders started being raised from slumber, all of them looked tired and ancient. Due to the soul arts that they were specialized in they could cheat death to an extent. While their cultivation could not go past a certain level they were still powerful.

While the reserve elders of the sect were being raised from their slumber the others continued to monitor the outside. The thick gray mist that covered their lands was thinking out, without the evil souls' presence their greatest protection was coming undone.

Without this natural defense, their sect would not even be able to defend themselves against the traditional cultivators from the other middle sized sects. If the Shadow Phantom Sect wanted to survive this they could not allow the invaders to progress any further. They needed to protect their sect ground that had been built by their forefathers.

In the background, a strange monolith stood tall. It was covered in strange runes and many grayish souls floated around it. Their loud cries were something that the people living here were used to but today the shouts continued to intensify.

“We must not let the monolith be destroyed, without it we will be unable to remain here!”

This spire that stood there was the true reason for the evil souls. Their great ancestor just took the chance to assemble it right after the large-scale battle in this area was over. Through it, he managed to trap the vengeful souls in this area. Thus without it, this sect would be unable to continue with their old ways.

Their illusory formations were now broken, the defensive barrier that shielded them for thousands of years was now also being absorbed. Due to them over-relying on spirit arts they were now defenseless against beings that used this type of energy as fuel.

All was not lost for them though as a certain white-haired person was hovering above the clouds where the air was thin and even the grayish mist didn’t reach. His name was Zhang Dong but most people knew him as the Golden Dragon.

“I managed to get here in time, that must be the reason for all these vengeful spirits.”

He looked at what looked to be some strange spiral spire. Thanks to his knowledge of soul energy he figured out how these people were able to create this sort of area. The monolith was sending out a strange signal that roused the susceptible souls to gather here. It was not something anyone would normally notice unless they were close to it.

“Now this puts me in a bind, if I leave this thing here the souls will gather here once more but if I leave it like this, souls that would normally pass on will also be affected.”

There was a moral dilemma here. This sect clearly relied on this contraption to keep other sects away from their lands, if he removed it they would suffer the consequences later. On the other hand, if he just let it be, some souls that would normally not turn into decrepit ones would be attracted to this place.

After passing through the mist their energies would be corrupted and they would start to change into vengeful spirits. This was something bordering on demonic sect behavior, while it was not affecting the living beings it caused harm to the souls of the mortals that had no protection against this influence.

“I’ll have to think about it later, first I need to clear out these…red vampires?”

He did not expect to see these types of invaders. They were still body refiners as the toothy bone spear ones but they were quite different. They looked like more monstrous vampires from old movies that could somewhat alter the composition of their bodies. In their normal state, they were just red humans but they could drastically alter the shape of their jaws as well as sprout wings and change their digits into sharp claws.

“Perhaps just like we have sects and clans, this Empire has other types of segregation?”

Zhang Dong was not sure but this was clearly a different type of enemy that would also have a different way of attacking. The ability to absorb the evil souls was already one of them, thus he needed to be careful. Luckily he did not spot any overly strong variants of these creatures, but if they could transform into something more dangerous was not off the table yet.

“Time to make my entrance…”

Zhang Dong made sure to hide his presence while being in this place. His soul core also allowed him to circumvent any defenses that the Shadow Phantom Sect was proud of but the energy he absorbed through this was still quite low.

The vampire-like creatures on the other hand were gorging themselves on everything they could get. Luckily for him, this energy would not be lost to him as he could still drain it from them instead. It looked like they had gone through more than half of what these lands had to offer. This would be quite the injection of power after he was done with them.

Afterward, he could worry about what to do with the people living here. With the soul energies declining this much it would probably take tens of years for new ones to gather. Yet due to the war that was happening there would probably be a big influx of angry dead people that flocked here.

“This should do it, those spells sure come in handy.”

While everyone below him was making a lot of noise Zhang Dong had taken some time to prepare. His fingertip was glowing faintly as he continued to draw up something that looked like a magic circle.

The sparkly runes and geometrical shapes glistened in the light that was shining above this gray miasma. He made it work to his advantage as he weaved this spell into being. What he needed was a distraction through which he would gain the opportunity to strike.

“That muscle-bound one looks like the leader but the real one… is over there!”

Thanks to his system he was still able to get through all the illusions when it concerned true strength. The leader looked unsuspecting and he was to the side while most of the creatures continued to assault the Shadow Phantom Sect’s grounds. It seemed that he was smart enough to let his minions take the brunt of the defense before deciding to join them in the hunt.

‘Well then…’

Zhang Dong vanished from his spot while hiding his presence. A few seconds afterward the spell circles that he created activated. They shone brightly as a star before erupting into a massive number of thin beams of light. They rained down onto the red-skinned attackers that quickly noticed this light show that was coming from above.

These beams of concentrated energy used the sun to add to their power. While he wasn’t sure if adding sun rays into the mix would do anything, the enemies looked like vampires which would go in line with how these worlds were set up. His shot in the dark was correct as the first monster that one of the rays connected with started going up in flames.

The area where all of this was happening quickly became quite chaotic. The cultivators behind the thin barrier had no idea what was going on. The rays of light evaded their city while showering the outside without mercy. The weaker red monsters were going up in flames while the strongest ones managed to last even through taking multiple hits.

Yet this was but a distraction to keep everyone looking up into the sky. The spells that he placed there would be giving out a firework-like performance for a full minute of time. The enraged red vampire beings quickly homed in at the area that was giving out this light. Quite a few tossed themselves towards it while some fired off their spiky nails in that direction.

This was reminiscent of the bone spears that the other variant of these invaders he witnessed. But even if they hit the correct spot it would do nothing. What was above the miasma was just a large spell array that could not be damaged by physical means.

The leader was one of them, his eyes were also drawn up to the sky where the bolts of bright energy were coming down. He did not move though, it was clear that he was content on letting his people be sacrificed while he examined the situation.

But this would be his last mistake, perhaps if he was together with his small battalion of forces there would be someone that discovered his attacker. Yet he had decided to place himself away in a safe spot without any guards next to him.

This demonic vampire looked like a nice posh butler. At this very moment, his head was flying through the air as it was quickly removed by the person that slipped behind him during the distraction that was created.

There was not even a cry nor was there a big explosion, the body just dropped down to the ground while quickly crumbling into dust. Just like their story counterparts these beings were apparently not so great at handling swords packed with holy and solar energy.

“Well then, now to take care of the rest…”

Zhang Dong smiled while noticing that after decapitating this monster the others turned to him. There was probably some connection between the master and its minions. After he had taken care of him, they looked quite annoyed.

Chapter 449

“They seem disorganized without their leader…”

An orb of shadowy energy that had a red tint to it floated towards Zhang Dong. This was what remained from the vampire look-alike that he had slain. All of the soul energy that this being sucked up was gathered there.

It was highly concentrated and seemed to still be alive, probably some of its being was still in there. It was not similar to any soul that he had ever seen before as it had its own unique fingerprint. Yet it was still made from the same energy and even though it was corrupt he could still absorb it.

This one in particular was brimming with vengeful spirits that had not been fully digested. But when he activated his own soul core they were quickly returned to the basic soul energy that all creatures had. The other creatures were already flying his way but after they saw their commander being absorbed soul and all they stopped.

“What is it? Not so brave when you can’t turn into a little soul and escape?”

It was obvious that these creatures were not easily killed and could in some way survive even if their bodies were destroyed. Probably if he didn’t have the help of his holy energy that he augmented with solar power these monsters would have been hard to kill. Even without examining their bodies, he could tell that they had good regenerative capabilities.

While this red variant of the invaders wasn’t as strong as the toothy bastards, they probably made up by being more resilient. Without the proper countermeasures, they would continue to regenerate their health even when facing off against a stronger opponent.

“You won’t be able to outlast me in a battle of attrition, now come!”

This was the perfect moment to strike, with sword in hand he took off towards the next target. When the number of enemies was greater it was smart to deliver a devastating blow to one of their generals, then their morale would crumble while he met less of a resistance.

But in this case, this was somewhat redundant. Zhang Dong's all-around strength was not something these foot soldiers could handle. The vast majority of them were around the core formation level with a handful of nascent soul equivalents here and there. Their leader that he had just slain with one swing of his sword would not pose a problem to his wife or Huo Qiang.

“Golden one… it’s the Emperor’s prey!”

One of the monsters shouted while he charged into the fray. His movements were swift and he did not plan on giving these invaders time to flee or attack. While they were shouting something about an Emperor or calling him the golden one, it was not the time for this.

The people from the Shadow Phantom Sect had a front-row seat. What unfolded before them was a one-sided battle where most of them could only see a golden blur flying around everywhere. Where the blur went hundreds of the red monsters just burst and then crumbled into dust. It was a one-sided execution as the red vampires could not contend with this degree of power.

Yet he did notice a strange similarity to the other variant of the invaders. Even though they had no chance of winning and the enemy was overwhelming them, they did not run. Instead, they continued to toss themselves towards him in a fit of rage. It was as if they didn’t care about their own lives in the slightest.

“I know that you can understand me, who is the Emperor that you spoke about? What plans do you have for these lands?”

At the end of the battle, Zhang Dong was left with one survivor. It was one of the more powerful red-skinned vampires that would be around the early nascent soul stage. At this very moment, he was holding him by the neck while trying to get him to talk. The structure of this invading empire was unknown to him so gaining some information from one of their officers would be interesting.

“Y-you… The Emperor will tear you limb from limb!”

But even though he continued to grip harder while also threatening this being with death they didn’t not talk.

“Do you really not care for your life? What was that about the golden one and being prey?”

“Y-yes, you are nothing b-but prey for slaughter, the Emperor will drink your blood and feast on your flesh… ugh…”

The ugly person that he was holding was promptly slapped by him as he was getting on his nerves. While he was not talking this didn’t mean that he would not later. His sect had many techniques that could force information out of other cultivators, if they would be successful on this creature remained to be seen.

After a few smacks to the face, the creature was quick to quiet down. He then used his soul core to relieve this being of most of its energy before making him pass out. From his spatial ring, he brought out a large rectangular box that looked like a coffin.

The Dracula look-alike was then promptly deposited into it before he dumped him into the replica of the Dimensional Regalia. While his spatial ring could not house living creatures this spatial treasure could. In it, the monster would be forced to lay dormant until he dumped him at his sect ground. But before that happened he needed to finish up here, the Shadow Phantom Sect was still here and needed some looking into.

Though the mist that was covering this area had thinned out he could still feel vengeful spirits floating in the distance. There was quite the concentration of them in the sect, the large spire in the distance was still operational.

‘Now what do I do with you…’

Zhang Dong floated towards the somewhat damaged protective barrier that the vampire beings had been absorbing. It was truly created from soul energy and probably harvested from evil spirits. There was no corruption here, the Shadow Phantom Sect didn’t seem to be one of the evil sects yet what they were doing was quite close.

Now he needed to make a decision. He could either let them be and have the large spire in the background attract more dead spirits to these lands or he could destroy it. Without this monolith, some of the vengeful spirits could pass on.

What that entailed for them he didn’t know, while he could absorb souls' energy he did not know where all of their memories went after their passing. Perhaps these souls that he was seeing were not even part of the being that they came from. They could just be blobs of jumbled-up memories that were once a person.

The people in these lands believed in reincarnation. After a soul passed on it would have its memories erased and then reborn. Some strong individuals could retain their memories, sometimes fully but mostly partially. But was it due to the being that created this world or some kind of natural phenomenon that was even older, he had no idea.

In the distance, he could see the robed leaders of this sect. They were all wearing grayish robes with hoods that made them look like some cultist members. The most powerful of them was a really old man. Thanks to his spiritual sense he noticed that the man was a lot older than he should be.

‘His soul is close to two thousand years old, he must have been prolonging his life in some way.’

The man was on the lower end of a late stage nascent soul master. These types of prolonging techniques most of the time drained energy from the practitioner. He would not be surprised that when this man was at full strength he was much stronger. His soul was also strange, it didn’t really fit the body.

‘It’s as if the body is trying to reject the soul while slowly falling apart…’

Then he realized what kind of technique it was. This left quite the bad taste in his mouth, the old man before him had transplanted his soul into someone else's body. The body was trying to reject this soul and slowly decomposing. This kind of method would probably allow this person to prolong his life for some years, ten at most.

‘Has this old bastard been jumping from body to body for all these years…’

Zhang Dong moved towards the faint barrier that was between him and the Sect grounds. Just with a little tap of his index finger he opened up a large enough hole to slip inside. The people from the Shadow Phantom Sect were clearly stunned by this feat yet they could not do anything about it.

“W-we thank the Golden Dragon for giving us aid.”

The leader was quick to move towards his direction while clasping his hands and lowering his head. To these people that could somewhat measure the soul energy radiating from others, Zhang Dong looked like a true monster. After coming back from the other world his soul was larger than anyone.

“You there, did the owner of that body give away his body freely?”

The old man was asked a question while feeling a pressure that he had never felt before. While Zhang Dong was angry this was not something rare. Many sect members offered up their lives, some thought this was a very honorable act.

This would be true for his own people. He could imagine Zhang Zhi handing over his body if he ever asked him to. The man was already his number one fan and having your Patriarch live on inside your flesh would be the greatest honor to someone like that.

Thus he was still on the fence on what to do here. The old man could have just conditioned his people to think that giving up their bodies to the already advanced elders was the proper thing to do. But not like that sect members on the bottom could so anything if they had no power to speak of.

“Senior that is…”

“Let me ask you all, are you fine with this treatment? Do the juniors from the Shadow Phantom Sect desire to have their bodies taken to serve? Does everyone know about this fact?”

He decided to go with another approach. The old man would probably not tell him the truth but thanks to his senior aura he might be able to affect the juniors in the crowd. They might have been too afraid to speak out otherwise.

Yet, from the expressions on their faces, he knew that they were aware of this fact. No one took a step forward to go against their elders. This was their way of life and it was how they managed to survive all these thousands of years. They were afraid of change, without the old elders that made them strong their sect would not be able to survive and they would be as good as dead.

“I see, I hope that you will change your mind if you manage to survive…”

Without wanting to be stuck here for longer he zoomed over to the monolith that was giving out the strange signal. While he would not destroy it, he could make it less potent. With time the treasure would stop functioning. The people living here would have enough time to find a new way that perhaps didn’t cause their own to lose their life.

Chapter 450

‘Did I do the right thing?’

Zhang Dong looked to his back where he saw the Shadow Phantom Sect’s protective barrier. He had already given them the advice to move out of here as more of the red monsters would be coming. There was not enough time for him to hang around this place and protect these people as more regions containing the power sources he wanted were still out there.

The monolith that attracted the angry souls of the dead was already working at a lower capacity. From what he could tell the people from that sect didn’t notice it and when they did it would be too late.

He did not like the way they lived but could he really judge them? Now they would have to find another way to survive, that is if they even made it past this round of the war. The red monsters seemed to be able to easily get through their barriers to attack them.

Now after the whole area had been mostly drained from soul energy they wouldn’t even be able to defend themselves from regular cultivators. The best way of surviving would be to run into the mainland yet he didn’t think that any sect would just abandon their lands unless they were truly positive that the end was coming.

But the more time passed the more information about the borders getting attacked would surface. He could only hope that they took the information to heart and acted accordingly.

‘I should probably stop worrying about others and think about my own problems…’

While he might have caused the future downfall of this Shadow Phantom Sect they would some years before the monolith of theirs stops working altogether. If he didn’t show up they would have been slaughtered so from a certain point of view he had the right to make some decisions concerning them but it was up to them to make the changes.

Thus after sharing with them some of the information that he had, he departed. The elders now knew of the potential danger from the breaches at the borders. It would be up to them and the others there to make a decision. He had spread his voice through the whole city and even the non-cultivators were able to hear the news.

Before they could get rowdy he left them, there was no time to answer more of their questions. They were probably arguing about their plans but going by what happened in these situations most of the time, they would probably bunker up.

Waiting it out when the enemy was too strong and attacking when victory was mostly assured was the motto of cultivators in this world. Unless they were mostly sure about having the greater forces they would bide their time. But when they were assured of their strength they would sometimes abandon all strategies.

‘Well then, I have managed to gather up quite a bit of soul energy from these vampires but I can probably get more…’

During this battle with the red beings, he planned to let a couple of them flee. Then he would follow this one member to their camp and clear it out. Regretfully all of these monsters were thrown into a berserked state after their leader had died. Probably they had a very clear policy about deserters in their midst so anyone fleeing would probably not return to their hiding place.

‘The passage is here but It would be unwise to go there alone now, their base will be built up by now, at most I could attack some of the smaller bases that they have…’

He could not only go back to his own system map. There he could see faint red blobs, with them having a faint energy signature; it was somewhat hard to distinguish where the exact location of their temporary encampments was.

There was also an annoying thought bothering him, they called him the golden one, it was as if they had seen him before. Perhaps after destroying their first base when they appeared out of the bridge had earned him a name among them. He was supposed to be the prey of their Emperor.

‘They were shouting some strange things about preys and hunts when they were dying… Is this some kind of sport for them?’

The mystery of this side of the empire was slowly unraveling before him. It seemed that they weren’t here for the resources but to perhaps hunt instead. Knowing the motivation of his enemies could aid him in the coming battles.

If they were just doing this for pleasure they would ignore any attempts of diplomacy. He would not be able to offer them treasures or lands, it would make them truly a difficult enemy to fight.

Normally conflicts started for resources or land, the invaders would not go out of their way to eradicate everything in their wake as it would leave the conquered lands in a devastated state. No one wanted to rule over a destroyed desert with no subjects to control there. But if these invaders just wanted to kill people they would not shy away from using drastic solutions if they started losing.

‘And they had to pop out at my side of the empire, my dear brother won’t help me with this either…’

Without the Long Clan’s aid, he was in a bit of a predicament. His forces were still in the process of being built up. Without a steady supply of spirit stones, he would not be able to create more nascent soul soldiers. Thus it was time to go for the next important location, one that looked to have been taken over by the enemies.

“What was it? Heavenly Forge Alliance?”

While this sect had a grandiose name, it was just a coalition of small clans that were proficient in creating treasures. After many millennia they had managed to form into a middle sized sect that wasn’t much different from others. They lived in a mountain range that was devoid of much greenery.

Instead of living on the land, they lived inside of it. This sect somewhat reminded him of a fantasy race of dwarves. They buried deep into the mountains where they mined various minerals and turned them into weapons. What it seems like they were doing was substituting low cultivation with powerful weapons.

This place shared its borders with the Shadow Phantom Sect here. It was the next on his list of areas to check as there were many mines with valuable resources. Some metals retained spiritual energy within them which allowed them to be turned into high quality weapons fit for masters.

Besides these, there were rumors of spirit stone mines in this small region. The sect was somewhat secretive about what they were doing as they surrounded themselves by high mountains and kept their cities underground. Their main area was in an active volcano that they had somewhat been able to harness.

A large-scale attack on them would be quite hard as the troops needed to go inside the earth. Due to the high concentration of metals and minerals, the tunnels were quite resistant to spiritual energy. Even a nascent soul master would have a hard time maneuvering the lava-filled chambers there.

The Heavenly Forge Alliance was another example of a defensive geared sect. They didn’t have the strength to attack others but they managed to entrench themselves inside the mountains. Where other cultivators abandoned these grounds they had survived while paving a path for themselves.

“Are there any survivors though?”

When going through the map Zhang Dong could see that the red vampires came from these lands. It made it look that they had finished clearing out the Heavenly Forge Alliance’s lands and moved on to the Shadow Phantom sect. Yet the troops that they sent didn’t seem like the main force which could mean that the people living in these lands could still be resisting.

“I guess I’ll know when I get there.”

With nothing else to do here, he activated his Qi and shot towards the mountains. The distances between these lands were quite large and even he would need a few days to arrive at the active volcano that was the capital city.

While going through the air Zhang Dong looked at his three cores. The soul core had increased in size but it was still smaller than the holy one. After his visit to the Long Clan, it had become quite bloated. This was bringing a slight imbalance to his cultivation as the two other cores were trailing behind.

The Dao seed that was in the middle of these cores had also increased in size but it could not extract more energy from the cores anymore. Only when all of the three had more to give would the seed activate and grow. He absorbed any lightning from storms that he passed through but this wasn’t enough.

Yet even though the seed wasn’t growing his power was still slowly going up. Even without being in the nascent soul stage, he was stronger than most great circle masters of that realm. He could not really consider himself a master at the core formation stage, this was something entirely different.

Following his visit to the secret ground, he had also become aware of the disappearance of cultivation realms. His predecessor stated that they were hidden for the sole purpose of hindering the regular people from attending the immortal realm. Now when his system was changed he might have to follow the old ways of cultivation.

“At least the system lets me change Qi into what I need for the cores but I’ll have to push through this stage on my own…”

This was not like when he attained the nascent soul realm, there was no information of the Dao Seed realm that he gave the name to this phenomenon. The system could only help him reach the apex of it but he would need to germinate this seed by himself.

It seemed that the key would be to combine his three Dao’s into this seed and then make it bloom. Would it create some kind of tree? Perhaps it would take the form of a lotus flower or something similar.

“Don’t think it will sprout into my soul beast again…”

While it was interesting to ponder what his new transformation would entail it also made him a bit sad. He would be probably entering into a new form of existence which would mean that he would no longer be getting a nascent soul.

“Maybe I can recreate him from the soul core later?”

His journey continued while his thoughts were taken towards his next level of ascension. While the war was supposed to take a hundred years he was unsure if he had that much time to train. Wang Long was there and so were the enemy emperors. But he would not give up until his last breath, many people depended on him and they trusted that he could get them through this bump in the road.

Chapter 451

“I always forget how vast this world really is…”

Zhang Dong had to take a moment to look at the map. He was surrounded by snowy mountains and blizzards. It was hard to fathom that people could live in a place like this. After traveling from his last location he entered an area with a very chilly climate.

Each and every middle sized sect's land was like another planet. A lot of times the weather conditions would switch between the locations. What decided it wasn’t really the geographical location but the distribution of elemental Qi.

For instance, his old Zhang Clan had been built in an area where mostly water Qi prevailed. Luckily it didn’t overpower the other spiritual energy types too much, if it did then instead of a city there would be a giant ocean size lake there. Only when there was a balance between these elements would an area that was habitable sprout out.

It was hard to find a place that was truly devoid of one of the main elements. Yet ones that one prevailed over the others were quite common. In this one, it was ice and wind, a truly uncomfortable combination. The strong winds only exacerbated the cold air and made it hard for humans to survive.

“This must be one of the entrances to the underground.”

Yet, the people had managed to find a way. Before him was a large hole in the ground that was radiating heat. While ice Qi prevailed over the upper world, fire had made the underground world its domain. It was as if it escaped to where the cold could not reach it anymore.

‘Supposedly there are many small volcanoes like these spread through this area.’

It was a strange sight to behold. This volcano was truly active and gave out a tremendous amount of heat. Even when he was getting closer he could see a large amount of steam that was being created. The sight was spectacular, not something that he had ever expected to see before coming to this world.

The fire from the volcano melted the snow around it and then quickly made it turn to steam. Yet after a few moments, the steam was cooled down by the chilly air. The place was in a perpetual storm of snow and ice as the steam was being transformed and blown around everywhere. If Zhang Dong could not surround his body with a layer of his own warm energy he would probably turn into a frozen sculpture within a day’s time.

“Down we go I guess?”

After taking a peek at his system map he dived into the active volcano right from the top. On the inside, his spiritual energy kept him safe from the increased heat. While the whole place seemed to be a death trap filled with molten lava there was a side tunnel. When arriving at it he noticed man-made columns and some writing.

“Welcome to the Underforge?”
He spoke out the written words while looking around. Instantly he noticed that there was something off here. On the walls, there were some strange incisions that looked like they were made with bladed weapons and other ones that looked like claws. There were no bodies here but a fight had clearly taken place here.

“These markings match the claw size of those red vampires… doesn’t seem that there were any survivors… did they just eat the bodies or something?”

After spreading his spiritual sense to examine the area he discovered some faint traces of human blood. The sect that operated in this area had sentries placed at most of the entrances in their lands. These volcanoes that led into the underforge were their border region which they would of course want to protect.

The entrance that he was looking at wasn’t very large nor did it seem that it had been that well-protected. Probably the soldiers were mostly placed as lookouts to signal any unwanted guests arriving and not as a force to repel them.

These people that lived in the underground were known forgemasters. They probably needed to have entrances that were large enough to let flying ships in and this was certainly not one of them. It was just a side entrance that was close to the border region with the other sects.

“The city should be that way…”

Zhang Dong knocked on the rocky walls and realized that it was quite sturdy. The system map could not detect any nearby cities. He could either try to go through these tunnels or try going through the walls. The only problem was that if he tried that he would most likely burn through his spirit energy reserves.

It was fine to drill a hole through the soft ground but when it was filled with metal the difficulty would increase. Even though the enemies that he met before were somewhat easy to defeat he did not know how many there would be down there.

With his current strength, it might have seemed that he should be able to bulldoze his way through all of these adversaries. This he knew but that way of thinking would only bring him ruin, getting too prideful would be his downfall like it was for many other strong masters before him.

Thus while spreading his senses in all directions he descended into the underforge. Bob was alerted to signal him if he discovered any pockets of minerals that could be useful to his rise in cultivation.

The opening took him through a long winding corridor that he quickly sped through. Then he found himself at a fork in a road that gave him three options. Luckily for him, there were many clues of where he should go. Thanks to the fighting that took place in this place it was clear where everyone ran through.

His journey continued and the deeper he descended the more signs of life he discovered. Yet there were no remains of the people living there, some broken weapons and destroyed furniture that was previously used by someone. Either these vampires that he had met were taking these people away or they were somehow disposing of the bodies on the spot.

It wasn’t hard to trace the bloodshed but there was a certain thing missing. After gaining his soul core he had been more attuned to the astral aspect. Even though people had died here there were no leftover souls. But after his previous run in with these soul vampires he knew that they were responsible for it.

‘I might be too late to save anyone…’

This left a bit of a bad taste in his mouth as he would not be here if it wasn’t for the natural resources. Without there being any survivors it also made it easier for him to just grab what he needed and leave. But debating his motives would not get him anywhere so he continued to venture deeper and deeper into the underforge. Soon he arrived at a wide-open area with quite a high concentration of earth and fire Qi.

“This must be the underground river of fire that I read about.”

Before leaving his sect he had gone through the areas of interest. After a quick read, he was informed about the main points of interest. All of the large and small volcanos led into the underforge. Then after passing through a wide range of tight corridors a person would come to a huge river made from lava.

This area was tremendously huge, even flying ships could go past. The main volcano that connected to the capital city was connected to this river made of molten rock. His plan was to fly through this place and then arrive at where the vampires arrived. On the way there he would help out if there were any survivors but after some time had passed something became clear.

“There is no one here…”

Zhang Dong continued to fly while looking around. Through the walls, he could somewhat sense the residential areas that people once lived in. Sometimes he would see buildings on the walls but there were no signs of life, only destruction, and emptiness.

The longer his flight continued the more his mood soured. Even when he picked up the pace there was no sign of the monsters nor the people that should be there. At first, he thought that all of them might have retreated to the capital that he was going towards but when he arrived there the sight was shocking.

Giant gates that were made from some kind of hard metal stood there. They had been bent out of shape by something. From what he had heard the city inside was supposed to be a marvel of ingenuity and the citizens inside tended to use inventions to help them with their day-to-day life. Yet when he crossed through the gates he discovered a ghost city.

“Are they all…”

There was widespread destruction through what looked to be a steampunk version of a huge city of cultivators. Small streams of lava flowed from the walls and into some strange vats. It seemed that they were somehow melting the snow outside and turning it to steam to run a lot of the mechanisms here.

At least that’s what he could tell from the ones that were still intact. From what he was seeing there wasn’t much left, everything was shredded or crushed under something large. There were strange markings on the ground that were somewhat familiar. It was as if some kind of giant worm or snake busted through this gate.

‘Probably the same creature that I saw at that bridge…’

There was another large hole in one of the walls that was now filling up with lava. The giant worm beast probably borrowed its way out through it. With its help, the red vampires had made their escape as it didn’t seem that any of them remained here.

In the distance, there was something like a tower, a remnant of some larger structure. It had collapsed on the side. Zhang Dong floated over towards it to discover a strange blood splatter on the ground. It looked like it belonged to a female body type and it was also next to something that soured his mood even more.

A crib made from metal was tipped over without anything remaining in there. The room he arrived in was clearly painted in gentle colors. Various toys and figurines were spilled out through the ground. One that was intact caught his eye, it was somewhat similar to an old doll that his own daughter still had.

He moved closer to it to pick it up. The moment he did the doll's head tipped to the side and quickly fell to the ground. The faint reminder of some spiritual energy remained on this toy which probably belonged to the child that used to sleep in the crib.

“What kind of person creates this kind of world…”

His mind raced as he felt rage rise up in his chest. So many people had perished here that he would never see the faces of. Yet this was only a scenario that was playing out by the design of some kind of otherworldly being.

Yet he was unable to go against it. The part that he was playing in this game had only started and the carnage would only continue. Millions more would suffer and he could not do anything about it. The only thing that he could do was to save the few that he could and take vengeance for the ones that had fallen.

Chapter 452

“Did you hear that?”

“There is nothing there, we already took care of the prey.”

Two humanoid creatures were walking through a darkened corridor while looking around. One of them had a strange feeling that there was something following after them. Yet every time he looked back there was nothing but the wind. Their partner didn’t feel anything out of the ordinary which just made him more paranoid.

“We are almost at the temporary encampment. If you don’t want the dark mistress to devour our essence you better relax.”

The red-skinned man with bat wings on his back scoffed at the person next to him. After a smack to the back of his head, the two took flight after reaching a clearing. There in the distance, they could see something that looked like the remnants of a city.

“Now stay quiet and let me do the repo…”

While talking, the person that looked like a vampire from an old movie turned around. Within a second of him looking at the city, his partner was gone. At first, he thought that his comrade was performing some kind of joke but soon he found that there was something strange, he could not move.

His whole body felt like it was underwater but he could not move a muscle or utter a word. Then he noticed that there was some kind of strange thread of invisible energy there. It came from the cavern they just left and it continued to entangle itself over his entire body. Soon he wasn’t able to feel anything as his entire body went numb and he was yanked back into the cavern that he came from.

There he finally saw the being that was responsible for it all. It was a man with silver hair and a strange aura around himself. At this point in time, his hand was around his neck and he was lifted up as if he didn’t weigh anything. Even though the body that he was proud of was full of muscles and well over two meters it was easily being helped up as if he was a small child.

“You should have listened to your friend but not like you would have been able to flee…”

Soon the red vampire was turning to ash while the hand that was holding him discharged some strange energy. Before this being died he remembered the person that the Emperor was after yet why this person had ended up here was unknown to him.

“I guess I should do something about that killing intent…”

Zhang Dong stood over two piles of ash. These two scouts were discovered by him after he left the capital city of the sect of the supposed forge masters. This city had been left deserted with not even a soul remaining as these vampires had a taste for it.

The whole scene left a bad taste in his mouth. He knew that these creatures were soul vampires which would corrupt the essence of their victims. After fighting some of them he also realized that the souls that they generated were twisted and corrupt. Even him with his knowledge was unable to untangle them anymore. He could only absorb them into his soul core while purifying the evil energies that they were now composed of.

But the empty city was not the only strange occurrence in this underforge that he found. While the city showed a lot of battle damage and what looked like the main palace, the resources were not taken. When he was flying around to look for survivors he discovered the treasure that had been opened.

Where regular cultivators would quickly grab everything that they could get their hands on it, these red vampires for some reason didn’t. What they were after was slowly making sense. They always talked about something relating to a hunt, this was nothing more than a game for them. The leftover treasures didn’t matter, they only wished to kill strong enemies instead.

He could not let such an opportunity slip by, even though he felt bad about so many lives being taken he needed these resources. With the help of the replica storage medallion and his spatial rings, everything made its way into his possession. As he was able to take full buildings with him, the time he spent there wasn’t long. Afterward, he decided to go towards the large hole that was dug up. There he discovered the scouts flying around and probably searching for more prey.

‘Why did they stay here and not in the city…’

The capital had far more defenses than this smaller underground fortress where the vampires decided to stay. But seeing how they didn’t care about their cultivation materials or weapons perhaps they didn’t trust the city defenses either.

‘Or they are just so confident in themselves that they don’t think they could lose? No that’s not it…’

Zhang Dong shook his head as these opponents he was going up against were somewhat peculiar. They never run away and always fought till they died. Perhaps it wasn’t fear of someone above them that was only driving them, maybe they just liked to battle an opponent that was their equal?

‘Also what were those two talking about, some kind of Mistress?’

There was more information that he needed to gather. While he could just attack the encampment that these invaders created it could somewhat wait. He was still angry about the massacre that took place but this was an important chance. Thus his form started to shift, what once used to be his face turned into something different and crimson.

Zhang Dong copied the appearance of the louder vampire from these two. After following them all the way here he had learned some of their mannerisms to help him in his next plan. It was time, to infiltrate this base and gather some information. He already knew that these people would not talk with him, they would rather die.

When he was this close there was no problem in measuring the number of invaders. This group had about three times as much when he compared it to the ones that attacked the Shadow Phantom Sect. Perhaps this was one of the main bases to which the troops would return later. If he managed to infiltrate them well he might be able to cause some serious damage.

‘They shouldn't be able to block out my teleportation feature and with the spirit stones I have gathered there won’t be a problem with escaping.’

With his spirit stones reserves renewed he would be able to easily escape if something bad happened. This place was also closer to his own territory which would lower the spirit stone costs even further. Thus after turning himself into a red vampire he was off to their camp.

The usual disguising technique was even able to modify his exterior to look like a demon but producing the scary-looking toothy mouth would not be possible. He would need to supplement this with some hypnosis and illusionary techniques but he was unsure if the soul suckers would be fooled.

“What took you so long and where is your brood brother?”

“Oh he wasn’t so lucky, he got ambushed…”

“Ambushed? Are there more prey out there?”

“Not anymore, I killed them all, they used some strange treasure. It was an unsatisfying hunt.”

Zhang Dong tried to emulate the speech pattern of the person that he took over. He wasn’t sure about the social hierarchy of these creatures but they did have some leaders like the one that he killed at the Shadow Phantom Sect grounds. The person that he was impersonating was someone that would be at the core formation level and on the bottom end of it.

“Yes, these outworlders are proving to bore the chiefs but there are ones that we need to look out for.”

“You mean… like the golden one?”

Zhang Dong prodded as by this point he knew what these invaders were calling him.

“Yes that one, the Emperor wants him, if we find him we will be rewarded greatly!”

“Ah yes, the reward…”

He just nodded in agreement as he didn’t want to prod too much. The info that he got from this guard was already enough and told him quite the story. Apparently, the leader was impressed by his performance at the northwest border. If this Emperor was on the level of the Azure Emperor still remained to be seen, perhaps there were multiple ones and they had some other leader altogether.

“What are you standing around, go make your report or the Mistress will have your head!”

“Yes, shouldn’t let the Mistress wait.”

With that, he removed himself from the entrance and headed inside. Going to this Mistress would probably not be the greatest idea. Being the leader and probably a nascent soul master level threat she might poke some holes in his story. The better option would be to just switch it up again.

Thus he slipped away into the shadows once more. This place was built into the wall and only the burning hot lava was illuminating it. These creatures certainly didn’t like light too much and could also see in the dark. None of them expected their base to be infiltrated this soon into the war effort though and just like the two before him another of the creatures was turned to dust.

From the scout, he switched into a guard that was patrolling the area. With his new appearance, he could now loiter around without anyone being too suspicious. The only problem was his old disguise, what would they do when the scout didn’t arrive to make the report?

‘Well, this will be a good chance to see how they operate.’

This place had been some kind of fort but like the main capital city, it was now devoid of any human presence. He could see some clothes scattered here and there but the insides were empty. If he wasn’t confident in his abilities this would have been a rather frightening experience. People just disappeared with no trace, devoured by some strange red invaders.

He went through some of the buildings which caused his rage to build up even more. These beings didn’t see them as anything more than animals, this was clear. They certainly had no problem in killing young children and the elderly.

Then suddenly as he was going through one of the empty buildings he heard a strange high-pitched sound that grated his ears. It made him peek out and look out into the distance to discover that the red invaders were gathering at a peculiar tower that was radiating red light.

‘Is it their Mistress? Did they figure out that the scouts had vanished?’

While the temporary enemy base was in an uproar he remained calm and collected. The empty building that he occupied gave out a faint golden light as a character that he etched on the wall disappeared.

“Well then… this energy signature feels higher than the rest…”

Chapter 453

“Mistress please calm yourself…”

“How can I be calm, none of them have returned!”

A rather voluptuous woman dressed in dark leather was screaming at a group of men that were kneeling on the ground. Her aura was radiating crimson energy which traveled towards a small horn that was on her forehead. Unbeknownst to her, there was a person that didn’t belong here watching her.

‘That horn, it’s similar to the one that one guy had but it’s a lot smaller…’

Zhang Dong disguised as a regular soldier was standing close to the entrance of a tower where all the screaming was coming from. When being this close he could safely use his spiritual sense to peek at what was going inside there.

The Mistress that these red vampires referred to was quite the beauty. Not as much as his own wife but she had all the right proportions. Even that red coloring of her skin somewhat added to her looks that would make any submissive male drool. At this very moment, she was shouting while cracking what seemed to be a whip-type weapon.

The Mistress was just informed that a large force they sent out had magically disappeared. It was probably the troops that he eradicated at the Shadow Phantom Sect area. Which gave him some information about them not being able to relay information to each other. That battle unfolded a while ago and it seemed that only now she became aware of it.

‘Perhaps they have no long-range communication devices like the communication jades? They probably had to wait for some scouts to come back for the information to reach them.’

What this meant was that even though these invaders were strong they didn’t communicate with each other well. Tribes had been mentioned which symbolized some kind of power structure and this woman seemed to be in some kind of leading position. The small horn on her head symbolized it but its size also put her in some kind of lesser role. Probably the real leader was back at the main base while she was some kind of commander.

“Enough, what of the other reports?”

This scantily clad woman eased up with the whipping and rested on some strange-looking throne with skulls on it. From what he could feel the skulls were quite fresh and probably made from the remains of the people they slew here. She asked someone that looked like an officer but he hesitated.

“What are you hiding?”

“M-mistress… actually one of the scouting parties has gone missing, they were supposed to report but we can’t find them.”

Right after the man ended the sentence his head went flying. A fast fling of the wrist was all the woman needed for the kill. The spiritual energy that was released quickly made its way towards her mouth.

“What are you waiting for? Find him!”

It was clear that she had figured out that there was something strange about that statement. While the men scrambled she remained seated with her eyes closed, it was as if she was concentrating on something.

“It’s true, two of the children are missing…”

There seemed to be some kind of connection between this woman and the rest of the grunts. Luckily this was something that she had to focus her attention on thus he wasn’t instantly discovered yet he found himself in danger. If there was a connection there, she would probably figure out that he was not one of those ‘children’ if they ever met eye contact. While he could copy the appearance of this tribe there was a limit.

‘Perhaps it's some kind of bloodline connection? Maybe one that goes through the soul?’

He could only speculate but now he needed to make a decision. Should he wait for the right moment to strike and risk being discovered or should he wait a bit more. If he wasn’t found by anyone then he might be able to smuggle himself further down the line. Perhaps if he figured out how these people operated he could take the appearance of this commander-class woman, then visit the main camp where the leader was to slay him.

Changing into someone of the opposite gender was not one of his favorite pastimes but he was willing to do it if he could save some lives. But if that would even be a valid option remained to be seen, would this woman even report to their leader or would just push into the empire to wage more wars. There were many places that they could invade and the further into the empire they went in the pushback would become more noticeable.

From what he had seen these invaders didn’t care that much about their own soldiers. It was somewhat similar to how cultivators operated but more the ones from a demonic sect. They certainly had no problem in killing their own if they were in a bad mood.

‘So what should I do…’

Zhang Dong rubbed his chin while also inscribing a character on the tower. It glowed a little bit before fading away. While there was a possibility of continuing with the espionage mission this was not the only way. He had already carried out precautions if they found him out and now after they noticed that there was something of the base became rowdy.

“Let no one leave.”

After the Mistress noticed that a scout didn’t return they began to check with anyone that had recently returned. Everything pointed to the vampire that he had initially replaced but now he had already switched with another foot soldier which gave him more time.
But while he was sneaking around and trying to not get noticed the ground started to shake. It wasn’t the magnitude of an earthquake but something below him was coming his way. The red vampires didn’t seem to be too perturbed by it so he kept his poker face up while remaining hidden in the shadows.

Then the rocks split apart and some other strange creatures popped out of the blue. Their bodies were quite large with the leader seeming to be at three meters. Their hands were quite big and forearm heavy, their faces resembling moles that one might find out in the open.

Their bodies were covered by dark fur but they did wear some leather to cover their nether regions. The elongated face was somewhat rat-like but their nose was quite characteristic and something found on a regular mole.

“Wampir tribe, what are you still doing here? Our Talpa tribe soldiers are already on the move.”

“Be quiet, we don’t take orders from you!”

The horned Vampire Mistress started arguing with the large mole creature. It seemed that both these tribes liked to go through darkened caves and the added heat didn’t seem to bother them. The vast differences between all of these tribes were starting to get very apparent. This was the third variant that came from that Empire and there could be many more.

‘This complicates things…’

From what he was getting here these people operated in some primitive social hierarchy. The members with the horns were on top and they all came from various tribes. The hierarchy was clearly strength based but it was strange that they weren’t killing each other. Normally intelligent humanoid beings of different species wouldn’t just find common ground, this was even less probable when they were as violent as these people.

‘Is it because of their Emperor? Perhaps they came to some kind of agreement or were forced by their strongest?’

Zhang Dong listened in on the conversation while speculating some more. He was together with many other guards and kept a low profile. With the arrival of these mole people, the attention would probably shift away from his intrusion. Perhaps soon he would have an opportunity to infiltrate further while also taking out some commanders.

“Why is this outpost in such disarray, I can smell your disorder.”

“This is none of your concern, our tribe will carry out their orders.”

The woman clearly didn’t want any help. Yet the mole man seemed to be highly capable in detecting abnormalities. After noticing that there was something off in the camp he turned towards the direction where Zhang Dong was kneeling with the other soldiers. The mole man’s strange nose started wiggling around as if it could smell something from his direction.

“You dare ignore me? What are you looking at?”

The mole man just pointed out towards Zhang Dong’s direction as it just answered the question.

“That one… the soil he carries isn’t from around here…”

He was a bit perplexed at the words that the mole person spoke. His disguise wasn’t blown yet but apparently, he was somehow able to sense the earth elements that he came in contact with. There were various ways to track a person and the soil under their boots was one.

“Not from around here?”

The woman turned towards his direction while the other soldiers that were there started looking around. No one was sure to whom the mole man was pointing to as they were all bunched up in a big group.

But the person in question knew that this would probably be it. The thought of trying to weasel out of it popped into his head yet he didn’t think that it would be a valid option. He knew very little of these people's culture, talking them down would be tough.

‘Judging how that woman treated the other soldiers, she might try to decapitate me just to be sure that I’m not a spy…’

“Guess plan B it is!”

Before the woman could take a good look at him he activated his trap. His palm that was down on the ground gave out a light that quickly traveled in all directions. This pulse of Qi when coming into contact with the runic drawings he created caused a magical explosion.

Instantly the place was turned into an inferno. Golden lightning bolts started going off everywhere and each time they touched one of the red vampires they made them crumble into dust. Without having much time to react the creatures were quickly disintegrated by the holy energy that was mixed with some solar rays.

But while these types of traps were very effective against the red vampires, the mole men had a different set of weaknesses. While he did jump away and flew into the air he could see some of them burrow themselves underground to evade this electric discharge.

The massive array of magical explosions caused the entire fortress to crumble. The massive surge of energy was above what these already damaged structures could handle. Yet even though he was successful in booby-trapping the entire area there were still many survivors left.

Most of all the two leaders that were in possession of the forehead horns were still standing. The woman was floating up in the air while the mole man peeked his head out of the ground after lasting through the magical mines.

Zhang Dong started looking around and even without peeking at his minimap, he knew that he was vastly outnumbered. They were in the ground and in the walls, also on the ceiling. He was surrounded from all sides and the lava just continued to overflow everywhere.

“Well then, I don’t reckon you’ll surrender peacefully?”

He asked only to hear a massive screech from the woman vampire that caused all of her kin to pounce at him.

“I guess not.”

Chapter 454

“You kiss your mother with that mouth?”

Zhang Dong was looking down a large toothy mouth that belonged to the vampire mistress. After his identity was revealed she transformed into quite the ugly monster that he was battling now. The alluring face that she once had was replaced by something that was more similar to a bat.

The monster was quite fast but not at a level that he couldn’t handle. The bigger problem was the other commander-class opponent that was hiding below ground. This one belonged to the strange mole people and each time he was about to deliver a devastating blow to the vampire lady he was interrupted.

It was the same pattern, after dodging the chomp to the face just before he could slice her head off a large number of spiky rock bullets was sent his way. The mole people could somehow travel through the earth as if it was made of water. Even when he tried to counter with his own ranged attack, he only managed to create a crater with no bodies left behind.

Even though the opponents traversed it as if it was an ocean, it was still hard rock mixed with lava. It presented a great natural barrier that protected them from harm, he would probably need to perform a more devastating attack if he wished to kill the leader.

The mole was also the one that somehow discovered his true identity. From what he knew, moles had a good sense of smell while they were practically blind. While he might not have carried the smell of humans thanks to his perfect disguise, some of the soil that he brought over was not from around here.

This was a miscalculation on his part but how should he have known that he also needed a change of clothes and perhaps a bath to infiltrate this place? Yet this would be a good learning opportunity for whenever he decided to infiltrate any further. These monsters didn’t seem to transfer information between each other too well, so his plan might still be salvageable.

‘First I need to survive though…’

After dodging a few sharp claws that had strange reddish soul energy empowering them, he was further pelted by fast-moving rocky projectiles. The mole person was a full-body refiner which made his Qi signature quite faint.

The commander class opponent was not the only mole man buried under the ground. He was skillfully using his men to fool his senses, thus he decided to rely on his AI assistant for help.

‘Bob, lock in on their leader's signature and present it on the map overlay.’

‘Affirmative.’

While visiting the hiding place of his predecessor he had learned that there might be something wrong with the system. Thus he was now unsure if he should be relying on his system. It was a hacked version of the old one but this didn’t mean that he was truly safe from the person that made the original, nor if the videos that he found at that secret ground were to be trusted.

For the time being, he needed to get rid of this problem, it seemed that this war would be the ending point of this world's scenario. If he could get through it alive he would have enough time to contemplate a strategy. Before that occurred he felt that he was free to use the system’s features to their fullest.

Thus now with a red marker on his map, he had a target to go towards. The vampire lady that was charging towards him was also a problem but first, he needed to focus on her ranged support. With a quick hand motion, he gathered energy before him, this was not a deadly attack but a quick distraction.

The whole place was bathed in a bright light that had a trace amount of holy energy. While it would not cause any lasting damage to the vampire it did stun her for a second. A second was enough time for him to charge down. While the flying opponent was shrieking loudly the moleman came to her rescue.

This time around though, Zhang Dong was ready. With the help of his sword, he performed a thrust towards the spot that the mole commander was. As he was assisting the vampire lady for a fraction of a second he remained in place and this was enough time for the sword of light to reach him.

“ARGH!”

While Zhang Dong could hear the monster's scream he was only able to wound him. Yet this was more than enough to cause him to retreat which was his plan all along. The vampire lady quickly recovered and when she spotted him floating in the air she gave chase. But now she would be in for a surprise as he intended to go through with his attacks now.

It was clear to him that these people were similar to cultivators in some ways, one of them was their will to live and get stronger. The moleman was quick to abandon his ally after getting pierced by Zhang Dong’s sword of light that pierced through the earth. Thus he would be quite busy in trying to recover from the wound and not care about the vampire ally.

After repeatedly evading the claw attack that shredded the entire landscape along with the vampire underlings, Zhang Dong delivered a palm strike to the vampire monster’s side. This sends her flying into the nearby wall. Previously a barrage of precise rock bullets would cause him to fail but now there was nothing stopping him.

“Talpa tribe, Get back here!”

The vampire mistress shouted while also probably realizing that the molemen were on the retreat. They didn’t take orders from her and would clearly protect their own leader that was now injured.

He could not imagine his own sect members acting in this way if someone was in trouble. Some of his moral values had bled over onto his disciples and people who respected him. They would even offer up aid to ones outside their sect circle but they would still prioritize their own faction’s well-being over others.

Thus without the aid of the second commander type, the vampire lady would be in for a rude awakening. With his current skills and cultivation level, Zhang Dong wouldn’t even need to break a sweat. By utilizing his sword arts the claws that she was using were promptly cut.

By applying solar energy to go along with his holy aura the vampire was unable to regenerate her lost appendages. Even when retreating and absorbing her own followers the radiant energy that he injected into her could not be removed. Soon after a couple of exchanges she found herself with a missing leg and one leg less. Her wings were also removed which caused her to plummet down to the ground.

“Your allies have abandoned you but maybe I could spare your life if you answer a few questions.”

Zhang Dong’s map showed him that the moleman had retreated into the distance. Clearly, he had judged this to have been unfavorable to him and his tribe. Now he could try chasing after them but his capabilities of traveling underground were more limited. His opponent would probably inform the leaders about what transpired here so he didn’t have much time.

“You will pay for this, you lowly worm!”

“Sorry but I’m not into that sort of play, now we could do this the easy way or the hard way.”

He grasped the monster vampire that started to revert to her more humanoid form. She was missing some limbs and bleeding some strange dark blood. Yet even now she was showing resistance and an unwillingness to cooperate.

“The emperor will skin you alive!”

She continued to shout and thrash about until the bitter end. An attempt was made of capture yet before he could go through with it the vampire did something strange. With all of her limbs cut off and Zhang Dong ready with the prison medallion she knew what was about to happen. Before he could go through with it, her soul was shattered not by his hand but by her own.

“I will not be captured by the likes of you! The Emperor will avenge me, the great hunt will continue until these lands run red with blood!”

The body of the vampire was quick to crumble into dust the moment her soul ceased to exist. There was nothing left for his soul core to even absorb as she performed this strange technique that would bring true death to her. Without a soul remaining any chances of reincarnation or rebirth would be impossible.

He could only watch at the pile of gray sand that formed on the ground. Along with the vampire mistress' demise, the other vampires quickly went into a fit of rage. Yet there weren’t that many left and with one burst of energy, they followed their mistress into death.

“Well, this was an unfortunate turn of events… I don’t think I can catch up to those mole guys like this.”

With the monsters now all dead the stronghold that he was in felt rather empty. It was devoid of any signs of life and even now he was unable to find any survivors of the crafter-focused sect that was once here. He did manage to line his pockets with various treasures and his soul core did increase in size.

“This has left a bad taste in my mouth…”

After giving out a sigh he peeked into the replica medallion to make sure that the one prisoner that he took was still in there. While he had hoped to bring the leader over for questioning, her officer would probably be enough. He had already witnessed these monsters in action but the information that this being gave him would help him confirm his theories.

“It would probably be wise to retreat, for now, those guys will probably come back with reinforcements but before that…”

Before leaving this place he decided to leave a few presents for any of those hunt loving monsters. If he was lucky he would have fewer enemies to contend with and perhaps some more information.

With that in mind, he left a save point to travel back to later on. This place was close to what looked like an enemy camp. With his teleportation feature, he would be able to open a gate to get back here. He could also decide on another infiltration attempt after the coast was clear but for now, it was time to return to his own people and decide on a new set of plans.

“This might take longer than I thought.”

He gave this place that was devoid of life another look before his body vanished and appeared next to one of his trusted allies. It was a burly red-haired man that looked somewhat excited.

“Senior brother!”

“Hey there Qiang, how is the war effort going?”

“It’s great, I haven't had so much fun in years!”

“Fun, huh…”

The place he was in now was a battle zone. The enemies continued to come and his elders would be tested. This war didn’t seem to be close to ending and the resources of his enemies were unknown to him, only time would tell if he had made the right decisions as this battle continued.

Chapter 455

“Zhu, we must hurry, the beasts are coming, don’t look back!”

“Why is this happening to us?”

A small group of cultivators was flying through the air. Two of them were on flying swords while the rest was tightly packed on a small flying ship. Behind them, they could hear loud screeching noises similar to what bats would sound like.

The two on the swords were core formation experts at an advanced age. In the boat were people that were wearing similar robes with the same clan symbol engraved on them. It was clear that these people were trying to flee.

“I don’t know, it doesn’t matter, we must make it to the border! My distant cousin knows one of the elders there, it's our only chance!”

The old man spoke to the old woman that he called Zhu. But she quickly shouted back at him while being worried.

“You haven’t seen him in over a hundred years, you don’t even know if he is still at the border wall, what if the sect turns their blades against us along with these monsters?”

This caused the old man’s brows to furrow but he just shook his head.

“What choice do we have? Do you wish to turn around now?”

He then pointed towards the distance where a cloud of gray mist started appearing. From within the strange sounds resonated and continued to increase in loudness. Soon the grayish coloring started to shift into a dark red while winged monsters with fangs and teeth emerged from within. Their strange shrieks caused everyone to shiver in fear.

Try they did, but their flying treasures were just not fast enough. Every second the monsters got closer and even when everyone continuously boosted the flying speed with their own cultivation but it was not enough. The creatures were gaining ground and soon they would massacre them just like they did their whole city.

“Wait what’s that?”

When all hope was lost the old man looked into the distance where the border region would be. They were nowhere near it at this point but some kind of blue light appeared out from the distance. It was followed by an earth-quaking roar and soon the true nature of this blue hue was revealed.

“A water dragon?”

The creature looked to be made from water-based spiritual energy. It was quite huge and many times larger than the ship the people were staying on. As the blue watery behemoth passed by them the old man noticed that there were several cultivators inside it.

“It’s a battle formation! Did the sects decide to do something about these monsters?”

While the old man was full of questions he also noticed that this large dragon wasn’t the only one. Soon to the side, another one appeared but instead of being made from water, it was scorching with red fire energy that was luckily being contained thanks to the water elements from the first dragon.

It was quite the spectacle, even more so when a third dragon made from earth and a fourth one made from wind energy entered the fray. They were constructs made by cultivators in a special formation and each one had the strength of an early nascent soul master.

The dragons used their breath attacks on the strange bat creatures that were following them. With them being now busy the small group of cultivators was free to make their escape. Their speedy pace had slowed down as they continued to gwack into the distance where the large-scale battle was taking place.

“Identify yourself!”

After a few moments had passed a loud voice was heard by everyone. In the direction the dragons came from, the old man heard someone call out to him. When looking at a scary-looking man that was built like a brickhouse was staring at him.

“W-we are from the Chao Clan, we had to abandon the city that had been overrun by strange human-like beasts.”

The man that he was speaking with was clearly a nascent soul master. After hearing the quick explanation he just gave out a grunt before monologuing to himself.

“Damn pests are everywhere, Is that youngster punishing me by sending me here?”

The man’s robe was unfamiliar to him but he recognized the symbols that were attributed to the United Element’s Sect. This sect was said to be on the decline before their Patriarch was announced to be the Emperor’s blood brother.

“S-seniorr…”

The old man wanted to ask if it was okay for them to continue but the man he was talking with shrouded his body in a layer of flames and took off towards the battle. Many other cultivators with the same robes zoomed through the air while mostly ignoring them.

“E-elder, what should we do? Don’t think these people are hostile…”

The old man nodded at the person named Zhu and they soon corrected their flight path to head towards where these people came from. They came to the conclusion that this sect was their best bet at survival as they seemed to be managing the monsters that could not push further and give chase anymore.

….
“Please don’t push, we will be performing a quick examination before you are allowed to move through.”

A person dressed in a white robe shouted with the aid of their Qi. His words traveled far and wide to the mass of people that were both on the ground and in the air. Everyone was standing before a very high wall that was as tall as any skyscraper. At the highest point, a certain white-haired person appeared. He looked into the vast expanse while spreading his spiritual sense in all directions.

‘Huo Qiang’s father is doing a good job at contending with these vampire monsters, maybe I should make good use of his battle skills, he is above the other early stage elders that just managed to push through.’

A few weeks had passed since Zhang Dong’s failed infiltration attempt. With the help of some unsavory techniques, they were able to get some information from the creature that he had captured. The scientists from his sect were more than happy to experiment and test out some weapons on the creature that was susceptible to solar energy.

There were a few things that they discovered after the autopsy and questioning. One was that this creature was originally human. Yet through some strange techniques, it had become disfigured and gained the enhanced traits that it had. The consensus was that their body refining technique had changed their previous physiology at a level that even affected their children.

“The great hunt huh…”

Zhang Dong murmured to himself while watching a small group of cultivators arriving from where he sent the core formation battalion to. The resources he had were still limited, there was no way for him to just pump out more nascent soul masters without any end. Instead, he used his much larger stockpile of core formation experts.

While they were nowhere near the power level of a nascent soul master, there were ways to improve their fighting capabilities. These were with various attacking formations that he had plenty of time to improve. It was much better to gather up the core formation experts to form an elemental formation dragon than to have them wandering around the battlefields alone.

The enemies they were facing against were quite powerful. They had many leaders that were around the nascent soul level. Instead of sending his men to just be massacred, they could now be useful. While the formation was more in line with a soul beasts strength they would act as support for his own nascent soul masters,

“Patriarch!”

“Give me the report.”

“As you wish!”

While contemplating this war one of the soldiers arrived to give him more information. While the mapping feature showed him the highest concentration of the enemies, there were also various stealthy scouts scouring the area for more information.

The information came in a communication jade that he quickly crushed into powder. In it he was informed about the casualty count as well as on which clans and sects were eradicated in the process of this ‘hunt’

While the man that delivered the information removed himself he was left with lingering feelings of anger. The monsters that he was fighting with now apparently took pleasure in hunting, if the prey was strong they enjoyed it even more. But there were ones like these vampire bastards that preferred murdering the weak and defenseless.

Their leader apparently took a liking to his performance when he destroyed their first base. While he did not make his way into these lands this could change depending on how much pushback they would offer them.

Zhang Dong decided to spread out his umbrella over these lands somewhat further than he had originally intended. Thanks to this many refugees flocked from the areas that were in chaotic combat with the invaders. Luckily there was enough food to go around, at least that was easy to produce in this world.

Initially, the plan was to wait it out but things were moving faster than he expected. The creatures didn’t meet much resistance from the sects and the lands along with their people fell. It was unknown if each of these invading tribes just killed the population or enslaved them instead.

For some reason, the attackers didn’t care about the cultivation of treasures of the sect. They were more interested in satisfying their cardinal desires of hunting or slaughtering. Due to this fact, his sect was able to confiscate quite a large amount of these materials from each city they managed to liberate.

With the ever-growing resources came the increase in their strength as he could use some of them to create more nascent souls or even core formation elders. While these new experts and masters would not be as trained in their arts they were better than nothing.

“Patriarch, the elders are waiting.”

“Good, I’ll be right there.”

Another messenger arrived to inform him about the meeting that he had ordered. After some walking, he arrived at a makeshift gathering room where a bunch of the new nascent soul masters he helped create were. All eyes were on him and while in the past this would have caused him to be nervous now it almost felt natural.

“Listen up, I’m sure you know what this is about, I would have not gathered you all here otherwise.”

The old men and women that were reinvigorated with their new nascent soul strength all nodded. They all knew that soon they would be taking the fight to the monsters that were ravaging their lands, it was time to launch a counter-attack and to see if they were ready for victory.

Chapter 456

“Carmilla has died?”

“Yes my lord.”

A tall old man with a clean-shaven visage was sitting in what looked to be a large throne-like chair. It had many strange engravings that depicted demonic-looking creatures. In his hand, he was holding a golden chalice in which a strange liquid was red and glowing. While speaking he took a few sips that when ingested made his eyes glow red.

The man’s pale face made him look like a marble statue devoid of life. This white skin tone contrasted with the pitch-black clothes that he was wearing. If Zhang Dong was here he would clearly know who this person resembled.

“Lord Valentine, what are your orders?”

“My orders? Just continue, if that stupid sister of mine had gotten herself killed by one of these savages then it was her fault but this makes things somewhat more interesting, do you know who it was that killed her?”

“Yes my lord, it was the one marked by the Emperor.”

The man that looked like a walking corpse perked up the moment his lackey gave him this information. Some time had passed since Zhang Dong had taken care of the soul vampire stronghold but only now did the information reach their real leader.

“Well that does make things more interesting… the Emperor’s chosen prey…”

The man that looked like a vampire straight from an old movie started rubbing his chin while looking at this scared follower. After a moment a devilish grin appeared on his face that sent shivers down the messenger's spine.

“My lord?”

Before receiving any orders the vampiric lord rose from his seat. He moved towards the side where a large gothic-styled window was peeking out into the horizon. There he saw a shroud of gray that was covering the whole landscape but with his enhanced eyes he could see all of the members of his tribe.

“I was bored out of my mind, maybe it's time to stretch my wings!”

In a flash, his body transformed into mist which somewhat mixed with the environment. Without asking the followers quickly followed after their master that had clearly made the decision to go out to hunt. They all changed into the flying bat monsters that were already known for terrorizing these lands.

On his way out a huge grim-looking castle could be seen in the distance. Surrounding it was a large wall of spikes that had thousands of human skulls pierced on the top. The moat that was around it was pitch black and the rancid smell of decaying flesh was everywhere.
….

‘Hm?’

Zhang Dong was done with his meeting, the decision to push into the enemy territory was made but suddenly something had changed.

‘Is there a large force coming this way?’

With the help of his mapping feature, he could somewhat see what was happening at the enemy lines. The largest concentration of energy that was the enemy base had shifted. The map was clearly showing him that the vampires were on the move.

‘Or did their leader decide to show himself?’

While he was planning to use some of his resources to help the refugees to escape the lands that were taken by the invaders, the stage of the last attack was not yet reached. Their enemies were spread between various tribes which didn’t really function well together.

This he confirmed by injuring the moleman that was quick to abandon the vampire mistress to save his life. They would rather have the allied tribes be eradicated than waste their own manpower for a potential hard-won victory.

Not like this was any different than how the human sects operated. But at least his side was more uniform in their beliefs and looks. It was a lot more difficult to see eye to eye with people that didn’t resemble each other, even more if they looked like they came from different planets.

‘Is this some kind of trap?’

Zhang Dong started contemplating this issue. Having the leader move out this soon was somewhat strange. Normally it was him that did these things as there were not that many people on his side that could handle themselves. Did the leader give up on their troops already? Perhaps there was fear of the Emperor mixed into it?

‘The leader could also just be stupid, it didn’t seem that these vampires thought much of us… whatever the reason is, this might be a chance…’

“Patriarch, the main sect sends words, there has been movement from the enemy! A large shift in…”

Zhang Kuo was here to inform him about the movement on the map. No one knew that he had his own internal version of the map he left at the sect. The map that he left at home was there to help his soldiers make their own decisions.

With its help, they were successfully able to successfully win most of their battles and evacuate if trouble was coming. It was true, the person with more information would be victorious. Before Kuo could continue with the explanation he raised his hand to stop him.
‘I know, something is approaching, have the masters gather, we will meet them in the field, have the ships move in, this might be an important battle that we must win. Use the teleportation gates if you have to, we need all able experts on this one.’

The decision was made, while he could not be sure if the leader was moving out themself. The dimming of the spiritual markers on the map at the main stronghold indicated that at least it was a sizable force. If they could predict the movements of the monsters they might be able to take care of them in one fell swoop.

If they could get rid of a large number of them, then the stronghold could be for the taking. Yet the enemy numbers were unknown to them. They might be quickly replaced by another bunch of body refiners that had their bodies altered. This war was supposed to last for a hundred years and be the last scenario before its ascension. Then there were all the other empires that were still frolicking on the east and north side of the empire.

At this moment in time, they were further north of the Dragon Gate Sect. This place had been ransacked by the invaders but part of the old guard that ruled these lands had remained while escaping. For the time being, they took over the border region where small skirmishes were taking place.

‘Huo’s daddy should be wrapping out the battle, if we move fast we should be able to encircle them without them noticing us…’

With the help of this mapping feature, it was quite easy to prepare. One part was seeing the movement of troops and the other was the knowledge of the topography. From how it looked the enemies would be passing through a large gorge. It was an area where lightning energies ran rampant which made it even better for him.

‘The large storms would help push the vampires down on the ground and keep them from fleeing… but will it be that easy?’

They had a moment of surprise and more information. It all seemed to be going his way but he could not let his pride get in the way. For some reason, these invaders felt confident in defeating them. He mostly attributed it to the way they ate souls.

Even if their bodies were turned to meat pace, as long as their soul survived they could save themselves. Regretfully for them, Zhang Dong was in possession of the soul core that could easily eradicate their trump card.

The leader was probably assured that even if he did lose the fight he would be at least able to keep his soul intact and regain his form later. There were many demonic techniques that prolonged one's life but due to them mostly not exceeding the heavenly grade they didn’t last. With each use, these techniques would somewhat damage the original soul which would either kill the user or alter them in some kind of way.

‘Well then, this will be a good test…’

With the help of the map he knew where to set up the ambush but this was only a part of the strategy. This would be one of the first large-scale operations that his United Element sect would be performing. Cultivators ranging from the foundation establishment realm all the way up to the nascent soul one would be participating.

They needed to be fast though, there wasn’t much time to prepare. If they were too slow the enemies would be at their doorstep before they prepared their countermeasures.

“I’ll go on ahead, have all the formation masters gather, we will be moving out in ten minutes!”

He shouted a few orders before hovering towards the gathering location. They had set up a temporary teleportation gate that was now working overtime. Through it, many soldiers and experts started to appear. They were quick to bow towards their patriarch, in their eyes he was a god-like being by now. If they had a chance to prove their worth in the coming battle they were more than willing to die for it.

The faces of the people before him were mostly new to him. He did not go out of his way to mingle with his sect members. Spending time with his family was prioritized while his underlings like Zhang Kuo were the ones forwarding his orders and interacting with others. Luckily after that one lie he experienced in the past, Kuo had made up for the lost trust.

“Haha, to think I’d see a day like this!”

While there were many new faces there was one that was quite familiar. It belonged to Zhang Jin that had managed to condense his nascent soul well enough to finally join in the battle. He along with a couple of other nascent soul masters were also going to participate in this battle but mostly during the battle phase and not for their knowledge about formations.

“I’ll leave it to you, gramps. Gather the forces, it seems like a chance like this might not repeat itself, if the enemies discover that he can follow their movements they will surely change their strategy.”

“Aye, leave it to me, I’ll straighten them out, It’s been a while since I’ve been able to use this!”

Zhang Jin was like a new person, he had mostly remained back at the clan or sect to manage it. Now on the other hand as a nascent soul master, he could finally sink his weapon back into an enemy. He rested his brand new large saber over his shoulder while strutting towards the gathering forces which he would be commanding.

‘Well then, let us get this show on the road.’

Chapter 457

‘Is that it? No wonder they are assured of their victory’

“Get ready, here they come, activate the soul-sapping formation when I give the signal.”

The group of cultivators that were with him looked out into the distance but they couldn’t see much in the thick fog that was approaching. It was a mass of reddish mist that looked ominous yet it didn’t seem to contain any enemies.

This was obviously due to the fact that the monsters had shifted into a soul-like form. It would not be possible for anyone not versed in soul arts to see their true appearance. These techniques were quite hard to counter as even with Qi attacks the user would not take any damage while also being able to sap away the soul energy from their enemies.

Yet in this case, they had underestimated their opponents that had Zhang Dong on their side. With his knowledge about souls and his soul core, he was more than ready to take care of these invaders. While it was hard to counter soul creatures, if you went through proper preparations it was quite easy.

“Now!”

He finally gave the order after the swarm of the monsters made their way over the trapping formation. It was placed through a large gorge that was surrounded by mountains and even though this mist was covering a lot more space, the monsters inside were more concentrated.

With the signal being given the people that were hiding in the mountains and outside the gorge started performing hand signals. Their bodies started to quickly radiate spiritual energy that was siphoned into the formation points.

At the bottom of the gorge, the earth started shining brightly with a silvery light that elongated through most of its length. Then out of nowhere shiny swords made from special energy shot out to create a prison of light.

“Fools, do you think you can contain me with this?”

The moment the prison of shiny swords formed he heard a booming voice from within. This was followed by a spiritual pressure that was akin to the horned monster he met at the fortress he destroyed.

“So you are one of the horny ones huh? Don’t think that this soul prison is ordinary!”

Some of the light swords started being pushed back by the crimson mist that turned into something that looked like blood. Yet even when it tried to push the formation was steady and stabilizing.

“How is it? You don’t seem to be able to break free.”

The formation that formed started constricting while the swords wrapped around the red mist. Even though it seemed like there was a lot of space for the mystified monsters to squeeze through, something was keeping them from moving through the gaps. Soon enough they started switching into their corporal bodies in hopes of breaking out.

“Too late for that now just become fuel for my soul core instead!”

Zhang Dong used the time that they were confused to position himself above the orb of constricting swords. He pointed out with his finger which produced a golden light. In a flash, the silver light turned golden along with the entire formation. This turned a trap into something akin to an oven and the souls of these vampires would be the ones being cooked.

“No, what is this, my strength it’s being drained away? You fools what are you doing, break through this prison at once, your lord commands it!”

The leader’s form had slowly taken shape. It reminded Zhang Dong of every other Dracula look-alike that he had seen in popular media. He was wearing a suit with a black cape that was crimson on the inside. Yet even when he was taking form his powers were being drained and flowed into Zhang Dong’s soul core.

‘Are they the soul vampires or am I one?’

Zhang Dong could hear the monsters screaming inside the constricting prison of light. The spiritual energy flowed into him and his core started to bloat up. After absorbing so much holy energy back at the Emperor’s home, he was finally equaling it out with all the soul energy he achieved through this war. After this he would need to shift towards lightning energy otherwise he was risking an imbalance of his three elements.

‘This is going well… a bit too well…’

While the sword prison that started out with a circumference of half a kilometer shrunk down by ten times, there was something fishy. To the sides, he could see some of the gray mist turning crimson and shifting into a few red vampires. This was planned beforehand as it was somewhat impossible to catch them all in one spot. Some of the minions were not caught in the initial formation and for some reason remained stationary on the outside.

‘Why aren’t they trying to help their master, was him shouting around some kind of trick to shift the attention away from them if that’s the case…’

The formation was at its end, every sprinkle of soul had been suctioned away into his soul core yet, some stragglers remained. When looking at one in particular he realized that he had been fooled by the main vampire lord.

“Something akin to soul transfer? Is it bloodline related?”

At first, the monster took the shape of a regular underling. Yet after Zhang Dong’s gaze turned to it, the being started to shift. Its face took on the appearance of the Dracula look-alike in a matter of seconds as if he was him from the start.

There were many strange techniques in this world. During the soul absorption, there was some kind of strange signal that was sent out. He felt it slightly but recognized it too late, this was probably the essence of the vampire lord’s soul which took over one of its underlings. With the flesh being similar the stronger soul had no trouble in taking over.

“So, these tribe members of yours are nothing more than vessels?”

“Savage, you will pay for this transgression, I wanted to offer your weakened body up to the Emperor but now you will die to sustain me!”

“What’s with that Emperor of yours, is he my number one fan or something?”

While the lord of the vampires was out of his prison it didn’t mean that he was fully recovered. The invaders suffered a lot of casualties already and any normal leader would probably sound the horn to retreat. Without the soul formation there to stop them, they could probably fade away to the sides to make it hard to chase them down. Instead, the remaining soldiers started screaming loudly while tossing themselves at the people operating the formation.

“Everyone, attack!”

Zhang Jin was quick to react as it was time for phase two of the plan. The nascent soul masters were waiting for this very moment and hiding. With the enemies concentrating on the formation masters, they were susceptible to another surprise attack.

Finally, he was not the only one putting himself in the line of fire. Normally he would need to take care of the leader while constantly evading the minions. While they couldn’t cause much damage they were quite annoying, one misstep could be deadly.

About eighty percent of the vampires had been trapped in the sword prison that was close to vanishing. If they managed to clear out the remaining twenty percent then the leader would not have anyone to slip his soul into. Even though it might have looked like a godly technique to the untrained eye, there was a weakness.

As every technique that was not at the immortal grade level, this one probably had one too. Zhang Dong could only speculate as he didn’t have any specific knowledge about it. Either there was a limit of times that the vampire could use this body swap art, or there was a limited range.

Thus the battle started with the Dracula look-alike pulling out a stylish crimson rapier. It seemed that Zhang Dong would be involved in a lot of thrusting motions as the enemy switched into a fencing position. With one swift thrust, he made the space around the blade turn crimson while shooting forward at a staggering speed.

He quickly threw himself to the side but even then he felt something grazing his cheek. Strange demonic energy started to invade his body but it was quickly repelled by his holy energies that were mixed together with sun rays.

“That was fast…”

The opponent he was facing was no beginner, the speed that this weapon could produce was something reaching the height past the great circle of the nascent soul level.If he was not the bane of demonic cultivators this one attack would have been his ruin.

“How could this be, what are you?”

Dracula noticed that something was off, the moment he saw the small wound on Zhang Dong’s cheek he was assured of his victory. His devilish grin quickly turned into a frown when the gash didn’t progress further but instead vanished.

“I’m probably the only person immune to demonic arts, you won’t be able to defeat me with tricks like that.”

“We shall see you savage!”

Another high-speed thrusting attack flew his way but this time around, instead of his cheek a little bit of his hair got tangled up into it. After the second one, Zhang Dong had figured out the art. While it was something that exceeded even his perception to a point, the attack in itself wasn’t that hard to evade if he predicted where it would land.

While this sounded easy in theory it would not be possible without his keen battle senses that he had honed for some years. Thus with small bursts of flight, he started getting closer to the vampire fencer that was dancing around him, soon enough his own blade was utilized to throw out some ranged attacks to break his enemies form.

“Speed is your forte and not caring about taking damage would make you a tough opponent if you weren’t up against something like me…”

Soon the vampire lord felt a gush on his chest as Zhang Dong sunk his blade into him. Just like his speedy attacks the soul switch happened almost instantly. The husk that had his sword inside of it was nothing more than a decoy. The move happened almost at the same time as the blade hit the flesh as if it was some kind of defense mechanism to save his life.

In the distance, one of the minions started shifting into the new appearance while battling one of his sect members. The unprepared cultivator took this chance to deliver a strike of his own but the enemy did not move from its place even when wounded. Its hand made its way towards this core formation master’s throat even when Zhang Dong charged from the distance it was already too late, the sect member was already being devoured.

“Shit…”

Not even a corpse was left behind and the floating sword he was using plummeted to the ground while other sect members cleared out. While he didn’t believe that he would be able to carry out this battle without any casualties it wasn’t easy when one of your men died. With rage building up in his eyes Zhang Dong took a swing to quickly dispose of the new body only for another switch to soon occur.
“This might take a while…”

He mumbled while quickly following after the soul that quickly moved from body to body. One by one he would kill them until none remained.

Chapter 458

“Don't let him get away!”

“Block their escape, corner them into one area otherwise he will flee!”

Zhang Jin and Dong were shouting out orders while pointing to some of the vampire monsters. With their leader constantly switching between bodies it was hard to deliver the final blow. It seemed that this technique didn’t have a cooldown timer nor was it very taxing on his cultivation. Yet there was one weakness, the vampire always switched to the closest minion available to take them over.

Thus they decided to encircle the entire area while not allowing the enemies to leave. While the soul trapping formation had run its course, it also had a secondary function of not allowing the monsters to turn back into the soul mist form. They needed to battle their way through the countless cultivators and battle formations that they were using.

‘This guy is a lot more slippery than I had anticipated…’

While Zhang Dong could probably take the leader out if it was a one-on-one bout, first he had to corner him. This could be achieved by removing the other monsters from the battlefield either by killing them or moving them to a far enough location this his soul couldn't jump into.

The longer this battle took the harder it was to find the leader. At first, it was obvious which of the monsters he was by their reactions but soon enough he started hiding. Whenever he changed he tried to slip into a larger group to flee as he had realized that there was no winning this battle.

“Dong’er, the sect members are getting tired, the battle formations take a lot of spiritual energy, they were not made with the intent of a prolonged battle, we must finish this quickly otherwise…”

During the chase, he had almost forgotten that not everyone had an almost perfect foundation as he did. The core formation masters in the huge dragon formations could only sustain them for up to a few hours during combat before they needed rest. By how chaotic this battlefield was, with monsters that could regenerate themselves to a point it was taking long to finish it.

With time not being on his side, he decided to go for broke. Before the enemy could escape he took up the lotus position and spread his spiritual sense to its maximum. His body started to glow with the usual golden aura as he tried to pinpoint the evil soul.

Then suddenly his eyes shot up and he pointed his digit towards one particular vampire that was crawling down on the ground and hiding behind some rocks. He needed to be fast and for this, he utilized a big chunk of his spiritual energy.

A beam of light shot out towards the monster that traveled even faster than the vampire lord’s own attacks. It split right before impact into many tiny golden rays of light that quickly showered the whole area with his energy. His aim was not to kill but to injure the monster, while he kept him immobilized his people would push the other remaining enemies out of the range of this strange game-like respawning technique.

It was clear that the monster was weaker in this new form that seemed a bit more sluggish than the one he appeared in. In Zhang Dong’s opinion, it was probably due to the soul still getting used to the new flesh it had taken over along with the soul it devoured to use it. There was probably a small pushback from its kin as it was being taken over.

“That’s it, I’ve got you now and you’re not going anywhere!”

After taking the holy rain to the back of its head the creature was stunned for just a second. This was enough time for him to get over and suppress it with his superior spiritual power. Instead of locks made from swords, he utilized chains to bind the vampire in place. Even then he felt a lot of resistance coming from the vampire lord that started shifting his appearance into a giant bat.

He would not last forever as binding spells like this did utilize a lot of spiritual energy while he was up against a body refiner. Yet he continued to suppress him while his allies tried to clear up the stranglers. With him being forced to remain here it was time for Zhang Jin and Huo Qiang to lead.

Zhang Jin had only recently made it through the change into the nascent soul realm. His soul beast was not yet formed due to this fact thus he had to utilize his other techniques that were still core formation based. Even then he was more than able to go toe to toe with the enemy underlings of similar strength.

Huo Qiang on the other hand as always tossed himself into the fray attacking the strongest opponent he could find. His style of fighting was not that well suited for cooperation as the increased heat produced from his attacks could hurt his allies. Thus he was mostly charging in before everyone else to help them identify the area that they should avoid.

This time around he needed to contain his battle hunger as there were far too many sect members encircling the gorge from all sides. At this point in time, they had managed to contain the monsters inside that were slowly getting slaughtered by mostly ranged attacks.

“You lower being, I will not stand for this!”

“Quiet down, soon we will be able to chat after my people dispose of yours.”

A little droplet of sweat appeared on Zhang Dong’s forehead as he started to get tired. It seemed that he might have underestimated the horned bastards too much. This monster had an unmanageable amount of stamina that was fueled by its soul and body.

The longer it had time to get used to the new vessel the harder it was for him to contain him within the shackles. While it would have been easy to make him explode when he had him contained, he needed to wait until the other monsters were dead.

When he looked into the distance he could see his people working hard. They were all working according to plan, if one of them got injured a group of sect members jumped in to save them. They formed a barricade with their bodies and the ones versed in medicinal arts were quick to mend them right up.

They were doing better than he had expected. Even with the increase in their cultivation art grade, it was still up to them to use it. With the help of his system faction bit, he was able to somewhat steer them in the right direction, even though he was gone for five years they managed to stay on course.

While this did bring a smile to his face, they were still getting injured. These monsters were quite ferocious, they were really end-game mobs made for the scenario with the intention of taking a large chunk of the outer empire for themselves. Without the help of the top sects and clans, the regular ones had no chance.

It was a strange feeling to see people be affected by your own decisions. In his past life, he didn’t have the opportunity to be responsible for any employees. He felt like a president of a company that was gaining more and more prestige. If it went well then they could take out the monsters occupying the border region and perhaps take out their fortress soon enough. If they managed that, then perhaps halting their advance would be a possibility.

‘That Emperor of theirs sounds troublesome. If I can get their base and reinforce it with my own defenses it could be possible to save many lives.’

His main objective was to create his own stronghold in the region. It would probably take some time but with enough cannons and formations, it might be possible to seal the bridge. There was not much space to maneuver there with enough firepower they could shoot down any flying ships or monster worms. They also seemed unable to borrow into the land at the crossing point and needed to get over to their side for a proper fight.

“Stop struggling, it's over, perhaps I’ll let you live if you let me bind your soul.”

“Bind this lord to your will, Impossible!”

“Are you sure, you are running out of bodies to switch…”

The vampire lord looked out into the distance where his uncoordinated tribe members were getting slaughtered by the larger number of cultivators. After their master was detained they didn’t seem capable enough on their own. They were quick to get into a frenzy which was easy to counter by soldiers with enough experience.

“No this cannot be… I will remember this disgrace outlander, I will have your head!”

“You still think that you will get away?”

Zhang Dong focused even more of his spiritual energy on the bindings of this monster while he continued to squirm around. It looked like his people would be fast enough, before he run out of Qi the vampires would be no more. Then he could either imprison this horned one or kill him on the spot. Without his soul having another vessel it would dissipate or be up for his soul core to absorb.

Yet, as the victory was assured something unexpected happened. These monsters were not cultivators so he had not seen them using any safety measures like hidden talismans. But when the victory was almost there, the vampire’s horn started glowing. It quickly shattered while producing a light that shot up into the sky.

“Shit!”

He instantly felt that the soul left the creature's body and flowed with that light into the sky. Even when he bolted towards it with all his might, he was not fast enough. The dark ray of energy started to constantly increase in speed until it vanished into the horizon.

The body that the monster was occupying quickly crumbled into dust as it turned into a lifeless husk. With the master retreating the other vampires were in even more of a frenzy now, it was as if they received some kind of temporary buff that burned their souls towards destruction.

“Hold them, they are breaking through the line!”

“AHhhhhh.”

“No, stay back!”

“Defend the injured, there is something wrong with them, they are getting bigger and faster!”

The cries of his sect members made him look back, he made a quick judgment call and turned back. His people needed help while the monster commander was long gone. While it might have been possible to chase him down, the lives of his people were more important. Before more people died he would protect them so that they could fight on another day.

Chapter 459

In a dimly lit chamber, a pool of blood started bubbling slightly. Soon a strange dark light flew through a hidden opening in the ceiling which caused a chain reaction. The blood started erupting and gushing in every direction while a humanoid shape formed in the middle.

“He Will Pay! All of them will pay, how dare they do this to me Valentine!’

The vampire lord’s body was crimson in its coloring, a side effect of the rebirthing method that he had used. Valentine looked at the blood flowing out from the small basin he was in as his body continued to absorb it and soon there was nothing left.

“That savage made me use the rebirth chamber, this much pure virgin blood was not easy to gather, I will not be able to go through another rebirth also in my current weakened state if those humans attack us again…”

The vampire started monologuing while four beautiful pale women appeared with his clothes. The man was quickly dressed up in the Dracula look-alike clothes, if it wasn’t for the red coloring on his face no one would have probably noticed a change. But he did as he glanced up to his horn, a visible crack was there that indicated his weakened state.

Valentine’s rage did not subside even after going back to his throne room, the gazes of his tribe members were telling a story. They could clearly tell that he had lost and even used up a valuable resource without which he would not be able to cheat death anymore.

The resources required for it was the blood of virgins at a certain level of soul strength which was uncommon. He needed to capture them first before performing a ritual that would allow him to add the blood into the pool. The old one took a hundred years to fill out and now it was almost empty.

“My lord you must rest, forget about the hunt, the savages can never reach this castle.”

One of the many wives that tended to his needs spoke out while bowing her head. The whole throne room was filled out by the closest of his kin that was still alive. His army of blood relatives had suffered a large defeat, this was a good proposal yet it only brought anger to this vampire’s eyes.

“Are you telling me to hide like a coward? I’m not the prey here, they are!”

The outburst of anger brought everyone in the room down to their knees but he could not deny the truth in those words. It was not time to take his revenge just yet, he needed some time to prepare. Leaving the area was impossible as his tribe was tasked by the Empire himself but his tribe was not the only one here.

“Bring over the eye, I need to speak with the other tribe leaders…”

The vampire woman that was previously trembling on the ground gave out a radiant smile while quickly moving to the side to bring over a basketball-sized demonic eye that was clearly alive. The eye was placed on a stand made of blackthorns, the moment it was set down a demonic scream escaped from the strange item and produced a reddish aura. This aura started to form into an image that slowly started to take shape.

“What do you want Valentine?”

Was the response that he got, a characteristic horn was protruding from the forehead of the person on the other side. A glint appeared in his eyes while looking at the person on the other side, if pushed correctly then perhaps his tribe would not need to face against the strange golden cultivator he faced which would give him time to recoup his losses.

…..

“How did we fare?”

“I’d say better than expected, there weren’t that many deaths and with the help of the healing arts all of the injured will be able to eventually recover.”

“I see…”

Zhang Jin looked at Zhang Dong in a worried fashion as he noticed that his grandson wasn’t as cheerful as he usually was. While to this veteran something like this battle was a great victory, the small number of deaths was an amazing accomplishment.

To Zhang Dong on the other hand, even losing a few people was a failure on his part. He knew that it was almost impossible to have a war with no casualties but it still pained him to see people that looked up to him to die. The only way to lower the death count would be for him to take a more active role and roam the lands himself.

But he was the leader of the sect, he was the only person that could not die or be injured. If he did, the whole war effort was at a risk of collapsing. He was the glowing beacon of hope and strength that his people relied on. As long as he was there to push them forward, they would continue to fight and improve themselves. While wars were brutal they were also an opportunity for growth.

“I’ll leave the troops in your hands gramps, be sure to give them some words of wisdom but try not to bore them too much, they have earned their time of respite.”

This was not the time for moping, it was a glorious victory on their part. With the help of his sect members, he had managed to deliver a devastating blow to the vampires and cause their leader to use up some kind of forbidden spell. Those always had their drawbacks and perhaps the next time they met he would not pose that much of a threat.

“Aye, I could use a drink, this is truly the time to be festive!”

“Please, don’t mingle with the women warriors too much, you have enough wives as it is you old fart…”

Zhang Dong delivered a smack to Zhang Jin’s head the moment he saw him staring at a somewhat voluptuous lady from the healer division. With his youth being somewhat restored Zhang Jin would probably use this opportunity to spread his seed even further than before.

“Don’t make me regret making you a nascent soul master…”

“What’s there to regret?”

The old man laughed while floating towards the encampment at the border region that they retreated back to. While the enemies were defeated they did not press the offensive as there was not enough information.

The map they had only gave a general idea of the enemy forces which could be too much for their one battalion of sect warriors that arrived here. Their forces were still spread out thin and it was taking time to recruit the other sects under their wing. Those had their own problems as they could not trust them to perform well against these monsters that had an uncanny strength.

Huo Qiang on the other hand had disappeared to chase after more enemies. While there weren’t many, some of the lesser vampires had escaped. He was at a level that they would not pose a threat to him after receiving a protective talisman made by Zhang Dong to ward off soul attacks he had gone on his hunt.

‘Everyone is working hard, at this rate we should be able to reinforce the border region. I’m not sure if expanding beyond this point will be that easy…’

While he did not know much about wars he knew one truth, they didn’t end in one day. Even in his old world that was many times smaller, wards could take months or years without ever ending. Here where the distances between sect ground were the sizes of continents it would be even harder.

They needed to slowly transport their troops and reinforce the defenses so that the enemy soldiers could not push further in. While those tribes seemed unorganized at the moment, this could change. There were two choices here, either they rushed in swords swinging or they waited to slowly build up their momentum.

The first option was quite risky and would probably cause a large number of deaths. The gap between the cultivators here and the strange beastman-like tribes was still large. They had more members that were comparable to nascent soul masters and they were all body refiners that didn’t require as much rest as cultivators focusing on spiritual energy.

‘Is sneaking in there a possibility? They would certainly not expect someone like me to go there alone…’

He did not want to leave things unfinished, not being able to kill the leader was a big blunder on his part. But even with his death, there would not be enough information about the occupied lands. Only now his spy network was slowly seeping in, after a big blow to the vampires the lands were ripe for the taking.
‘This is going to get hectic…’

Zhang Dong let out a sigh while vanishing from the spot, he appeared at his private quarters at this location. There as always he contacted his wife and had a little chat with his children through a long-range communication device that could carry a hologram of him. These required special towers to be constructed at certain locations but after they took over the lands here, it was an easy fix.

After catching up it was time to get rid of some spirit stones and reevaluate his cultivation method. He slowly went down to the ground to position himself in the usual lotus position. After clasping his hands together he started to concentrate to look within himself.

The three cores were not aligned, the recently absorbed soul energy was seeping out of the soul core. What he required now was an abundance of lightning energy which he was lacking.

‘The most common elemental energy and I’m lacking in it, well its better than searching for more holy relics to absorb…’

Some of the spirit stones that he ransacked from the underground cities had already been absorbed. The weapons and magical treasures that he could use to bolster his body's refining state had also pushed him towards the apex of this technique. The body he was in the possession of was that of a nascent soul master at the great circle level.

Anyone below that level of strength would find it hard to even produce a scratch that would bleed. This variation of the golden body was a great defensive measure that would allow him to go toe to toe with those horned bastards which were precisely on that level.

‘If the generals are at that level then the Emperor is either at mine or slightly above it…’

While glancing at his struggling lightning core he decided on his next location. Sneaking into the vampire castle didn’t seem like the greatest idea at this point in time. If he managed to bolster his spiritual energy even further and evolve this seed in some way, then no one would be able to stand in his way.

‘I don’t need to endanger my people, If I get stronger those strongholds won’t be worth much nor will that Emperor. Even if I capture that location it won’t end the war. I need to get more powerful and this location seems to have the lightning energy that I require…’

Chapter 460

“I really need to create more waypoints through this empire…”

After the issue with his borders was resolved Zhang Dong continued with his travels. This time around he traveled eastwards towards an area fabled for their stormy weather. He decided to travel lightly without his soldiers as moving the heavy flying ships around would just bring unwanted attention.

His soul and golden cores were brimming with power yet his original one that was meant for lightning remained the smallest. It was possible to upgrade it with the help of spirit stones but with this method, he would burn through his reserves too fast.

This system of his didn’t have many methods of earning him spirit points. Spirit stones were the easiest and then he also had his faction that supplied him with a daily dose of points. Thanks to this he would never run out of them but it was not nearly enough to progress his cultivation.

The amount that he got from his faction mostly covered the teleportation expenses. There was always a reserve he needed to keep for any potential traps from which he needed teleporting out. If someone decided to employ any teleportation blocking formations it was still possible to flee but only at an increased cost.

Then there was the problem of Wang Long that had all the same features as he did and perhaps even some that he wasn’t aware of. These systems tended to alter themselves along with its user, it didn’t seem that his evil counterpart was using any kind of crafting abodes and only utilized the system store for all his needs.

But with a supply of spirit points, there was no reason to use any other functions. That store could provide everything, cultivation materials like potions and pills were also included. Luckily for him, Wang Long never practiced with the arts he bought and always tried forcing the fight with his superior cultivation. While that worked against the young masters he faced in the past it would not against him.

‘I wonder what that idiot is up to, some time has passed since then…’

Due to the war, all information that concerned the northern region was halted. He had no idea what happened with that bridge that he managed to defend the attack against. The long clan was unwilling to send their people to defend it which meant that these invaders had probably built another stronghold there.

Wang Long had made his way towards the demonic cultivators that were situated close to that location. If he was still there was up to debate but with so many of these invaders around he would have a lot of spirit points coming his way. The longer this war continued the more Wang Long would grow and after getting his ass beat the first time he would probably prepare better for the rematch.

“This world sure is vast though…”

Even now he had not had the pleasure of freely exploring this entire empire. The distances between the cities were massive and it felt like he was on another planet whenever he went between them. The differences between the environment and the people living there were sometimes extreme.

“So it’s supposed to be past that storm huh?”

Before his journey could continue he was greeted with a stunning phenomenon. A huge wall of wind and rubble was before him. It was a giant twister that was hundred of kilometers long and if he managed to pass through it he would arrive at an area filled with electrical discharges. It was hard to imagine that anyone could live there but large trade ships with enough armor were able to pass inside.

“What was the sect's name that rules these lands? The Lightning Dragon Sect? Reminds me of that thunder sect I visited in the other empire…”

This sect's name was very similar to one of the techniques that he bought of the system store all those years ago. With it he could summon serpentine dragons that could act independently from him and aided him in some of his previous encounters.

It was actually one of the larger middle-sized sects that had made it into the top ten. Thanks to this natural barrier that they used to their advantage they were hard to invade. But from his standpoint, this was one of the biggest weaknesses. When people started relying on these types of defenses they crumbled if they were ever removed or countered. The same thing happened to the sect with soul arts that was almost crushed by the red vampires.

‘If an armored ship can cross this, then so should I’

Zhang Dong nodded to himself while surrounding his body with a protective layer of Qi. This he probably didn’t need as his body had already reached defensive capabilities of a pinnacle heaven grade weapon. Yet, this was not the same for his clothes that would be shredded by the sharp winds and rubble flying around.

‘They are lucky that I’m not interested in the wind qi that is gathered here or their biggest shield would have to go.’

Finally, he plunged himself into the tornado and continued with his flight path. The inside was of the storm was quite dark and it was hard to maneuver. But with the help of his map, there was nothing that he needed to worry about. The shield that was around his body was enough to make this an underwhelming experience. Perhaps if he visited this area when he was weaker it would have been a struggle but now he was like an unstoppable rocket going forward.

Now on the other hand he was just ignoring these massive torrents of wind energy. Even though this storm had the thickness of hundreds of kilometers at the speed he was going it wouldn’t even take him an hour to pass through it. The experience was quite underwhelming as the inside was devoid of light and chilly.

‘At times like this, I wish I still had my phone to watch some movies or something…’

Even though the world was vast and beautiful, long journeys like this were somewhat boring. There was nothing to do besides to look at the scenery that passed by in a flash. It was as if he was stuck in a high-speed train with nothing else to do but look out of the window.

‘Wait what’s that?’

In an unexpected turn of events, he spread out his spiritual sense to do a quick scan. There he noticed that there was something a few kilometers in front of him. There were many people there and they were getting closer.

‘A flying ship going out?’

This was not that out of the ordinary as this place could be passed even by the locals. Either a person needed cultivation of at least an early nascent soul master or a strong enough ship with metal plating. This was certainly the former but something was off, when he used his sense further he noticed an oddity.

‘Is that… mana?’

The spot he was scanning was clearly a flying ship with a lot of people on it but besides the usual variations of spiritual energy, he felt mana similar to the one he interacted with in the other world. It was slightly different with its own flare but it clearly wasn’t spiritual energy used by the cultivators of this empire.

‘I did hear some information about strange men in full body armor using straight swords…’

The war had taken off now so more information was flowing over towards him. There were rumors that some of the fleeing cultivators brought with them that his people reported to him. One of them was a rumor about people looking like knights that used strange sword techniques.

This was something worth looking into thus he increased his speed slightly to see intercept the flying ship. While he was still inside the storm there should be a latch there that he could climb through, if not he could also force his way inside. But this could still just be a specialty of some clan and not be related to another invading party thus he decided to not make any presumptions.

‘There it is, the ship isn’t in good shape either and… they are fighting…’

The storm was making things hard on his spiritual sense but when he got closer the mystery was revealed. On the inside, he felt a larger group of cultivators using their spiritual energy meant for combat. It was clear that a fight was taking place, even the ship was slowly falling apart and the shield formation that was keeping the storm at bay seemed to be flickering.

This ship’s exterior was not made from heavy metal, instead it was designed with energy shields in mind. If the formation that was producing the shield was damaged more it would go out and the people inside would suffer the consequences.

‘This thing won’t last much longer…’

It was their lucky day as Zhang Dong was an expert in the field of formations. Within a few minutes of him arriving he was already mending up all the holes and reinforcing the shield so that it wouldn’t burst into tiny pieces of spiritual energy.

The ship had a strange exterior appearance, it looked like a whale made from wood. It had no mast or anything that would make it resemble a flying shield. Yet it was moving as if it was swimming through the air. With The shield being fixed he made his way inside by slipping through the formation he had reinforced.

‘There should be a way to get into the interior without destroying the exterior, it would be unwise to damage this thing with so many people in it…’

After a moment of searching, he found the entrance at where the whale had its blowhole. There was a sealed entrance that could be opened from the outside. After a little fiddling, he was through and found himself at a large empty hall.

“Fighting took place here…”

The moment he arrived he could see blood stains and nicks in the walls and ceiling. The place was mostly made from some special wood that would be resistant to core formation level of strength.

“These look like they were made by double-edged blades, could it really be those magic knights?”

Now that he was inside he made his way through the various hallways. The inside of this flying whale was quite large, it was similar to a luxury cruiseliner from his modern world yet much larger. The further he went the more destruction he saw which finally culminated in dead remains that were still fresh.

Without wanting any more dead on his hands he bolted forward now with full speed. Within a moment he got to the area where fighting was taking place, people were shouting at each other and various energies were being used.

‘They really are knights…’

What he saw was a group of armored men surrounded by radiant light. The blades they were holding truly gave him that magic knight vibe and they were clearly hostile against the cultivators they were facing.

Chapter 461

‘Are those mana arrows? Those weapons are imbued with runes and spells too…’

After arriving at the large whale ship Zhang Dong made his way through the destroyed corridors. At first, it felt like he was running through a maze but soon the path took him to a large hall that looked like some type of ballroom.

Chandeliers made from gold and expensive crystals were swinging in the air but also down on the ground due to the battle that was taking place. This ship’s interior looked very costly, not something a military vessel would possess. It seemed to belong to a rich merchant or some sect master with too much money.

On one side there was a group of regular-looking cultivators in robes. The lands he was going towards were led by the Lightning Dragon Sect. The robes that these people were wearing didn’t fit the moto though. They were brown with a somewhat tree motif which also blended in with the wooden whale ship they were using.

On the other side, he saw armored men with shields and swords. Their swords were radiating mana that seemed to be close to something at the upper stages of core formation. Then behind these nights, there were people in blue wizard-like robes chanting something. Above them was a ball of flames that would probably soon be used as a projectile.

‘That one looks a bit stronger than the rest…’

Almost all of the knights were wearing silver armor but there was one in the back that was different. The armor he was wearing was quite shiny and golden. The sword he was holding was somewhat larger and the mana it radiated was similar to his own holy energies.

‘Is that some kind of high level paladin from a game or something?’

It was clear that he was the leader but it didn’t seem that he was interested in the cultivators that were desperately defending themselves. He just stood there with both his hands resting on the hilt of his giant sword that was vertical to the floor.

The battlefield soon told Zhang Dong the story, on the other side he saw an old man with a large gash that went from the shoulder down to his stomach. It looked like he had almost been cleaved in half. This person was a nascent soul master at the early stage. He was still alive but the wound was deep and probably soon to be done for.

‘These knights are the bad guys right?’

This was not Zhang Dong’s fight and he did not know what had transpired between these people. It could have very well been the cultivators that were at fault but if he didn’t step in then only more deaths would occur. Besides the martial masters that were at the forefront, he could see women, children, and the elderly behind them. They were all quivering in fear, some of them were even injured.

Thus while the silver knights shrouded themselves in blue light and aimed for another attack he appeared between the two groups. His materialization was fast and took everyone by surprise yet while the cultivators behind him just edged away the silver knights continued with their assault.

For people wearing bulky armor, they were quite fast, the mana that shrouded their bodies was giving them superhuman speed and reflexes. Some of them were even performing strange speed-based abilities that to an untrained eye would seem like teleporting.

‘Damn, I thought they would at least back away for a moment when an unknown element appears, these guys are either stupid or arrogant.’

Normally when an unknown foe appeared it was best to assess the situation slowly. Yet these just continued with their onslaught not caring for the white-haired cultivator that just materialized out of thin air. But one of them was keeping an eye on him, when Zhang Dong did make himself known the golden armored one started moving.

“I don’t think so.”

The blades connected with a barrier made from light that instantly discharged a large amount of electricity towards the attackers. Due to them using metallic weapons and armor it was an easy feat to give them a shocking welcome. The mana barriers they were using for protection didn’t fare well against his overwhelming spiritual energy either.

In a flash of light, the small group of silver knights flew in the opposite direction of their charge. They all collided with the walls and slumped forward as they were instantly knocked out. The difference in strength was just too large between them, perhaps if he was a regular core formation expert then these men would be a hindrance but as he was now, there was no contest.

“Lay down your weapons and I might still be lenient with you…”

While the cultivators that were behind him started to inch away while mumbling the armored knights didn’t react at all. It was as if they were dead set on winning this battle only when the man in the golden armor spoke up did they move to the sides.

“You are not his match, I Arnet of the radiant dawn will be your opponent!”

‘He has a cool title to go with the paladin appearance I see?’

While Zhang Dong was someone that enjoyed cultivation novels he also had a weakness for heavy knight armor and straight swords. The man before looked like a character from a game that he would probably role-play as.

“Arnet is it? I see that these knights listen to you, how about you make the smart decision and surrender, this will not go as you think…”

“Silence, you shall not stand in our way, you should be the one to surrender and cease these barbaric ways, I see that you also poses the radiant light perhaps the lord will be lenient with you.”

“The lord? I presume he is your leader but before you make any demands, shouldn’t you make sure that you have the advantage sir knight…”

Zhang Dong vanished from his location and instantly appeared behind the babbling person in the golden armor. His hand was placed on the man’s shoulder and with a quick discharge of his spiritual energy, he was taken down to his knees. This fight didn’t need to take long, if he took out their leader the mindless carnage could be stopped.

“H-how… my radiant protection of the goddess is being dispelled?”

This knight's mana barrier was a lot thicker than of the silver knights but for him, it was as if he was wearing armor made from paper. By using his knowledge from the other world it was simple to remove the similar shield. Surprisingly this thing wasn’t only for defense, it was somehow able to boost this warrior’s all-around strength and probably the reason why he was able to contend with a nascent soul master.

“Maybe the goddess likes me more than you?”

“Blasphemy!”

The man ended up squished into a wall after Zhang Dong pushed him back. While the radiant light vanished from around his body the threat was lowered yet after a quick recovery it surrounded him once more.

‘That armor and that weapon are also making him stronger…’

How this opponent operated really started to remind him of an RPG game. There most of the time the player character got stronger by leveling up and gaining better gear. Sometimes the numbers on the armor far outweighed the characters basic capabilities. It seemed that it was the same for these people, the key to beating them would be to either remove their weapons or disable them.

At this point in time, he could only overpower the magic the armor was generating with stronger magic that he could wield. But when the opponent had enough time they could just reset the effect and continue with their battle. It seemed that he would need to strip these guys of their clothes and examine them if they really were from another empire as he presumed.

The fight continued as everyone else started clearing out from the large hall. The silver knights made way for their leader that quickly recovered and charged in once more. His speed was quite impressive and the way he wielded the blade produced arcs of holy energy that shot in all directions.

What his opponent didn’t count on was Zhang Dong’s mastery of the holy arts. These rays that were produced were just gulped up by his holy core. With one last effort the knight took off into the air, giant angelic wings of gold sprouted from his back and his sword increased in size while being covered in a bright yellow glow.

“Take this, you scoundrel!”

“Scoundrel, really?”

The man came down like he was a rocket, if the hit connected this whole ship would probably be blown to kingdom come. It was clear that the knight had forgotten where the fight was taking place or he was desperate enough to try his luck.

But just as the radiant blade’s tip was about to connect with Zhang Dong’s face his finger made its way towards it. As if it was never there the radiant weapon crumbled into many tiny particles of light. The flashy golden wings on his back burst along with the rest of the energy he surrounded himself.

“I guess that I took it? So what now?”

Zhang Dong smiled while pushing with his finger on the sword that the man was holding. The difference in power was too much, even with both his hands on the sword the man could not move it even by an inch. Instead, he was getting pushed back himself.

“Protect the lord!”

Finally, the enemy knights had recovered enough to help their commander. But in reality, they were planning to withdraw which was quite apparent. The magic they were using was easy to read, he knew that the silver knights charging his way were only a distraction. While he was busy the mages were creating a teleportation spell to flee, at least they had enough sense to finally withdraw.

“I won’t let you.”

With a flick of his finger, he sent the golden knight tumbling back. Following his lazy movement, his finger glowed with blue light very similar to the one gathering about the mages.

“T-the mana isn’t gathering, what is going on?”

“Is that barbarian using mana canceling, how can he use magic?”

They were quick to notice where the source of the canceling magic was. Zhang Dong waved his hand forward to produce a shockwave. It quickly pushed the charging knights away and embedded them in the wooden ship walls once more. The place was quickly falling apart, if they were not on this ship he would have dealt with these knights a lot sooner. But if he truly started using all of his power then the whole ship would be done for.

“Stay down if you want to live, you are all my prisoners now!”

He proclaimed while sending off a suppressive attack against all of the magical knights and mages which promptly caused them to be knocked out. Only the commander was able to last through it but he wasn’t looking all that great himself.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 462

“We will never forget this senior, the Spirit Whale Merchant Troupe always remembers their debts!”

“I will never forget Senior’s gallant form!”

“Me neither! I will spread the word of the Golden Dragon for the rest of my life!”

“... Please everyone just calm down and tell me about these people, how did they get on this ship?”

After the battle was over Zhang Dong disabled all of the stowaways. With the help of some high quality rope, all of the silver knights and mages were tied up in the middle of this large ship hall. Under them, he created a mana canceling formation that would not allow them any access to any of their enhanced techniques.

While these knights were quite strong they had one large flaw, without items that could channel their mana they weren’t much stronger than lower Qi condensation practitioners. Even the golden knight mostly amounted to someone at the 5th Qi condensation level if he was stripped of the magical armor.

‘After they get knocked out it’s easy to get rid of the mana, if the flow is disturbed these people can not regain their previous might but the mana canceling formation won’t work in active battle, at least not without a large spiritual vessel with a lot of energy.’

“Lord Golden Dragon, please let me explain, I’m not sure if you have heard about us but we from the Spirit Whale Merchant Troupe are a coalition of merchants that trade between many large-sized sects, while we might not be the most prominent merchant group…”

The man continued to talk while Zhang Dong listened. First, they were just regular merchants that mostly did business with the middle-sized sects. There were other companies that were similar to that one merchant group he once interacted with.

That time he ended up together with the Divine Fist Sect which then led him to the other world. While these people weren’t as rich, they still possessed some resources that he could use and that he would not refuse. With how troublesome times were now, he needed all the help that he could get.

“So, you say that these people suddenly appeared as you were leaving the port city?”

“Yes senior, they might even still be there.”

“I see…”

The person he was talking with was the leader of this merchant troupe here. He described the events that transpired about an hour ago. After they loaded all of their items they headed for the storm but as they were going through these invaders had somehow appeared on board.

They could not explain how they managed to teleport themselves in without properly setting up a teleportation gate. Magic was somewhat different from Qi arts so they were able to use that to their advantage. The formations that this ship had were not designed to protect them against magical teleportation.

“Was the city you left attacked before they appeared?”

“I’m sorry senior, I do not know that we were preoccupied with our own problems, we did manage to leave the port without any problems though…”

‘This feels like a sneak attack more, did they want something that was on this ship?’

It was strange that instead of the city they aimed for this ship. But this was another of the empires, not the same monsters that were closer to his lands. They seemed like a band of religious nuts but they were probably not hunting others as livestock.

‘If they are not here for pleasure as those other bastards, then they are probably here to do business. They might have wanted to steer this ship elsewhere along with all the resources it had.?’

He could only speculate only after using some techniques on these members to make them talk would he be able to confirm his theories. But these knights could be testing out the waters before invading further. Words of their invasion were already widespread but they weren’t as forceful as the people from those tribes.

‘Maybe they are looking to test the materials this empire has to offer and steal them for themselves? A nation aiming more for profits than conquest perhaps?’

Zhang Dong could only shrug while looking at the knocked-out humans. They had regular human looks but were clearly more aligned with the western part of his previous world. Blond hair and blue eyes were very prevalent amongst them.

“I see, that will be all, you should go tend to your people now, here if there is anyone in a grave condition give them one of these pills.”

After the report, he gave the merchant a small pouch with some pills. The moment the man laid his eyes on them they almost popped out. While for him they were not anything special, the merchants could see their worth as the highest grade holy healing pills. If ingested by someone they would quickly heal even deep wounds.

“You have my gratitude senior, we will be sure to send out regards to the Long Clan and…”

“Ah, if you want to thank me then send them to the United Element Sect that I hail from instead.”

He chuckled a bit as any resources given to the Long Clan would not flow into his pocket. The pills were also very easy to make as he just grabbed some that were made by his sect members. After infusing them with some of his own healing energies they had enhanced properties that could even work against demonic corruption.

The biggest reason that he brought these pills along for his journey was for such an occasion. After trying to chase Wang Long down he had realized that he was losing too much time on helping others. Instead of spending hours healing the injured, it was better to prepare some pills that would work in a similar way. Only if the situation was grave would he need to act himself.

“In you go.”

All of the silver knights made their way into the regalia replica medallion that now had a full-blown prison building inside of it. With how much he was capturing prisoners the need to house them was created.

This he achieved by transplanting a working prison from his own sect. Inside were many cells with spirit and mana sucking formations just for such an occasion. Together with them were also autonomous puppets that were able to transport some food to the prisoners.

Escape was impossible as they were trapped in a pocket dimension and only he knew where the true exit was. Only a great circle nascent soul master would have a possibility of forcing himself out of there and even then as long as he held the medallion on his neck, it would be easy to suppress any escape attempt.

After the prisoners were in the medallion the wooden puppets dragged them into their cells. Later he would dump them off at his sect for questioning. Luckily for them, the techniques his clan used were in line with hypnosis and no torturing was included.

In his opinion, this method was superior as a tortured person could always lie after they reached their pain threshold. But if they were coaxed into thinking they were talking with some friend or family member they would spill the beans.

“I shall be off then, your ship didn’t suffer much damage, I also reinforced your formation so you don’t have to worry about it becoming unstable.”

All of the people here started to quickly bow before him. It was quite uncommon to see a person like him that just helped people out without taking much in return. If he wanted he could just ransack the whole ship and no one would know about it or care. With his current status he could just snatch everything up in the name of the Emperor.

‘I guess this isn’t going to be as easy as I expected…’

On the outside, he rocketed forward and approached the end of the wind storm. When he finally was outside he was greeted by quite the spectacular look. Instead of the huge winds, there was just tranquility and silence.

`The wind elements are all focused on the tornado around this area, after you go past it the concentration is really thin but instead…’
While at first everything looked calm, soon the scenery changed. Out of nowhere a thick bolt of blue lightning connected with something that looked like a pointy pillar made from steel. This produced a loud thunderous roar that sounded as if it was produced by a dragon.

“That’s probably where this sect got their name from.”

When he looked up he could see something that looked swirly. They were in the eye of the tornado but the sky above wasn’t clear. Instead, it was filled with clouds radiating lightning energy. But this wasn’t the source of the lightning elements yet. When looking at the clouds in the distance he could see a massive shiny pillar.

‘So that’s it, I can barely see it from here…’

There was a legend to this area, an immortal ascended to the heavens one day and left behind a pillar of lightning energy. It seemed he was versed both in wind and lightning elements that worked together nicely. He wouldn’t be sure until he got closer but that lightning energies stored in there would probably help him boost his cultivation to another level.

‘The lightning and this wind are separate from each other, even if I absorb all of it, the winds that protect this place should not dissipate.’

He could feel that the lightning elementals were thin here and only when getting closer to the central area would they increase in power. The wind's energies were the opposite as they were the strongest back here and slowly dissipated further in. While the winds offered protection the lightning bolts were a big hazardous risk.

‘Those pointy lightning rods were probably created to prevent the people here from being shocked, they might even thank me if I manage to get rid of them.’

Zhang Dong now had a target to get to, the lightning bolts that were raining down from the skies could be absorbed but it would be much faster if he got to the source instead. Then there was also the problem with these shiny knights.

In the distance, he could also see a city at which many flying ships were floating in the sky. They were attached with huge chains to what probably was the port city the merchants mentioned. Just as they explained to him, the attack only occurred when they were entering the wind barrier.

‘The city does look normal, those guys were not aiming for it at least.’

With no smoke or angry dead spirits hovering around after being killed he didn’t really have a reason to force himself into the port city. Yet before going ahead, he needed to scout out the area for any traces of mana, perhaps he could find the spot where the knights teleported onto the ship.

“Well then, I have my work cut out for me, time to go!”

Chapter 463

A note from Kuropon

Next chapter will be delayed as I'm taking a break for Easter.

“They are really not here but why were they trying to infiltrate that ship?”

Zhang Dong was floating above the port city where many various ships were floating around. After helping out the merchants he decided to see if the inhabitants were doing well. The people were just minding their own business and continuing with their work as if nothing happened. Due to the storm barrier communication with the ships inside was impossible thus they had no idea of what had happened.

‘I can feel a trace of mana being used and it's coming from there.’

Before any pesky cultivators came out to invite him to some kind of feast he disappeared towards a faraway location. After landing behind some large rocky formations he found something interesting.

‘This does look like a magic circle.’

On the ground, he saw a circle with a pentagram in the middle. Around the pentagram were various runes that were identical to the ones he learned about in the other world. It seemed that these people could have a connection to it or magic was the same even in the other worlds.

“But I can use this to my advantage…”

There were a few options here, he had captured the group that had attacked the ship but they would probably not reveal their plans to him without a lengthy interrogation process. Yet this teleportation magic here could help him out with that problem.

‘This does look like a two-way portal, someone had to have stayed behind on this side to stabilize it.’

With that in mind, he moved his hand towards the pattern on the ground. The mana burned out a clear pattern for the spell being used and left a trace amount of mana. This mana would lead him to the mage that stayed behind on this side.

The magical technology being used here was slightly above what the cultivators in this world were capable of. It was mostly impossible to make it inside of a flying ship with a teleportation formation unless there was an existing gate inside of it. Yet these people were able to make it inside without one.

‘There could have been some item smuggled to the inside but even with that, this could complicate things if they can just ignore protective formations and get inside cities like this.’

This was the biggest problem here, if these people were able to get through the ship’s protective formations it could be possible for them to get into fortified positions. Even with a smaller force, they could cause widespread damage and then flee before launching a full-scale attack.

‘But if I attune the formations to this type of mana signature it should counter it, I’ll have to send it over with these prisoners when I have the chance but before that, I should trace this to the source.’

He had arrived here to absorb lightning energy but instead, there were more invaders from the other Empire running around. If he was lucky the forces that were gathered here would not be large enough to give him any trouble. But for some reason, he was feeling bad about this one, with teleportation being involved the forces of his enemies could have been up to something.

After grabbing some of the soil with his hand he performed a tracking spell that he learned from the other world. The spoil started radiating blue light which expanded to the sides rapidly. Soon it started taking the shape of a wolf made from mana that would be used as his tracking hound.

“Well then boy, get the scent, and let's go.”

The wolf made from pure mana started sniffing at the ground where the pentagram was. After a couple of whiffs, it turned its head to one side while giving out a howl. It had caught the mana scent of the tracking target and quickly sprinted towards it with its master following behind it.

With his finger, he pointed towards the wolf made of light to hasten the process. With an injection of the energy, the creature bolted forward at speeds similar to a core formation expert. The distance he was going was unknown to him as he needed to rely on this spell.

‘I guess I’ll look at the scenery for now…’

Zhang Dong’s journey started and while continuing the chase he was sure to get hit by some of the lightning bolts that were shooting down from the sky. Each hit was quickly absorbed with this lightning core which grew in size by a tiny fraction that was hard to notice.

‘Would be nice to have more of these cores, I’d be immune to all elemental afflictions but the downside is being reliant on external factors for cultivation.’

Sometimes he wished that he had picked up sword fighting as his main profession. This too was a Dao from this world that he could train himself in yet it only relied on regular training.

‘But this way is certainly faster as long as there are resources to borrow from, otherwise understanding the elemental arts gets quite vague.’

While contemplating the world's Dao he made his way towards the giant torrent of electrical energy in the middle of this area he was in. Of course, he was hiding himself from the sect that ruled this area otherwise they would have made moving around their lands a lot harder.

Luckily for him, these invaders weren’t as obnoxious as the ones roaming close to his lands. Even when going in deeper he didn’t spot any chaos besides the continuous lightning strikes raining down from the heavens. Yet this could have just been the quiet before the storm, if they were more methodic then they were perhaps only taking their time before the full-blown invasion.

“Wait… that’s enough.”

Suddenly his spiritual sense that was feeling out for magical activity sounded a red alarm. Before his mana sniffing wolf was discovered he quickly snapped his fingers to make it disappear. The reason for this was simple as right before him stood a trapping barrier similar to the trapping formations that cultivators used.

“A protective spell, if I go through here they will know that I’m here, that is unless I counter it.”

This was not a threat to his life, it was mostly a large-scale detection spell. Probably the spell was created to monitor everyone entering the area. A normal person would not feel that anything was out of place when going through the threshold. But somewhere in the zone that this spell was created was something keeping track of people entering the area.

Before launching any countermeasures Zhang Dong decided to look around. The area he was in was composed of empty hills with forests populated by some lightning beasts. Even from here, he could see some white thunder tigers wandering around without caring for the thunder cracking in the distance.

‘At least the closest settlement is many kilometers away, even if I cause some damage no one should be hurt but first I need to get through this barrier.’

While Zhang Dong had impersonated a magical spirit emperor in the other world he didn’t spend that much time here. He had gone through all of the libraries he could but he was not all-knowing. Magic was a field as vast as cultivation and worked in mysterious ways, if he wasn’t careful his enemies would be aware of his presence and then he would need to switch to plan B.

‘Going in forcefully isn’t always the best way, most of the time it’s better to take your time and feel things out first…’

With that in mind, he placed his digits on the edge of the barrier. First, he started with one finger to get a good feeling for the energy signature. Slowly but surely he added another finger and traced both up and then down. Finally, after he got a good feel for it a third finger was added and he started pushing towards as he attempted to push the thin membrane-like barrier out of the way.

‘There we go, slow and steady… there we go!’

Thanks to his slow approach he was able to produce a small opening that expanded to let him through. Without activating the initial barrier the only thing he needed to do was mask himself by creating a familiar mana signature around his body.

‘But this is strange, I don’t really see much enemy movement on this side of the empire. Could it have something to do with the way these people use their power?’
The tribes that he met closer to his own sect appeared faintly on the mapping system he copied over from the Long Clan. This was mostly because they were body refiners with a slim amount of Qi. These knights that he was up against now were similar, if they didn’t activate that mana aura they were quite weak.

‘Their main base should be in this location…’

Zhang Dong glanced towards the area that was bright red and closest to the bridge entrance into this empire. It was south-eastwards and together with the information he received confirmed the location of one of the opposing empires. It was a lot brighter than the stronghold where those vampires were.

‘There must be quite the concentration of energy there, it might be difficult to get through their defenses…’

It was a perfect circle that encompassed a huge area. It was clearly something like a grand formation protecting the area. Perhaps if the Long Clan had listened to him they could have controlled these locations and held back the invaders but as it was now it was too late.

“But this is no time for my mind to wander, I need to see what these guys are up to…”

He had shrouded himself in his own version of mana to counter this detection spell but this also forced him to travel on foot. If for some reason he produced even the smallest amount of Qi his cover could be broken. For the time being his body refining would have to be enough as it was not something that easily detectable.

“I guess you guys won’t just let me through, huh?”

A group of electrically charged beasts looked towards him after the concealment spell. While using it he didn’t seem all that strong so even these foundation establishment creatures saw him as a fast meal. But he did not want to waste his time and stamina on these small fries, he needed to find the hiding place of this magically inclined race of invaders.

“Well then, which one is the leader… that one.”

Thus he looked towards the biggest looking tiger that was causing little bolts of energy to shoot off from its whiskers. After taking care of the alpha beast the other would probably let him through, if not then this might be quite the journey.

A note from Kuropon

Thank you for reading!

Don't forget to follow, favorite, rate.

Donate | Discord |

Chapter 464

“Has there still not been any word from Varus?”

“I’m afraid not my Lord.”

“It might be the nature of that storm, they might not be able to contact us from the outside until they return. I want someone to immediately inform me if Varus reaches out to us.”

“It will be done, my lord!”

A group of people dressed in noble-looking attire was talking with each other while someone was listening to their conversation. This person had melded himself with the nearby wall with the help of a concealing spiritual art.

‘They do seem more organized than the other group…’

Zhang Dong was sticking to the wall like a certain superhero. After getting through the magical barrier he arrived inside of the enemy camp. This area was shrouded by various illusory spells that made it look like plain rocks from the outside.

Yet when he managed to get inside he was greeted by a small fort that reminded him of old medieval castles. It had four towers with sentries that were monitoring the area as well as many other soldiers doing patrols. But while this magically inclined race of people could fool other cultivators with their mana-based spells, they were also susceptible to techniques using Qi.

One of these techniques was on display now as Zhang Dong was able to sneak in without being noticed. He was invisible to them, even if he moved there was no sound being produced, and keeping his breath still was something easily done by any average cultivator.

‘Their spells are effective against cultivators but they also don’t know how to counter spiritual techniques…’

This reminded him about the time he had infiltrated the vampire fortress. There he had failed with his infiltration attempt so this time around he was playing it safe. He could spend days in this spot without moving to gather information but the big question was if he should.

The other option would be to go for the man he was spying on. The person called Varus seemed to be the golden knight he had stuck into his medallion. Supposedly that person had infiltrated a flying ship which was probably the one that he saved.

From the conversations, they were having it seemed that they were gathering information. Varus was supposed to take over the ship along with its cargo. They wanted to inspect the higher quality wares that cultivators were using without announcing themselves to the world.

They were taking a more methodical way to this war of empires. It seemed they wanted to test the waters first before going into a full-blown exchange. This was a more expected way of doing this as they probably had no idea of knowing what martial masters from this empire were capable of.

‘But if they are just waiting for the right time to strike, then they aren't much better than the other guys, or perhaps there might be a chance to talk things out before more people die?’

He only had the merchant ship incident to go back to. There it seemed that these knights didn’t care much for the lives of the people there. It was clearly a hostile attack but due to his appearance, it ended prematurely if they actually killed all of the noncombatants after successfully capturing the ship was unknown to him.

‘Perhaps there is a possibility of reaching some kind of agreement with these people but if they don’t keep their word we’ll just be helping them fortify themselves here…’

Violence was not the only way to go around these things. If these magical knights could be reasoned with then perhaps if they gave up some land they could have peace. Yet the enemies could take a ceasefire agreement as an opportunity to build up their forces before launching an attack.

While contemplating the possibility of a diplomatic resolution he noticed that something was happening. A larger group of knights started heading into the middle of the fortress where a large pentagram was located. It was about thirty meters in diameter and quite similar to the one he found after the ship incident.

‘So that’s their teleportation spell… It has its own problems I see.’

At first he thought these people had superior transportation technology but now he wasn’t that sure. The magical circle started glowing but instead of a gate forming through which people could go through a large number of them appeared right in the middle.

This teleportation spell was in some ways inferior to the teleportation gates he used. It did teleport a large group of people in a flash yet it had a big disadvantage of not being able to continue. After the spell finished the group was there but no more could go through. Only after a cooldown period would other people be able to use it again. This was different for the gates he implemented in his sect through which others could continuously go through.

‘This variant does have its uses though, it doesn’t require that many materials and can be used in active combat, there is no danger of the gate being destroyed while people are going through it either…’

What appeared there were about fifty soldiers with a peculiar gray-robed man in the middle. He had a peculiar getup that reminded him of various wizards from popular media from his old world. That he was right in the middle also indicated that he was someone in a high position. The person that he was spying on and that was the commander of this fortress was quick to greet this Merlin look-alike.

“It’s a pleasure, Grand Wizard Argus.”

“Lord Gregory, it is good to see you…”

They exchanged greetings while Zhang Dong looked from the distance. There was something off about that wizard though. He could not feel him out as easily as he could the other mages or magical knights in this area. The commander was a little bit stronger than the golden knight that he captured before but this old man felt like trouble.

“Actually… we have lost contact with Lord Varus…”

“You have? What aren’t you telling me?”

The commander seems to be hiding something from this grand wizard that he was talking with and it was obvious.

“P-percival was part of the group.”

“Do you mean to tell me that my apprentice has gone missing?”

The old man’s brows shot up while looking at the golden knight commander. While he was trying to explain himself Zhang Dong peeked into his medallion. In there he could see the suppressed prisoners trying to use their magic to get out of their cells. He didn’t actually kill anyone during the altercation so one of the mages was probably the one they were talking about.

‘Could it be that kid?’

While all of the mages there were mostly old shriveled up men there was one that was younger. His age was closer to thirty but he was at a similar level to everyone else which did align with the title of grand wizard apprentice.

“I don’t blame you, Lord Gregory, I’m sure my stupid apprentice probably forced you to send him out, that idiot is too hasty with everything.”

Argus gave out a sigh while also moving his hand to the side. Suddenly in his hand, a blue light appeared that expanded upwards to form a large wooden staff. With it in hand, he really started looking like a high level wizard.

“Don’t worry I’ll find that idiot and drag him back here, now give me some space.’

With the staff in his hand, he ordered the soldiers to move to the side while smacking the ground with his magic stick. This caused the floor to produce more blue light that bubbled upwards. This bubble started forming into an orb that produced an image of white mist.

“Hm…he is clearly alive but something is blocking my spell, are there people capable of shrouding spells?”

Zhang Dong started to get nervous now as the wizard continued with his chants. He had the knowledge of some protective spells that he was using now but it was all from that other world. Would they be enough to counter this grand wizard?

‘Even if he can get through the spell barrier, he shouldn’t be able to go around the protective formation that works on different laws… right?’

This was truly an interesting display as the man continued with various other chants some of which Zhang Dong was actually familiar with. But the more this continued the more nervous he became as there was a feeling of being discovered soon. The biggest problem was that he had cemented himself into this location and if he moved then discovery was imminent.

“I don’t know who this mage is but he will know the name of Argus!”

The wizard started looking mad as after attempting a few tracking spells he was unable to make the fog vanish from the magical orb that he produced. Yet he didn’t seem to be at the end of his ropes yet as various magical items appeared around him along with some talismans to aid his cause.

A tremendous amount of magical energy erupted from the spot he was standing in. The knights that were to the sides were quick to remove themselves from the vicinity as small arcs of magical lightning started to form. Soon enough to Zhang Dong’s shock the orb that was cloudy started clearing up and an image of the man he identified as Percival was shown.

“Hah, I see he is alive and in some kind of dungeon.”

The knights that were to the sides started cheering after hearing that the people they sent out were still alive. But the person that was the one that apprehended them was wondering if he needed to move out. If he acted quickly he would probably be able to take out this Argus with one move. The man’s mana capacity was truly enormous and it reminded him of the demon lord he faced off in the other world.

Yet he hesitated, for the time being, he was not sure if these people could be reasoned with. They were not the same as those who hunt hungry monsters that did all of this for pleasure. They were probably here to get resources and perhaps to explore and not to only conquer, perhaps there was still a way to talk things out.

“Now that I know that he is alive it will be a trifling matter to find his whereabouts!”

With a wave of his staff, the man pointed at the glowing crystal that quickly changed to the top view of this location.

“That’s strange… isn’t this where we are, did I make a mistake…”

The old man started conducting some experiments but with each new spell the location continued to be the same, it was right at the spot that Zhang Dong was hiding which was on one of the castle walls. Soon the wizard and the golden night were looking at the exact spot he was sticking to while squinting with their eyes.

‘Shit, I really suck at these infiltration missions…’

Chapter 465

‘Let’s calm down, they shouldn’t be able to see me… right?’

Zhang Dong had found himself in a pickle. On the magical orb that the mage formed to find his apprentice the spot he was hiding on was being shown. From this vantage point, he could see the old man looking his way but his cover wasn’t blown quite yet.

The wizard named Argus continued to look between the spot he was in and the magical ball as if he wasn’t sure of what he was seeing. Sometimes the image changed to that of his apprentice that was leaning up against a prison wall and then back to the empty spot that Zhang Dong was in.

“That’s odd, is something there? I guess there is one way to find out..”

Finally, after playing around with his beard the wizard quickly pointed towards his hiding spot. Even without asking, he knew that something was coming as the mana particles around the wizard’s staff started to change. It was not something a regular person would notice but he was different.

Without a sound, there was a shift in the temperature around the area he was in. It was some sort of fire spell aimed for the spot on the wall that he was clinging to. If he didn’t move he would receive damage and his cover would be blown.

‘Doesn’t that old fart care about his apprentice? What if he kills the only person related to his apprentice?’

Zhang Dong was slightly perplexed about the old man’s immediate reaction. If it was him he would probably not try to blow up the only clue to his disciple's whereabouts. But perhaps this was part of the man’s plan as this amount of mana was not as deadly as he had originally thought yet his body reacted on instinct. With a high-speed jump, he propelled his body upwards to put some distance between himself and his enemies.

“I have you, now tell me where you have my apprentice!”

It was all a scheme created by the old Merlin look alike. The moment he revealed himself Argus used a quick teleportation spell to put himself above Zhang Dong’s position. A mass of small magic circles appeared from all directions which soon shot out a vast number of blue glowing chains.

The chains had a clear intention of trapping him in place. It was clear that the first attacking spell was only a distraction to reveal the enemy and the chains were there to trap him. Yet Zhang Dong was not easily captured as his body turned into a bolt of lightning to dodge the incoming energy shackles that came from all sides.

‘How many of these chains are there?’

The sky was covered in them, there was not much space to maneuver to getaway. He was unsure if this was something that this magician conjured up by himself or if this was some kind of safety measure that existed beforehand. One thing was obvious though, this man was strong.

“You will not get away fiend!”

“Hey now, I’m no fiend, and do you really want to kill the only person that knows where your apprentice is hidden away, what if he dies along with me?”

There was something odd that he noticed during this fight, this old man’s killing intent wasn’t all that strong. During his many battles he had grown a certain battle sense but this man didn’t seem that frenzied. The attacks that he was using were also not meant to kill but to capture.

“Why you…’

Then suddenly something odd happened, the shackles that were chasing after him halted with their advance. They didn’t vanish into thin air though instead they just floated there like snakes ready to pounce when ordered to.

“What do you want?”

“Wait, that actually worked for once?”

Zhang Dong was surprised by the enemy actually listening for once instead of just charging towards him like a madman. He had never had much luck when it came to the diplomatic approach, most of the time his fist envied all the conversations. Even when he was the stronger one the enemy rarely avoided conflict unless the gap was truly huge.

‘So, does this mean that these people care for their own?”

The only explanation for this reaction was the relationship between this old man and the student. Now the question was what he should do, in reality, he was holding most of the cards. Even if he didn’t manage to get a deal, escaping should be possible.

The wizard here was at the level of a nascent soul great circle master but not exactly the same. He did possess the mana to match his Qi but this didn’t mean that they were on equal footing.

The mages were quite stationary during combat, if you could crush their mana shield they would quickly crumble. They were like slow-moving turrets that could blast everything with spells but their only way of evading counterattacks was either a slower flight spell or teleporting.

That teleport that Argus performed was tricky though, even Zhang Dong could only react to it without knowing where the old man would appear. Then there was also the range, could this old fart move large distances away and constantly barrage him with deadly spells? If he took too long more of those golden knights would probably also show up, one of them was already flying up here with a shield and golden lance in hand.
“Grand Wizard, I will aid you!”

“Stand down Lord Gregory.”

This golden knight Gregory had a more intricate armor than the one he met at the ship. On his back, there were golden wings which were probably responsible for his flying capabilities. If he had to measure this knight’s power level he would put it at a lower middle nascent soul stage which at this point in his life wouldn’t amount to much.

“But Grand Wizard, the Knight Commander forbade us from consulting with the barbarian natives.”

“I will speak to Lord Lucius later but for now we shall converse…”

‘Knight Commander? Sounds like some big shot could be their leader if this Wizard has to answer to him.’

By the looks of things, the Wizard carried a lot of weight here. Even when another leader’s name was brought up he didn’t care. Yet, the shackles were still there and the knight remained in the sky as they clearly didn’t trust him to not escape.

“If you are finished then perhaps we can discuss a few things, here how about we take a seat.”

Zhang Dong smiled while waving his finger forward. The two people he was looking at flinched the moment he released energy that was very similar to their own. In his mind, he thought that perhaps if he showcased that he could also cast spells then perhaps these people would see him more as one of their own. But there was also the probability of them becoming more hostile after seeing a ‘barbarian’ using their holy arts.

“This, how is this possible? Are you someone that is from the Kingdom as well?”

The spell that he used was a creation spell. It produced a floating platform with a round table. On his end, there was one chair while on the other was another one for the Wizard. To separate himself from the weaker knight he decided to only allow Argus the sitting spot. This showed that he considered the mage to be on a more equal footing than the golden knight.

“From the Kingdom? No never heard about it but I also dabble in some magic, now how about you take a seat?”

The furniture he produced was glowing with blue energy and radiating faint blue light. He was unable to create things out of thin air only when fueling them with his energy would they be able to exist.

“Grand Wizard, don’t trust this barbarian, it has to be a trap!”

Gregory was very suspicious of the chair that Zhang Dong beckoned Argos towards. This was quite a normal reaction to doubt an enemy. If it was some kind of trap then their strongest member could be quickly taken out of the picture.

“It’s fine Lord Gregory, there are no traps there.”

The old man floated down to the chair to sit in it which also took Zhang Dong by surprise. He thought that he would remain standing, it was as if the old man was assured that there were no tricks involved. Argus seemed to be confident of his ability to see through the magic being used here or his own mana shield that was still protecting his body.

“My name is Zhang Dong, I do not wish to harm you or your apprentice but he and some other of your people attacked a merchant ship, they were lucky that it was me that captured them otherwise they would all be dead now I’m not sure what to do with them, your people have taken the lives do you think they deserve to live?”

This was the truth, if any other powerful cultivator appeared instead of him they would not bother with capturing these invaders. They would probably have no problem in blowing up the whole ship if they started losing though either.

“What do you mean barbarian? Of course, they deserve to live!”

“Oh do they? You come to our lands and slaughter our people. Do you call us barbarians so that you can justify your wanton slaughter? Is it not just an excuse to dehumanize your enemies and make yourself feel better?”

Zhang Dong raised his voice while looking at the man named Gregory. This was not something new, it happened everywhere when groups were involved. It didn’t matter what the difference was, it could be race, it could be religion or it could just be the city a person was born with. People liked to divide themselves into groups, then when conflicts arose it was easy to divide themselves from the enemy.

“How dare you!

“Lord Gregory, that's enough, leave us.”

Before the person in shining armor could get mad he was restrained by the magician. His shouts were muffled by a magic spell that the mage created in a fraction of a second. Soon he was forced to fly down towards the rest of the small army below them.

When glancing there Zhang Dong also noticed many crossbows and other ranged weapons being pointed towards him. It was clear that the moment the discussion ended he would find himself in quite the pickle. This could be of course prevented if he could get this Argus on his side and for some reason, the man was wise enough to give him a chance to explain himself.

“I must apologize for my companion’s outburst, I’m aware that we are nothing more than invaders in your eyes but I implore you to see past this notion, and perhaps we can come to an agreement.”

Finally, it was time to give his diplomatic skills a try, he had already alienated the golden knight by his previous emotional outburst but luckily this old man was not offended. Perhaps it was actually possible to resolve this without bloodshed for once.

Chapter 466

‘This is an interesting turn of events…’

Zhang Dong found himself sitting with a person from another empire. After a quick introduction, the man named Argus started talking, the main point was the release of his apprentice. Now the big question was if this man would promise him something in return and then actually keep that promise.

‘Will he attack me the moment I take out this apprentice of his?’

The magician was quite strong considering he was not a cultivator. His code of conduct was unknown to Zhang Dong but for now he seemed to be reasonable enough. After the golden knight was forced to go down to the ground the two were left chatting. Soon the mage produced a tea set with black tea which he decided to drink as a show of good faith. It was not poisoned or tempered in any way that he could tell.

“Sir Zhang Dong, first I would like to apologize for Sir Gregory’s behavior, his words were too harsh and I hope that you can forgive his ignorance.”

“Ah it’s fine, being called a barbarian is an interesting choice of words but you don’t seem to agree with that way of thinking.”

This wasn’t anything new, during a war it was normal to dehumanize the enemy in some manner. In this situation, they gave the native cultivators of these lands the label of barbarians. Through this, they could put themselves on the moral high ground.

There was no problem in killing savages, they were nothing more than uneducated brutes that had not been enlightened. Thus they could easily justify the massive number of deaths that were caused by the wars.

“I’m sure we can reach an agreement but that is if you can keep your men in check”

Zhang Dong didn’t exactly trust this man yet. While he was acting nice the soldiers below could be getting ready for another attack. His system teleportation window was already floating to the side. If he found himself in danger that he could not get away then teleportation would be the only option out.

“The knights will follow my orders, you don’t have to worry. Now Sir Zhang Dong, state your terms, what will it take for you to free my apprentice and also the other knights.”

At first, he thought that the man was more similar to a cultivator but to his surprise, the wizard seemed to care for the other soldiers as well. When he was glancing through the magical orb to see the cell his apprentice was in he certainly saw a few other knights there with him. While a martial master from this empire would probably only care for their disciple this man also wanted to help the other captives out.

“So you want me to release all of the prisoners? That might increase the cost of the deal though…”

“That does not matter, my apprentice is dear to me but the soldiers that kept him safe are also important.”

“Interesting, well I won’t circumlocute and palter, what I want is information. Why did you come to these lands, what do you really want and is there any possibility of you halting your advances before more people die?”

“That is…”

The old man started rubbing his beard while thinking, it took a moment before he finally decided to speak up.

“Very well, I can talk about my homeland but for the second part I’m afraid that I’m able to make that decision…”

“Oh?”

Zhang Dong was surprised that the man was actually willing to talk. The reason for capturing the men that invaded that ship was to get them to reveal their origins and military structure. If this man gave him this information then he would have no use for these men. Though returning them so that they could just kill more people was also a problem.

“But before I speak, can I have your word that you will release my apprentice and the men that you have captured?”

“That depends on the information you give me, to be frank, I was planning on getting it out of your men anyway so it depends on you Mr. Argus, also please don’t lie to me, I will be able to tell if you do.”

With various techniques at his disposal, he could tell if someone was telling the truth or not. That is when other cultivators were concerned, this man was covering himself with a thick layer of mana that would be difficult to prod at. The man was still human though, there were many ways he could read his mannerisms that would help him.

“I might be many things but I am no liar, do I have your word?”

“Fine, I can at least promise to release your apprentice but only if the information you give me has validity.”

“I guess this will have to do, I will keep you to your word.”

The man nodded while also pointing out with his finger towards the middle of the round table. Zhang Dong didn’t flinch but he was vigilant, the spell the man was performing didn’t have any malice behind it. After the mana gathered in the middle he was presented with a large holographic depiction of the land.

“This is my homeland, we call it Avalon.”

To confirm the man’s claims Zhang Dong quickly used his system to copy the map being presented there. In a matter of seconds, it was added to his world map and compared to the other landmasses.

For the time being, he had a detailed map of the Azure Dragon Empire and also a semi-detailed one of the Emerald Phoenix Empire that he had visited. When he aligned the borders those two fit together perfectly. The man didn’t lie to him, this version of the map was vague but it loosely aligned with the Azure Dragon Empire’s borders from the southeast regions and the Emerald Phoenix Empire from the north side.

‘It stretches mostly towards the southern region but doesn’t come close to my sect.”

The world map was slowly taking shape. To the West were those maniacs that were seeing everything as some kind of game. In the East was the Emerald Phoenix Empire and below it was this land of Avalon which seemed to be divided into two large continents.

“This continent here is the land of Avalon, it is my homeland and where all of the soldiers come from.”

“If that’s your homeland, what is this other continent there?”

Zhang Dong pointed towards the other piece of land that was color-coded black. From how Argus presented this land it looked quite desolate and hard to live in.

“That is the continent of Ragnos and the reason for us coming to these lands. It is the birthplace of the demonic races that have been plaguing our lands for millennia…”

‘Oh… this does sound like an average hero setting, don’t tell me that they are here to find some McGuffin to defeat a demon lord or something?’

“We have come to these lands to find the legendary holy sword Lightbringer…”

The more the man talked the more he didn’t like it. It seemed that these people were justifying their actions by the impending demonic invasion. This holy sword might not even exist or it could have been destroyed many hundreds of years ago. But this changed things, perhaps if he could help them find this fabled sword then they would just pack up and leave?

“Lightbringer you say? Do you have any specifics of how it looks or its origins?”

“I’m afraid not, it’s an old legend passed down by our forefathers. The sword had returned to its resting place after the previous Lord of Ragnos had been slain over a hundred thousand years ago. For the prophecy to come true we must bring the sword back to Avalon where the chosen hero will appear to claim it.”

“I see, so if I helped you to find this holy blade would your people leave these lands?”

“Would you help us find the secret blade of legend?”

“That depends on your honesty, if what you say is true then this relic would have unfathomable power, a power that could be easily turned towards us.”

“Sir Zhang Dong, you don’t have to worry about that ever happening, the holy blade can only be used by a true hero with a pure soul.”

It seemed that this weapon followed the usual tropes. It could have been an intelligent item with a spirit living in it that put its master through trials to test their worth. Perhaps it was another setting that would play out after these people left these lands with the weapon in hand. Another person like him could be summoned then to fulfill the prophecy that was aided by another system.

‘But if it's a weapon created by the system, then perhaps I could use it instead?’

Argus did not have a description of the weapon or its location or he was not telling him everything. These people probably didn’t come here without any clues on where the sword was hidden. Perhaps they even had some special item that could detect where the weapon was. He was quite sure the old man would not reveal this information to him but this was enough, with this knowledge he could actually start bartering.

But now there was an actual clue to getting rid of one invading force. Perhaps if he helped these holy knights out they would be grateful enough to help him with battling the other forces. He was not sure how powerful these people were but they should be at least on the levels of the others.

Sooner or later they would clash with the other invaders with which they probably didn’t have anything in common. During this scenario, the Azure Dragon Empire would lose most of its lands and be forced into the middle. But this would also cause the other empire's to make contact with each other. While they went into combat with equally strong foes his side would have some time to gather their forces for a counter-attack.

“I see, Sir Argus, I think that if what you are telling me is the truth then we can reach an agreement. If you agree to hold your advances towards our lands I should be able to convince the other sects to aid you in your search without all of the bloodshed.”

The weapon in question would probably be useless in the hands of the cultivators. These lands were too vast to explore but if everyone knew what they were searching for then perhaps this item could be retrieved before they suffered more deaths.

“You could do that?”

“Why yes, you might not know this but you are talking with the Azure Emperor’s brother!”

It seemed that they would be coming to an agreement but before he could continue there was a shift in the environment. Zhang Dong looked down to where the teleportation formation was placed and saw a group of ten golden knights appearing. All of them were radiating power that was at the level of a nascent soul master at the great circle with some even being slightly above…

Chapter 467

“What is this supposed to be? I thought that we could reach an agreement and this is how you repay me?”

“I…”

Zhang Dong was looking at an approaching squadron of golden knights. While he was on the cusp of making a deal with this wizard Argus the teleportation spell was used. A small group of powerful magical knights appeared out of thin air that was now charging towards the location above the castle.

“Lord Lucius please stop, this man is not our enemy!”

“Argus, have you lost your mind? Are you colluding with the enemy or under some kind of enchantment? Worry not, I Lucius Lightburn of the Golden Braves will cut down the enemies of our holy kingdom.”

With the enemies coming his way Zhang Dong decided to fly away from the round table in the sky. At first, he thought that this was a betrayal of trust but then as the conversation continued it was clear that the mage had nothing to do with it.

“Sir Gregory, was it you? Do you mistrust this old man this much to call upon the Knight Commander himself?”

Down on the ground was the knight that he saw before. It seemed that the man had called over their forces while he was having his talk with the Wizard. Argus was the strongest person here so he did not expect someone to ignore his orders. This was a rule that was prevalent in the cultivation world that he was now used to. Here on the other hand the most powerful might not even be their King.

‘What should I do… Can I take them out and still continue? Would they work together with me after I kill their powerful knights or just feel resentment instead?’

There were ten knights in shiny gold armor flying towards him. They were all riding large muscular horses with wings coming out of their backs. The one in the front looked like a legendary pegasus with a full golden barding covering its body. These magical beasts felt as strong as nascent soul masters and clearly specialized in speed.

“Argus, I see that we’ll have to talk this over some time later but my offer still stands but that depends if you can convince these idiots first.”

The old wizard’s eyes went wide as he flew to the side. It was clear that the man wanted to attempt a less bloody solution but his comrades had other ideas. Zhang Dong was unsure of the man’s position in this army but it felt to him that Argus was in some kind of strange position of a consultant. The knights would take his orders to a point but the real leader was someone like this Knight Commander coming his way.

This Lucius character stuck out from the rest. While they were all wearing heavy plate armor and covering their faces this Knight Commander was letting everyone see his face. He was quite handsome, his eyes looked like blue sapphires that were radiating light. The hair looked like golden straw that for some reason even when he charged towards him didn’t get in his face. It was as if he was a supermodel that came from a shampoo commercial. The weapon of choice was a golden halberd that was radiating holy energy.

‘Would be nice if they were lightning-based enemies…’

While Zhang Dong could absorb this type of energy there was a limit. This limit was close approaching as both his soul and golden core were practically full. Unless he took in more lightning energy to equal all three cores out then he was risking a cultivation backlash. At this point in time, he had not reached his limit but there were ten golden knights coming his way and all of them possessed holy-based attacks.

“Duke Lucius, stay thy hand! This is not the time for combat”

Argus tried to get the supermodel to stop but even he was ignored as the whole squadron of flying horses just zoomed past him. The golden halberd in Lucius’ hand started giving out a radiant glow as he was preparing to poke him with it.

‘So, they divide themselves by nobility… maybe that’s why they aren’t listening to this wizard?’

While propelling himself back he continued to gather more information. It made sense why the other soldiers didn’t like the wizard that much if he was some kind of gifted commoner. Nobility tended to distance themselves from the peasants that they considered subhuman to them.

It was a similar division to the sects and clans. Even when the other group was strong unless they had some backing or history they would see them as lesser beings. It seemed that the wizard was outside the tightly knit group of knights that would listen to Lucius over him.

‘I guess that means that he can’t do anything for me which means…’

Zhang Dong glanced at his system window where his escape teleport option was already brought up. With one click he could be out of there and back in the lightning-covered lands where he saved a safe location for himself. But he decided to stall for a moment, while combat was inevitable it was a good chance to measure his enemy's strength.

The knights that he was facing were radiating might similar to top nascent soul masters with their commander being the most powerful. This situation didn’t look too favorable for him, he might have been slightly stronger than their leader but there were too many enemies to count.

With that in mind, he decided to not engage the group in a close-quarters battle instead, he pointed out with his finger that quickly produced a ray of light. This ray before impact split into many smaller ones that showered the ten enemies with his attack.

Yet before the moment of impact, all of the knights raised their kite shields. All of them were uniform in their looks with a head of a lion on the middle part. At the moment of impact instead of an explosion, his attack was somehow suctioned towards the lion’s mouth then after a fraction of a second, it was sent back towards him.

“Wait, that’s illegal!”

He shouted out while infusing his body with more power to flee. While the attack came from him it was somehow altered through those shields. He was unable to control it anymore and if it collided with his body there was a possibility of being injured even with his body refining skill making him impervious to most damage.

This was quite the surprising turn of events which then turned for the worse. When he was dodging the blasts sent back his way the knight leader managed to catch up to him. The flying horse that he used was actually faster than he had assumed.

“I have you!”

There was no hesitation as the sparkling halberd headed towards his head. The man ignored the wizard’s shouts while going straight for the kill. He was not sure what that Sir Gregory character had told this knight commander but it was enough to cost him his head.

“How about you take this instead?”

But he didn’t despair yet, there were various ways to get out of this predicament, one of them was his trusted moving skill that he had perfected through his battles. Thus the moment the weapon went for his head instead of a bloody stump it created a light show of electrical energy.

Instead of his head flying off an afterimage containing a jolt of holy electrical energy was discharged through the man’s weapon. It traveled further up his hand and was discharged through his entire body along with the mount Lucius was riding on.

This was the opportunity that he was waiting for, this technique was able to stun even the strongest opponents for a moment. A sword appeared in his hand along with his true form to the flank of his enemy. With a quick swing of his weapon, he decided to punish his overzealous opponent.

“Hmm?”

But Lucius didn’t seem that impressed as he twirled the halberd in his hand to deflect the shorter blade with ease. His horse then took off forward before turning around for another attack. This was not his only problem as the other enemies had caught up to him and surrounded him from all sides.

‘Could they be resistant to the golden lightning, or is that armor just that good?’

It seemed that he was not the only person that could resist holy attacks. Perhaps to get the edge over these opponents he would need to utilize one of his other Dao’s. Using his soul core to weaken his enemies before striking them down seemed like a good plan but there was something protecting them.

Zhang Dong found himself in an evasive battle the knights attacked from all directions while he dodged. The only thing on his side was that he could perform more difficult aerial maneuvers than the men on horseback. Like an eel, he managed to evade all blows with only sustaining marginal cuts on his white combat robe.

‘These guys aren’t that simple.’

After a few exchanges, it was clear that these knights had gone through many battles together. Whenever he aimed for an opening there was someone blocking his way before he could deliver a finishing blow. They reacted quickly and covered each other's backs even though he was a lot faster than them.

Then there was also their leader who after the first few exchanges took himself out of the main battle. He would monitor him from afar before jumping in for the kill, it was him that constantly tore his clothes as he barely evaded.

‘If this continues I might actually die here…’

Zhang Dong realized that he had been too haughty for once. He had allowed the enemies to come this close in hopes of testing their true strength. Now he found himself with no time to do anything but dodge. His movement techniques seemed to have been seen through and the armored men weren’t damaged by his holy aura nor his lightning. He was also unable to affect their souls either putting him at a large disadvantage.

‘I guess it’s time to make a run for it…’

“Oh my god, isn’t that the radiant goddess herself… and what is this! She is holding the secret sword Lightbringer!”

During the onslaught, he shouted while pointing in one direction. The knights were taken off guard and even when they didn’t want the Lightbringer name had some weight behind it.

“The Lightbringer?”

Lucius turned his head around to look at empty space along with some other of the knights. Yet when they looked back towards the man that had shouted the lies he was already to the side and waving.

“You really fell for that? Well, I’ll see you next time, ciao!”

What they witnessed was a smiling Zhang Dong waving at them after finally having a chance to activate his teleportation escape. Even when they tried it was already too late, their weapons hit a few energy particles that were left behind while he vanished to fight on another occasion.

Chapter 468

“Duke Lucius! Why did you interrupt my negotiations with the native, he was about to set free my apprentice but now…”

“Wizard you are out of line, you might have the required skill to participate in this secret expedition but you are not part of the army.”

After Zhang Dong had vanished from sight everyone was momentarily stunned. Soon all of them were looking towards Argus the mighty wizard and Duke Lucius who was the commanding officer here. Just as Zhang Dong had suspected the Wizard had no say in the militaristic part where the nobles resided.

“Everyone, we will divide our forces into four and follow this barbarian, he could not have traveled far with such a fast teleportation spell he must still be close to our location! When you find him activate the beckoning spell, he might be alone but that savage is strong, don't try to fight him alone!”

“Yes sir!”

The group of ten golden knights was quick to follow Lucius’ instructions as they all spread out in three directions while dividing themselves into smaller groups. Their commander on the other hand took the fourth position himself. Everyone here knew that he was the most powerful warrior that didn’t need anyone watching over their back.

“Wait, if you kill that man then my apprentice could be lost…”

Argus stretched out his hand as he tried to call Lucius back but no one was listening. The moment the knight commander appeared his overseeing privileges were overwritten. All of the knights now ignored him as they were given the order to find the white-haired native that had been here. Even Gregory that had called for help had gone with them.

“You blasted fools!”

The ground started shaking as bolts of blue energy appeared around his body. Yet his anger soon subsided as he heard a familiar voice.

“Is this a bad moment to interrupt?”

This voice belonged to the man that he had discussed a few things before. It was coming from his left hand in which Argus was holding a comma-shaped bead that was made from green jade.

This communication jade was thrown his way when Lucius had attacked during the diplomatic talks. He had surrounded it with a thick layer of mana as at first he thought that it might have been some kind of malicious item but now he knew what Zhang Dong’s intention was.

“Sir Zhang Dong, is that you?”

“Yes, we were interrupted previously but I still think that we could work something out. That depends on if you can somehow convince those nobles of yours to work with me though…”

Argus looked around and quickly snapped his fingers to produce a sound canceling barrier. The soldiers here would certainly inform the knight commander if they heard him talk to the person they considered a barbarian.

“First I must apologize for the behavior of my countrymen, I’m not sure how I could regain your trust.”

“Oh, that’s fine, I understand the social structure you are under. While we might not be able to work together directly if you promise to halt your advances I could help you with that Lightbringer and about your apprentice, I’ll drop him off in a few hours so keep in touch through this communication jade, I set it up so that you can contact me through your mana signature.”

“You will release my apprentice?”

Argus was shocked by the words of the man he was talking with. Even though his people attacked him in a brutal fashion to kill him, the man was still seeing the bigger picture. Bringing them the Lightbringer would be the fastest way of ending this invasive expedition. This Wizard knew how the nobles operated and that it would take a massive effort to convince them to see it his way.

“Yes but I will be keeping those soldiers, I do not trust them to not just go back to killing the people that live in these lands.”

He could not disagree with Zhang Dong’s words. The people belonging to the kingdom’s war machine would follow the knight commander’s words. It was him that was the true leader here as he had the highest noble rank of a duke. But this could change in the future, he was not the only duke in the kingdom, and then there was also the royal family with its many members.

…..

“Just give me an hour or two and I will send you the coordinates of your apprentice.”

Zhang Dong concluded his conversation with the man named Argus. The old wizard was not opposed to working with him so he would throw him a bone. The apprentice that he had in his medallion was a bargaining chip but he needed to show some goodwill. The rest of the soldiers were too dangerous as they would probably listen to that knight commander that wanted him dead instead.

“Those idiots think that I wasn’t able to use wide-area teleportation.”

After clearing up things with his new associate there were now two things that he had to do. One was to go towards the large torrent of electrical energy to further his cultivation by another step and then there still were the golden knights on his trail. Those people had some nice teleportation technology which meant that if he attacked his pursuers they would quickly gather at his location.

‘Or at least that’s what they are hoping for, keep me busy long enough for all of them to arrive in one location. They made a huge mistake though…’

Zhang Dong through his communication jade could hear Lucius give out his orders. There was nothing specific there but with the help of his map he was able to pinpoint the locations of his enemies. Even though the map had trouble discerning the power of these enemies he just needed to use their hideout as a reference point. The big question now was, did he gain more from taking out these golden knights before cultivating?

‘All of these people aren’t hostile, they can be reasoned with but if I just murder their Knight Commander along with a large part of their strongest men then I will probably lose any goodwill they could offer me…’

If he just went along with the guerilla tactic of taking out the smaller forces and running he would probably be successful. Yet this would put a target on his head, even if Lucius was defeated or captured those nobles would probably hate him. The man named Argus didn’t have any political power and they would probably set a bounty on his head for killing their noble leader.

This was not an easy choice to make for him. When looking at the bigger picture then it was better to postpone the fight for a later date. If he managed to get this sacred sword to them he would have all the leverage. Yet if they saw him as a true enemy of their people, even with the relic in hand they could choose to attack him as the trust would be hard to gain back.

‘Argus mentioned that some other nobles would arrive later, ones that see things more his way, that would probably be the right time to strike up a deal…’

Zhang Dong clicked his tongue while looking out into the distance. These lands were vast and populated by many cultivators. While the magical knights weren’t wantonly attacking everyone they saw they would probably retaliate swiftly whenever met with any kind of resistance.

“You can never save everyone huh?”

He knew that the morally right thing to do would be to take out the invaders before they cause more damage. Yet it was not the correct way of winning this dispute with people that were searching for some strange relic. As a leader he needed to see the bigger picture here, the sheer amount of people that could be saved by an earlier end to this war outweighed the ones he could save by acting now.

Thus with a heavy heart, he turned away from the map indicator that informed him about the general direction of his pursuers. They would not be able to find him as he was a lot further away than they expected. He could only hope that they would continue to remain hidden in these lands instead of going into a full confrontation with the sect living here.

‘Well then, first I need to drop off this apprentice… that looks like a good location.’

In the distance, he saw a large mountain that was getting struck down by many lightning bolts. It was a good natural barrier that could not be crossed by any cultivator below the nascent soul mastery level and a good hiding place for his mage. The constant lightning bolts made it hard to use any detection techniques and spells which made it perfect.

After taking off he quickly surrounded himself with a golden spiral of energy. Using this he drilled himself into the mountain range. There were no naturally formed caves here so he had to make some space so that this apprentice would be able to survive.

“That should do it…”

With a wave of his hand, he brought up some wooden furniture along with some food. He did not know how fast Argus would be able to come here as the distance from their hidden castle was about a day’s journey with his own flight speed. If the wizard could fly as fast as he could for a whole day he did not know.

“W-what?”

“Well hello there, you must be the apprentice Argus mentioned.”

“You know my mentor? Who are you, what do you want?”

“I don’t want anything, you just need to stay here, your master will come and pick you up later so it would be better if you stayed here, if you happened to die then It would probably sour our relationship.”

After the little explanation vanished from sight. The apprentice was left in a hidden cave made by him and surrounded by rocky mountains. He had reinforced the exterior so there was no problem with the mountain collapsing on the man inside or him being able to get through the walls himself. Air would be supplied by a handy treasure he had taken from his sect and with enough food and water to last him two weeks he should have been safe.

“Old man Argus, I have your disciple stashed in a safe location, he should be fine there for a week or two but it would be better if you didn’t stall too much. Also, bring some lightning protection and maybe some mining equipment.”

“Mining equipment?”

He could not see the wizard’s face but he was sure that the man was confused about his words. After some further explaining, everything was clear, the Wizard was on his way to free his apprentice and Zhang Dong started his journey towards the zone containing the largest amount of lightning energy.